It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Dreaming to become the number one Karakuri martial artist, Musashi left Miyamoto village for the first time,
trained under Bokuden, and fought against Benkei on the bridge of the capital city,
but after a hard struggle, Ushiwaka ended up claiming the good stuff.
Ryoma is Alone in the Wind
Ouch!
What is it-dasu?
Sorry for kicking-dasu.
No need to worry.
But...
Ryoma
A man shouldn't be bothered by that; instead, one should be large-hearted!
Uh... what are you looking at-dasu?
Clouds.
Clouds?
I envy clouds. They are never tied to anything, and they wander around the sky as they desire.
Where will you be heading to?
I am going to Yoshioka Dōjō to train my swordsmanship-dasu.
Swordsmanship! The world is losing the need of swords.
That's impossible-dasu. For any Karakuri martial artist, reaching the extremes of swords is the eternal aim-dasu.
Small. That's small! If you call yourself a man, you should dream to change this Jipangu State!
I think you're having some strange dreams from a nap-dasu.
I have to hurry, so excuse me-dasu.
He's living in the past, for a kid!
This is the Miyako Palace. Musashi was staying in this village for the time being.
What makes him think that the era of sword is going to end-dasu?
Stop! You there!
Kondō
I never saw you around here before. Identify yourself!
Ju- just a moment-dasu! Aren't you forgetting your manners by not telling your name before finding people-dasu?
What did you say, you impudent kid?! Don't you know Kondō, the chief of Shinsen Family?
Is that it-dasu? I am Musashi-dasu.
Um, well... It's alright. I see that you're a honest guy.
Anyway, did you see this guy before?
Huh? I remember!
Do you know this guy?
I saw him on a lawn at west-dasu.
Damn, that bastard! So that's where he was hiding at!
-Everyone, hurry!
-Got it!
Ju- just a moment-dasu! What did he do-dasu?
He is a crime who's planning to rebel against the Miyako Palace!
I didn't thought he was a bad person-dasu...
Yoshioka Dōjō Inc.
The chief of the Yoshioka Family Dōjō must be here-dasu!
I was careless that time, but I won't lose this time-dasu!
Excuse me-dasu!
What's your business?
I am Musashi, traveling about to gain skill in combat-dasu!
I came to have a match against a person from Yoshioka Dōjō-dasu!
You're asking to have a match against tens of thousands of us at Yoshioka Dōjō, kid?
Age does not hinder the path of sword-dasu. The stronger one wins-dasu!
What did you say, you brat? I was being kind and you still want to be whipped to death?
Now, now. He's just a kid. Chill out.
We are no way letting a kid like you enter the Dōjō. Go back home.
Please-dasu! A match!
Even for a bit!
Excuse...
I'll do whatever it takes to have a match against them-dasu!
Anybody want to buy some fishes? Fishes to sell!
Fresh fishes!
These fishes are good for your body after all that training!
Hey, Mr. Fisher, I'd like to buy the amount of one basket.
Thank you-dasu.
This went well-dasu!
This way, Mr. Fisher!
Huh? Where did he go?
I made it-dasu.
Hey, you! Where are you going?
I'm here to deliver the fishes, but I got lost-dasu.
You got lost?
Are you joking? The kitchen and the back door are very close!
Er, to be exact-dasu, I'm a special kind of not having sense of directions...
But... it'll be all right-dasu. I'll deliver this and go back right away-dasu.
-Stop right there!
-Suspicious. We'll take you to Dōjō and find out who you are!
Who is this guy?
Yessir, he is a suspicious man wandering around inside the estate, Master Sējūrō.
He might be a thief as well.
To creep into my Dōjō, eh? How brazen of you.
I'll cut off your neck right now!
No, that's not it-dasu! I just wanted to have a match so I crept in and that's all-dasu!
You're that stupid brat!
You're that kid beaten in Okayamāna! Are you here to be beaten again?
After the painful training, I am now different from me of the past-dasu!
Good then! If you really want that much to have a match against this Yoshioka Dōjō, I'll fight you myself.
Are you going to be my opponent-dasu?
Yes.
You don't really have to fight against this kid, brother.
If you end up losing for some reason, the name of our Yoshioka family will be scratched!
Don't worry! There's no way I'm losing to such a brat!
But! If you lose to me, you must shout Yoshioka Dōjō is strong as expected around the town!
Agreed.
Start!
Uh, what about my wooden sword-dasu?
We do not lend wooden swords to a stranger of doubtful origin!
Denshichirō
No way!
Secret technique: swan stance!
Now, kid, you may pounce from anywhere!
Even if you say so...
Can't you blow a single hit against this stance?
Well then, you'd like the family secret: hole deception!
No, that's not the problem...
This will do-dasu!
I'll face you with this-dasu!
Mystery technique! The hit of reward for all your hard work!
Hmph, kid, you still have a long way to go.
Secret skill! The hit of letting you know that it won't work.
How dare you!
Still weak! The hit of yours!
It seems that I won-dasu.
I may have slipped the wooden sword off my hand, but my body has no single scratch whatsoever!
The real match starts now, kiddo!
Not willing to accept defeat-dasu? Try taking this strike without your wooden sword-dasu!
We still have an ultimate secret technique left at our Yoshioka Dōjō.
The name is!
(Shinken Shirahadori: 真剣白刃取り. Stopping a sword by bare hands)
Shinken Shirahadori!
You try that-dasu!
The first one to be exhausted first will lose!
Damn, is this end?
How's that, kiddo? It seems that you reached your limit.
I'm not finished yet! Secret technique: If pressing down doesn't work, I'll raise instead-dasu!
Here it goes!
I won! I finally defeated Sējūrō-dasu!
How dare you do that to my brother, you brat! Nothing matters now! Finish off this brat!
I'm overwhelmingly at disadvantage at this rate-dasu. I must do something...
That's it-dasu!
Move or be hit-dasu!
What are you doing? Follow and get him!
-You're not running away!
-Stop right there!
I'm not running away-dasu! This also is a strategy-dasu!
I won't have to worry about being surrounded here-dasu, but...
You may come from anywhere-dasu!
Get him!
Why are you taking so much time against a single child?
Get out of the way! I'll take him down myself.
Come!
Die, you brat!
Prepare yourself!
-Stop that!
-What?
You're..
Who are you bastard?!
I am Ryoma.
Damn you! Are you going to get in the way of our battle?!
That's not what I have in mind, but it's pretty unsightly for an adult to have a match against a kid with a real sword.
Nonsense. Don't make me laugh! You're going down first!
Take another step and you'll get a hole in the middle of your stomach.
Do not move.
Now, run away when you have time.
Bu- but, as a martial artist, I must not run away...
They jumped into the river!
They disappeared!
We can't find him!
There they are!
Gentlemen! See you again!
Are you running away, you brat? You coward!
I am not a coward!
Musashi has bought Denshichirō's wrath. Wait for the stormy latter half!
What's the problem? They gave up the pursuit, so you should be able to sleep well.
I must pay you back for saving me-dasu.
But I'm not getting the courage-dasu.
You shouldn't be worrying so much. You're gonna lose your topknot if you worry so much from your youth!
I... have became a coward because I was saved by you, Ryoma.
Hey, Musashi. Running away isn't cowardly or something.
You'll eventually understand:
Running away also is a superb tactic.
That's the tactic of Ryoma who is a wanted man-dasu!
Oh...
The tactic of a wanted man. That's a good thing!
Hey, Ryoma. You don't even look like a bad person,
but why are you trying to overthrow the Miyako Palace-dasu?
To call the dawn to Jipangu State.
Huh? There is a dawn for every day-dasu.
That's what I meant. I mean that I am trying to make Jipangu State a free and peaceful place without a war.
Why did you became a wanted man when you're pursuing for peace-dasu?
Once that happens, those high ranked people won't be able to be arrogant anymore.
Now, let's talk about those difficult subjects tomorrow, and you should sleep now.
In the Miyako Palace, disciples of Yoshioka Dōjō were looking for Musashi.
And also, Shinsen family was desperately looking for Ryoma.
Kilimanjaro
3 mons
Blue Mountain
5 mons
Columbian
3 mons
Mocha Mattari
American
3 mons
Meanwhile, Kojirō was...
Here it is.
I do not need sugar!
Adding sugar to coffee is a heresy!
Oh, okay.
Mocha is great as always. The feeling of soft and good flavor filling my mouth...
I'm sorry to interrupt your rest, but did you see this guy around?
Isn't this Musashi?
Do you know?
Well... kind of. Did he do something?
Yes. Sējūrō, our head at Yoshioka, was hit on his head by him...
What?! Musashi took down the head of Yoshioka Dōjō?
Oh! Are you understanding our mortification?
Unbelievable. I never thought the head of Yoshioka was that weak!
If that was the case, I could have taken him down first!
What is that?!
My hair!
Damn Musashi! That weak but lucky bastard!
Hey, Ryoma, where are you taking me to-dasu?
The hideout for making the new Jipangu State.
Huh? While I like what you're doing, I don't want to be a comrade of a villain-dasu.
TEA
I like how you're upfront with what you're thinking, no matter what it's about.
I finally found you, Ryoma.
This my hideout.
Huh, it's pretty small for a hideout of making a new Jipangu State-dasu...
You're very outspoken guy.
Anyway, come in.
Musashi, I finally found you!
We must report back to our master Denshichirō right away.
Hey, I thought making a new Jipangu State would involve preparing for a war.
It looks like you're in a commerce-dasu.
That's right. I'm doing this on purpose. Money is more realistic than fighting to make a new country.
What do you sell-dasu?
I sell peace.
Peace?
Right. We give food to a country with famine, and prepare to
help people living in villages that became battlefields.
Is that what it takes to make a new Jipangu State-dasu?
Now, Musashi, do you know why they fight?
Huh?
They are fighting because there are not enough resources.
If everyone could have anything they want...
What do you think?
That's...
They will live without fighting.
That's what I am talking about. The Jipangu State that I'm dreaming for
is the place where everything is enough and no fight occurs.
Shinsen Family House
What? You found Ryoma's hideout?
I saw him entering a farmhouse close to the Miyako Palace with my bare eyes.
Great. I will show him my wrath this time!
-Let's go!
-Got it!
Everyone! Go!
That brat is definitely at a farmhouse!
Yoshioka Dōjō Inc.
Understood? We must catch him as of today!
I entrust you on this.
Mr. Ryoma, you look like you're enjoying.
I wonder if you want to be my comrade, Musashi.
But still... I must become the number one Karakuri martial artist...
When I manage to become the number one martial artist, I will marry Otsuru-dasu!
Musashi!
I still must aim for the number one Karakuri martial artist-dasu!
I see. If you're that determined, you just gotta push the limits.
Even though our dreams are different, let's do our best for the objectives.
Yes!
What's that-dasu?
Someone has come near to our hideout.
I found you, Ryoma! You're not running away from me this time!
I still have a lot to do. I am not intending to be caught.
What is this smoke?
Now! Let's run away!
Hey, Musashi! I will have revenge on you for my brother!
You didn't need to come in time like this!
Musashi! Prepare yourself!
-Here they are!
-It seems that Shinsen family followed us too.
Ryoma! Prepare yourself!
I am not Ryoma!
Excuse me.
This way! Chase him!
You're not running away any more!
You call this running away-dasu?
Since I can't fight as freely there,
I just changed the place-dasu!
What the? He's not Ryoma!
Where is Ryoma?!
What the heck is that?!
Ryoma!
Damn you, Ryoma! When did you come out with that?! Come back here, you coward!
Come up with something else than walking, Kondō.
Even though I am called a coward, I'm not dying until I achieve what I dream!
Ryoma! I finally understood-dasu!
Musashi, prepare yourself!
Final blow! Extreme forward rush!
Are you running away, Musashi? Coward!
Running away is a tactic-dasu!
Musashi, see you soon! The dawn of Jipangu State is soon!
Meeting with Ryoma, a wind-like Karakuri man, has let Musashi take a big step forward.
Run, Musashi! Until the day that your dreams come true!
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
After the painful training, I am supposed to be a martial artist worth of one's salt,
but I still don't have the crucial sword-dasu.
Because of that I went to meet the master of sword craftsman, I was refused-dasu.
Damn! If he's not going to make me one, I'm going to make one myself-dasu!
Next story! Kotetsu the Excellent Sword Calls for a Storm-dasu.
Be sure to check out the next stormy story-dasu!
Next Episode
Kotetsu the Excellent Sword
Calls for a Storm
Look forwards for it!