It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Dreaming for the number one martial artist of Jipangu State, Musashi was fighting against numberless Martial Artists,
but he met a wrong opponent, the infamous Denshichirō, the boss of Yoshika Dōjō
boasting countless members across the land.
Kotetsu the Excellent Sword
Calls for a Storm
That's very absurd, to have a match with that wooden sword!
A match between martial artists shall only be done with real swords like this!
I lost! I'm going to die-dasu! Someone help me-dasu!
Kid, you're half asleep.
It was a persimmon-dasu!
We were going under a persimmon tree moments ago.
I don't know what were you dreaming about, but you were pretty agitated.
Damn, I want a sword too-dasu.
I will get a sword and become the number one martial artist of Jipangu-dasu!
We're soon at Sakai village.
Welcome to Sakai
This place is Sakai harbor, a village of merchants.
Denshichiro came to Yoshioka Dōjō Sakai branch to get Musashi.
Yoshioka Dōjō Inc.
Sakai Branch
Welcome
This is the face of Musashi who wreaked havoc on our Yoshioka Dōjō.
What a sly face!
Martial Arts is about Form
He should be in this Sakai village. Understood?
Search for him thoroughly and report to me as soon as you find out where he is!
He is not just a weak brat, so be careful!
Got it!
Master!
What is it?
The sword craftsman you asked for is here.
Good. I'll go right now.
This person, Kenmochi Kotetsu, is a historically famous sword craftsman of the long Sengoku period of Jipangu State.
Made by Kotetsu
A sword crafted by him is called Kotetsu, and it is told that only masters of swords can have one.
I am Denshichirō Yoshioka, a substitute instructor at Yoshioka Dōjō.
Kenmochi Kotetsu.
Long story short, I'd like to ask you to make your excellent sword Kotetsu.
I reject.
What?! You dare to reject the request from the substitute instructor at Yoshioka Dōjō?
Don't you know Yoshioka Denshichirō, a name famous all over Jipangu State?
I do know.
Then why do you reject? Crafting a sword isn't something dishonorable.
I regret to say that I already gave up crafting swords.
Gave up?
How's this? We'll pay as much as you want.
I do not want money.
Then what do you want?
Nothing special.
I see that you are without greed. But know this.
Whatever reason you have, you will make and give me a sword.
Excuse me.
Wait! He is not done yet!
I will allow you ten days!
I will go receive it myself. Understood?
Are you alright with this?
No matter how wide Jipangu is, nobody dared to deny my request.
Moreover, I can't count how many people lost their lives by denying my request.
I am starved to death-dasu...
This smell must be dango-dasu!
Dango 5 mon
Tea 1 mon
My belly's going to meet my back-dasu...
Part Time Job Notice
3 mons an hour
Traffic expenses provided
Meal provided
Immediate interview
Sakai Ginja 634-5
Musical Tea House
Meal provided
Wow! It's a help from the heavens-dasu!
Are you ready?!
Yes!
Alright, let's get you working right away. Your job is simple.
Bring these whenever there is an order.
When is the mealtime-dasu?
After you work.
Okay.
One dango plate on the 3th table!
Got it! One dango plate!
Hey, hey! Hurry up and bring it!
Yes, sir!
Here it is-dasu!
Here is your order-dasu!
Huh? Otsuru!
What is it?
You're Otsuru-dasu! It's me-dasu!
I don't know who you are.
Don't joke on me-dasu! I am Musashi, from Miyamoto village-dasu!
I don't know anyone named Musashi!
Musashi?
Otsuru, it's me!
What are you talking about?! My name is Otama!
Otsuru, you're cute when you're angry-dasu...
What are you doing?! Help me! A pervert!
No, that's not it! There's a misunderstanding-dasu!
That was pretty bad. We don't need to trigger PTA any further...
I'm sorry-dasu...
It seems that you're not suited for working at the front of house. Maybe you're better off with carving dango sticks.
Uh, the meal...
-Not yet!
-Okay...
Musashi is working in this tea house.
Musashi, you're going down as of today!
Understand? Do not let Musashi run away!
Roger!
Oh , at least you have a specialty.
Where is Musashi?!
That voice...
What are you doing?!
Move away! Musashi is here!
Musashi! Prepare yourself!
There's Musashi!
Stop!
Musashi is running away on that roof!
They're damn persistent-dasu!
Huh?
Musashi! Prepare yourself.
Dammit! Do as you want-dasu! One vs many is cowardly-dasu!
Do not call this cowardly. I am more than enough to finish you!
Otsuru! I'm going to the next world earlier than you-dasu!
Damn that Musashi! Follow him! Find him!
What's going on-dasu?
Now! Run away! Come!
What a relief-dasu...
I must say thank...
Kojirō!
You insolent brat. How rude of you to call the name of your lifesaver without respect!
Sorry-dasu!
Thank you-dasu.
Bu- but why did you saved me-dasu?
I cannot forgive how the numerous grown-ups at Yoshioka are trying to chase a young kid like you!
I am not a kid!
Then what are you?
I am a martial artist despite how I look-dasu!
Hmph, don't make me laugh! You don't even have your own sword! You should be ashamed!
Th- that's too much!
A sword is the life of a martial artist! I will not accept whoever without a sword as a martial artist!
This excellent sword is Seki no Magoroku, also known as Monohoshizao.
Feast your eyes!
Hmph. Idiot.
What did you say-dasu?!
You're a showoff-dasu!
That was close-dasu...
Damn that Kojirō!
Musashi was insulted by Kojirō. Will he ever get a sword? Wait for the stormy latter half!
Caught one-dasu!
Hungry-dasu...
Here, Musashi. I made these rice balls for you. Eat as much as you want!
Thank you for all of these-dasu, Otsuru.
Otsuru, these are tough-dasu...
Tough...
Otsuru...
I can't eat-dasu...
Hey there! Brother!
Brother, why are you gnawing on stones?
I... I am too hungry to move-dasu.
Here, brother! You can have this!
That was good! I am full-dasu.
Thanks to you, kid, that really saved me-dasu!
But... weren't you going to take that fishes to your home-dasu?
It's all right! I can catch them again with this!
All right! If that's the case, brother will catch for you-dasu!
I did it!
You're awesome!
Thank you!
That was nothing-dasu.
But still, that harpoon pierces pretty nicely... Who made it?
My dad made this!
Dad?
The number one sword craftsman of Jipangu, Kenmochi Kotetsu!
I am his son, Kotarō!
Lucky-dasu!
Nope, no way.
Don't say that, and please help-dasu!
I really want a sword from a master craftsman-dasu!
I gave up being one!
Please, just one for me! Help me become the number one martial artist of Jipangu!
But it's your effort alone that will make you become the number one in Jipangu. I can't make you become one!
I already know-dasu! From now on, I'll risk my life for that-dasu.
But... still...
I... really want a sword from a master craftsman-dasu...
Please-dasu! I want a sword from an expert-dasu!
I want one-dasu!
What should I do with him?
I want a sword-dasu!
Sword...
Once decided, Musashi was persistent.
Please-dasu! I want a sword no matter whatever it takes-dasu!
Please-dasu! I want a sword of an expert-dasu!
-Please help me-dasu! I'll pay you-dasu!
-Dad...
Please-dasu! I need to be the number one martial artist of Jipangu...
Master Bokuden... I am so mortified-dasu...
Bokuden?
I won't be able to become the number one anymore...
Hey! Musashi! Wake up!
Ah! Good morning-dasu.
I must ask you; who is the master you learned swordsmanship from?
My master is Tsukahara Bokuden-dasu.
Do not lie! Bokuden does not take students!
Bu- but I really am his student-dasu.
Then tell me, the ultimate purpose of a sword, according to Master Bokuden!
Uh... what was it?
-What's the problem?
-Um...
You were lying at all!
I do not lie-dasu!
Then tell me right now!
This is going nowhere.
Wait! Just a moment! I remembered!
The true meaning of a sword is to win without fighting.
Solidness(武) of martial arts(武道) originally means to stop(止) a spear(戈); in other words, to stop a weapon.
To borrow the words of Laozi, the one who easily defeats an enemy does not engage.
Good job!
Yes! Thank you-dasu.
I have a reason why I stopped being a sword craftsman.
First, you must know that a sword has a spirit.
A sword inherits the mind of the crafter and the yielder.
To one with a wicked mind, the sword would also become so,
ending up as nothing more than a tool to take lives away. Do you understand?
I don't really understand-dasu, but I don't use swords to kill people-dasu.
Well said, Musashi. Your eyes are clear.
Because I had a good sleep.
Musashi, listen well. I will make swords for you for the last time.
Re- really?!
But you will have to learn the mind of sword craftsman.
Right!
The material of Japanese swords is iron sand of high purity that slept for a long time under the grond.
The iron sand must be forged thousands and millions of times wholeheartedly in order to make one.
I wonder if they're still not done yet...
-We did it!
-We did it-dasu! Hooray-dasu!
-Good job!
Musashi, these will be the last swords that I make in this world. Use them to the fullest.
Thank you so much-dasu.
Master Kotetsu! Huh? I suddenly got sleepy...
Dear! Big problem!
Wha- what's going on?
People from Yoshioka Dōjō came and...
What? He didn't made the sword I asked?
We will not accept any request from anyone!
Then I'll make him make one!
-You know what to do!
-Yes!
What are you doing?!
Help! I'm scared!
I will exchange your child for a sword made by Kotetsu. Tell him so!
Help me!
Kotarō!
What a cowardly gang. I will save Kotarō even if I have to exchange my life for him-dasu!
Kotarō! I'm going to save you-dasu!
Yoshioka Dōjō Inc.
Sakai Branch
Musashi has appeared!
-Musashi!
-How dare you!
Musashi is here-dasu!
No need to worry-dasu! It was the back side-dasu!
Prepare yourself, Musashi!
What is that posture?
Musashi! Don't you see this?!
Ko- Kotarō!
Give up with your futile resistance! Or this kid dies!
Musashi! Put down your sword!
D- dad!
Kotarō!
Unforgivable, Densichirō!
Spare me. I'll give you money as much as you want!
Unforgivable-dasu! I will send you to hell-dasu!
Musashi! Stop that right now!
Don't stop me-dasu!
Did you forget already, Musashi?! A sword does not exist to injure a person!
Master Bokuden would said so too!
If you kill this guy, you just end up disgracing your sword!
Alright-dasu.
And this is how Musashi has managed to get the excellent swords, Kotetsu.
And also, on that day, that famous dual blade has born,
but Musashi is yet to realize.
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
Master. A word with good echo-dasu.
Finally, I got a student-dasu!
A student is convinient! He lets me eat dangos without worry, and guides my path.
But this student is powerful than me, heh...
Next story! I am a Master! Excellent!
Be sure to check out the next stormy story-dasu!
Next Episode
I am a Master
Excellent!
Look forwards for it!