It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
On the journey to be the number one martial artist of Jipangu, from the master sword craftsman Kotetsu,
Musashi managed to get the excellent swords at last.
He was very satisfied! He felt like he already became the number one of Jipangu,
but what will be waiting in front of him? Wind or storm?
I am a Master
Excellent!
Ship is about to depart!
Repeat! Shop is about to depart!
Wait!
Just a moment!
I'll ride too-dasu!
Safe-dasu!
Anyway, since I'm training martial arts, so this is nothing!
Hmph! How unsightly.
What?!
Huh? Kojirō!
Hah, you call that training for martial arts? You look very unsightly, like a dancing duck!
Dancing duck?
That's right!
How dare you bastard insult me-dasu!
Unforgivable-dasu! Tamely do a fair match with me-dasu!
Oh, I see you got something that does look like a sword.
I see your training wasn't enough to identify where to draw your sword out and where not to!
Can't you think about the trouble to other passengers? Do not forget who you are!
But I wonder... isn't that sword a toy?
N- no way! This is an excellent sword made by Kotetsu, the famous sword craftsman-dasu!
By having a match, you will see its sharpness-dasu!
Pull your sword out, Kojirō!
What a hopeless guy.
Okay then. Let's have a match on there.
Agreed!
Now, Kojirō! I'll finish this as of today-dasu!
Huh?
I forgot that I had no time to play with a baby wild boar like you!
What did you say-dasu?!
Kojirō, you're cowardly-dasu! You're not a man-dasu! You're not even a martial artist-dasu!
This is a intense tactic that uses brain, Mutekatsu-ryu!
(Mutekatsu-ryu: 無手勝流. Winning without fighting)
Have a time to reflect on yourself! Idiot!
You're noisy-dasu! Shut up! Shut up-dasu!
Damn you, Kojirō! You cowardly bastard!
I feel so miserable-dasu...
I will never forget this-dasu!
Damn that Kojirō! If we meet again, I'll cut you into ten pieces-dasu!
What a great sword!
That's splendid! Excellent swordsmanship. I am genuinely struck with admiration.
Nah, I'm not on the level of that-dasu.
Your way of taking sword in is just right too...
I am a beginner martial artist named Kohē, and I want to be a student of yours.
Student? With me as the teacher-dasu?
Right. I will start calling you as master from now on.
Bu- but, I, yet, no, I... train... no, developing techniques...
Your modestly makes you even more elegant. I respect you.
Err, thanks. I'm grateful-dasu.
I see a tea house over there. I want to think about your teachings while you have some dangos.
Dango?!
I can't refuse that-dasu. I have no eyes for dango, no, for your enthusiasm, so I'll talk with you-dasu.
That's my master! The way you eat dangos is so manly and superb.
Right, if you are a swordsman, even when you eat, you must not be modest.
I see. With a excellent spirit...
If you want mine too, you can have them.
If you leave your food, you won't become a first-class martial artist-dasu!
I feel so full.
Owner! How much are they-dasu?
They are 100 mons.
100 mons?!
I have no money for that-dasu...
No, master. Leave such things to me, your student-dasu.
The food was excellent today. Here you go.
Thank you.
Having a student is convenient-dasu...
Studehehehehehe...
Kumanomiro from here
Jipangu Martial Arts Competition?
Yes. It is the most important martial arts competition of Jipangu at every year-end by Ieyasu, the shōgun of Edotopia.
What happens if I win?
Of course you become the number one martial artist of Jipangu.
With your level of technique, you cannot lose.
O- of course-dasu! From now on, I am heading to Edotopia-dasu.
I will go with you.
Something's not right-dasu. I think we're going inside to a mountain-dasu.
Huh? I see a sign there.
Do not enter. The life of violators is not guaranteed.
Hōzōin
Hōzōin.
Hōzōin? What a weird name-dasu.
Master. I've heard about them.
He is a monk, but he puts the sutras away, and he is told to be using a weird spear.
A monk is into martial arts-dasu?!
That's not all. It is told that he's gathering lots of students to start a war, planning to take down the country.
Takuan, a monk in my village, would shout YOU BRAT!-dasu.
With the master's power, let's punish them for the people and for the world!
No need to say-dasu. I will destroy such sign-dasu!
Huh?
What is it?
Is it you? Did you asked for a fight to master Hōzōin?
Hey. This person is my student-dasu.
If you have something to say, do it to me-dasu.
What, you? Stop with that joke and beg for pardon on your knees!
I'm not joking-dasu. I hate cracks, snails, and begging to a braggart-dasu!
You're not a simple brat, to ask for a fight instead of being obedient!
Don't cry even if it hurts!
-Master!
-Leave it to me!
I will take care of this bunch-dasu!
Then.
You brat, shut your mouth!
It doesn't matter now! I'll show you the Aragiri in Hōzōin flavor!
(Aragiri: 粗切り. rough cut)
This is nothing! I'll teach you something instead-dasu!
I am done for!
Don't overact! It's just the back side of sword-dasu!
I will not do something useless-dasu!
Don't be flustered in front of a brat! Surround him and beat him to death!
I am Musashi, working to be the number one martial artist of Jipangu-dasu. I won't be down so easily-dasu!
Master Musashi!
Don't get away from me-dasu!
Right! Master!
You're pretty good, Kohē!
No, this was by chance.
I was just imitating you.
They're being annoying! Finish them with real spears to make them shut up!
You bastards!
No, master! We have to run away from here!
No- nonsense-dasu! The cowardice of many people attacking us two is unforgivable-dasu!
Master! Are you alright?!
No problem. I've been playing using swords even when I was in my home town Miyamoto village!
Sword play is something to laugh about!
It is definitely a training-dasu! I'll show you clearly-dasu!
Don't let them run away!
Awesome, master Musashi!
This is nothing!
Master Musashi!
Maybe I pushed him too much...
You are now in the grave of nature that nobody can escape alive. One less trouble to face.
Is Musashi going to die like this? Wait for the stormy latter half!
Musashi? What are you looking at?
Clouds-dasu.
Clouds?
I will be a man with a bigger spirit than that clouds-dasu!
Right, you will be!
When that time comes, Otsuru,
That time?
When that time comes... what a soft hand-dasu!
So thin-dasu!
How slippery-dasu!
It's awkward, but I love you-dasu.
Otsuru!
Shocking... Wh- what is this place-dasu? It is like a grave for martial artists!
That means, I also will...
I don't want to die-dasu!
I must become the number one martial artist of Jipangu-dasu!
I will not break down by this-dasu.
I will not give up-dasu!
No more...
So this is the stronghold of Hōzōin.
Hōzō Temple
Are they planning to rebel over the shōgunate government?
A kid martial artist invaded?
Don't worry, Master Hōzōin. We've buried him into that cavern.
Hōzōin
Was he alone?
No, there was someone who is told to be his student, but that made no sense,
We are unrivaled
and he disappeared unbeknownst to us.
Get lost, you rat!
But what if it's a spy came to observe us Hōzōin family?
We do not have any secret that would bring us trouble.
On the other hand, the mountain housing our training site must be kept free of invaders.
Strengthen the defenses!
Yessir!
Please... somebody save me...
If I die here, I wouldn't be able to die without regrets-dasu.
So hungry... So thirsty too-dasu...
That student was heartless too after all-dasu...
If I knew I was going to end like this, I shouldn't bluffed about being a master-dasu...
Master! Master Musashi!
Hold this!
Wah! Rescue of heaven! Kohē!
So good! Thank you, Kohē. I owe you my life-dasu.
What are you saying, master? This is also what a student does.
Here it is. Your favorite food is dango, right?
So good! It's excellent-dasu!
These are nutritious dangos made with sticky rice, sesame, and honey, which also serve as emergency rations.
You have awesome things-dasu!
Calm down, master! Calm down!
Thanks to you, I'm fine now-dasu.
What's that temple?
It must be the castle of Hōzōin.
No. I will beat those ferocious monks who made me suffer black and blue.
Kohē, follow me-dasu!
Is anyone there?
Who is it?
You're that brat from yesterday!
So you live.
Musashi from Miyamoto village is immortal-dasu! I am here to settle this with a match-dasu!
Interesting.
Interesting. So you ask for a match to me, Hōzōin.
Being indiscreet is not a bad thing.
I am Musashi from Miyamoto village, working to be the number one martial artist of Jipangu!
I want to ask you for a match.
A match against a different school is prohibited, but I'll let you have one since you came all the way for this.
You there! Contend with him!
Right!
Match!
Let's start!
Huh?
I lost!
Next!
These ones are nothing-dasu! I want to have a match against Hōzōin-dasu!
Some confidence you have, to hold your sword against me. Well then.
But I do not have a match without a real sword. Will you accept?
That's what I wanted-dasu!
Musashi! ...Master!
Do not worry-dasu.
Come!
That's one strange lance-dasu!
(kamayari: 鎌槍. Spear with curved cross-blades)
This kamayari is the special weapon of our Hōzōin family!
Begin match!
Come!
I didn't put the metal part to my calculations-dasu...
Did you see? This is the specialty of kamayari of our Hōzōin family. This spear also can cut. It is capable of anything.
Prepare yourself!
I cannot find a way to take advantage of anything-dasu!
Finishing move!
Are you running away, you brat?!
That's not it! I just came out because the air was stale inside that limited space of Dōjō!
One second before you admit your loss!
I cannot move-dasu!
Time for skewering!
Prepare yourself!
Who did that?!
How dare you...
Huh? You're...
The opponent is a boy. If you must fight, I will content with you.
Emblem of hollyhock. He must be Jūbee, director of the police department who takes care of whole empire...
Jūbee
He has clear eyes without a cloud.
Did you see something?
A clear sky.
I am relieved to hear that.
Did you forget the match-dasu, Hōzōin? Prepare yourself!
I got you!
I lost.
Why-dasu? This match is a draw...
No. It is my loss, as my spear has been cut off, as well as my pride.
I will devote more, from now on.
Re- really?
I did it! I did it-dasu!
I want to have a new match against you in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition in Edotopia.
Your wish will certainly be achieved.
Then.
Take care!
Thank you-dasu!
You are an interesting boy, Musashi, to claim to have Jūbee, the unrivaled, as your student.
Ah, right. You forgot something-dasu.
I know that you saved me when I was in danger-dasu.
Oh... was that so? I was kind of busy...
To tell you the truth, I am not qualified to be your master-dasu. Please understand-dasu.
No. It's me who have to apologize. I am Jūbee of Yagyū Family(柳生家).
Yagyū Family? Then you must be directly under the shōgun...
I used you, Musashi, to spy upon Hōzōin, under the order of the shōgun.
That's why I must apologize.
No, instead, if you wasn't there, Jūbee, I would end up as a skeleton-dasu. Thank you-dasu.
Musashi. I am struck with admiration for the breadth of your spirit!
You're all talk again!
But still, I ask you for a match in the future once more-dasu.
Then, we shall meet again in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition.
That's a promise-dasu.
Right. Then see you at Edotopia.
Not knowing the world-famous Jūbee, he had a short but good dream, being called as a master.
Moreover, Musashi managed to have a good match against Hōzōin.
He was heading to Edotopia, heart rosen with dream and hope.
Who will be waiting for Musashi? Wind or storm?
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
Being on a journey alone really is tiring-dasu.
I was dozing, and what the?! My swords were stolen-dasu.
I met a man called Baiken while looking for the culprit,
but the real culprit was actually his brothers.
Next story! Clean and Poor Kusarigama-dasu.
There will be a stormy fight!
Next Episode
Clean and Poor Kusarigama
Look forwards for it!