It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
On his way to to Edotopia, Musashi was captured by Hanzō, the head of Iga ninjas.
But thanks to Kojirō, Musashi escaped by the skin of his teeth.
He keeps heading to the east, hoping to participate in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition.
A Man Ishimatsu
Friendship Falls
Shimizu Harbor is famous for the smell of tea and chivalrous men.
According to a folk song, that is this Shimizu Harbor.
Wait! Wait for me-dasu!
Wait for me-dasu! We'll settle this as of today-dasu!
Hmph. That noisy guy found me again, I guess.
Damn! Don't make fun of me again-dasu!
Now! Have a match-dasu!
There's a fight!
Now, Kojirō, pull it out-dasu!
Hmph. According to some people from the past, death is the only cure for idiocy.
What's that-dasu?!
This is also for you. Maybe I'll cure you for once.
Wait! Waitwait! Wait!
That fight! Just a moment!
You're not stopping us-dasu!
Idiot! I never said you to stop! If you're going to fight, why not have me, Ishimatsu, as your comrade?
Ishimatsu
Now! Tell me who's on the bad side!
Is it you?!
Or is it you?!
This is a real match done, with our lives at stake-dasu!
If you join for fun, it would bother us-dasu!
You brat!
What are you blabbering about? Fight and fires are not fun if it's not flashy and loud!
Now, get up! Get up!
How dare you hit the head of a martial artist-dasu!
You do pretty well, brat! Interesting!
No, I can't. I forgot about this.
What's the problem-dasu? I guess you suddenly got scared during talking about what's good in the life-dasu?
Brat! Who'd get frightened by a quack martial artist?!
Saw that? This is enough; a sword is overkill!
I am completely mad now-dasu!
I don't even have to touch such blunt sword! You may pounce on me from anywhere you want!
What's the problem? Are you frightened by my punch?
Hmph. I didn't feel a pain in the first place with that punch-dasu!
It's just that... my pride as a martial artist does not forgive attacking an opponent without sword using one-dasu.
Oh, at least your spirit is high, for a quack martial artist!
Stop calling me a quack-dasu!
Hmph. Those low-classes. I hope you play together for a while.
Fat pressure!
This is nothing!
Rope! Give me a rope-dasu! A rope!
Huh! You're pretty good for a quack!
Conversely, you're pretty interesting-dasu.
Hmph! Not trying to brag, but I, Ishimatsu, do not approve of anyone that's crooked!
Here it goes!
You got a stone for your head.
Same goes for you too.
-What was it all about?
-Idiots.
I see, Musashi!
Did you say that you're looking to be the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu? You looked pretty strong!
You do pretty well too-dasu, Ishimatsu.
Hmph, of course! Not trying to brag, but I, Ishimatsu,
is the number one fighter of Jirochou family, which just saying the name will make a babyt shut up!
Huh?
TEA
Hey, Musashi, wanna take a break over there?
That is, I don't have money...
Idiot! You can stop thinking about those stuff! I, Ishimatsu, know the best!
Huh, maybe he's out of any remaining strength.
Here is your order!
Whoa! I absolutely love dangos-dasu!
Indeed, I see! Musashi, you said you were born at Okayamāna, right?
Right. I've came from Miyamoto village-dasu.
Eat, eat! Eat your dangos!
Then, without hesitation!
Musashi, I like your attitude and whatsoever!
I really like you too, Ishimatsu!
Oh? That's happy to hear!
How's this, Musashi? Would you want to be a brother with me?
Huh? Our mothers are different-dasu!
Idiot! I'm not telling you to be a biological brother!
I'm telling you to be a friend deep in the hearts!
A friend?
Why, Musashi? Would you hate becoming friend with me?
No, that's not it-dasu!
I was never asked to be friends before-dasu...
Wait! Wait for me-dasu!
That's why I told you not to play with that violent Musashi!
I'll never play with him again.
Are you going back already-dasu? Let's play more-dasu!
Now, let's go back right now, as the food should be ready!
Yay!
Why is that-dasu? Let's play more-dasu!
You should go back too, Musashi.
Let's play again-dasu! Play with me-dasu!
It happened.
Why so blue? Hey, let's exchange the cup of brothers!
Hey, sister! Get us liquors!
We don't offer liquors!
Hmph, what an unprepared place!
Well then, let's end this with these dangos!
Brother! Looking forwards of us!
I also look forwards of us-dasu!
But, Ishimatsu, why didn't you pull out your sword-dasu?
That is because of this.
Huh? What's that-dasu?
Actually, I was going to a temple to give a prayer in place of our boss, Jirochō.
If I fought using swords during the road to the temple, I'd being rude to the dead.
Our boss has sealed this sword.
By the way, what were you going to ask for in the temple-dasu?
Ah, we have a big battle tomorrow, so I was going to pray for our victory.
Oh, I must hurry up.
Bye, brother! See you again if we are destined to!
I'll pray for you to be victorious in the fight-dasu!
Thanks!
He's awesome-dasu!
Then I'll go too-dasu!
Customer!
Please pay up!
Huh? Didn't Mr. Ishimatsu paid you-dasu?
Nope, not at all! 50 dangos, total 100 mons!
Even if you say so, I can't pay what I don't have-dasu...
Dear customer!
Were you thinking to run away without paying?
Nononono, that's not it...
Bro, it seems that you're troubled.
I can pay for you instead.
Really-dasu?!
Instead, I'd like you to do a part-time job in my boss' place.
Part-time job?
Yes. There's no way I'm paying for you for nothing.
You can eat and drink as you wish.
Moreover, you can even make extra money.
Wow! I'll do it-dasu! Please let me do it whatever it takes-dasu!
Great! Will do so!
So good-dasu.
One more dish-dasu!
You eat pretty well, for one who already ate dangos to death.
I'm seeking to be the number one martial artist, not only in swords, but also in eating-dasu.
Oh, by the way, are you also planning to participate in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition in Edotopia?
Of course-dasu.
What's so funny-dasu?!
Do you think a brat like you can participate?
I guess he's out of his mind after eating all that.
What did you say-dasu? That's rude, especially when you don't know what I can do-dasu!
Hmph! Then I'll show you that you wouldn't!
Jirobē!
No need to worry-dasu! It was the back side of sword-dasu!
How dare you defame my younger brother.
Please stop!
Kurokoma
While I don't know what happened here, since I'd like if you saved my face, Katsuzō Kurokoma's,
please put your swords back in.
-No, this guy...
-We all have to prepare for tomorrow's battle.
-But still...
-Please stop!
I'll remember this, you brat.
I apologize for showing you such bad things.
It's alright-dasu. Anyway, who are you fighting with-dasu?
Against Jirochō family.
It's bad. A battle against Ishimatsu...
Do you have any problem with that?
N- no, it's nothing serious-dasu.
This is bad-dasu...
Musashi has to fight against Ishimatsu unwillingly. Wait for the stormy latter half!
In the dead of night.
Someone opened a sliding door of Katsuzō family house.
Thankfully nobody's here-dasu.
I must not fight against Ishimatsu-dasu...
Mr. Musashi!
Where are you going in this deep night?
Uh, that is, to toilet.
Oh dear, the toilet is at there...
Are you planning to run away?!
Hey, watch your mouth when you're talking to a guest!
Sorry, boss.
You brat- no, you've had about ten times of a normal person.
If you don't work as much as you ate, that'd be bad, wouldn't it?
If you try to run away or something, you'll pay for that! I'm being polite.
Uh, no, that is... just... I was just practicing with my swords.
As a martial artist, I must not skip practicing even for one day-dasu.
Hearing that truly makes me happy!
Please do your best in tomorrow's battle.
But, why are you fighting against Jirochō family-dasu?
That is because Jirochō family is trying to take over the Shimizu harbor.
Jirochō family is a bunch of bad guys who always pull out their swords whenever they find something they don't like,
and they make children cry and don't follow the traffic lights - they only do bad things.
Were they really that bad-dasu? They didn't look so-dasu...
That's the trap! They approaches you with a kind face, and when you relieve, they show their fangs and...
I stood up to help the people suffering from Jirochō family.
Was that so-dasu? I apologize for trying to run away, not knowing the situation-dasu.
Leave tomorrow to me-dasu.
Please do so.
Got it-dasu!
And a new day came. Jirochō family and Katsuzō family have met in a field where Mt. Fuji was visible.
Ishimatsu, why did you have to become a comrade of bad guys-dasu?
Hey! Jirochō! You shall withdraw from Shimizu harbor as of today!
Jirochō
That's what I was going to say to you! It's not too late, so if you value your life, you'd better go back right now!
Shut your mouth! Go for it!
I've hit!
I hit with back side-dasu!
What? Back side?
That's good to know. Now, face me!
I have won this match-dasu!
This is not a match! This is a real fight!
You're persistent-dasu!
I have won this time for sure-dasu.
Hmph, who needs a sword when I have this instead!
Hey! What are you doing?!
I told you to do your best as much as you ate, but this wasn't what I expected!
No... I can't...
Wh- what are you doing-dasu?!
Hmph, you must be an idiot!
Wh- what is this-dasu? I'm on your side-dasu!
Hmph, that doesn't matter! You embarrassed me yesterday!
I'll finish you right here, right now!
Huh?!
Die, you brat!
I can't-dasu... My hand won't stop shaking-dasu!
Ishimatsu!
It was a close call!
Why didn't you pull out your sword?
But... but I...
I... my hands were shaking...
I get it. All right, Musashi.
Ishimatsu!
I... I was scared-dasu!
You idiot! If you were going to cry, you could have just not come to this battle!
That's your fault, Ishimatsu-dasu!
Huh? My fault? What are you talking about?
I came to punish you-dasu. I heard that Jirochō family are the bad guys who're trying to take over Shimizu harbor-dasu.
You idiot! You're talking about Katsuzō family!
This is for Jirobē!
Ishimatsu!
I'll finish you!
I... I cut a person for the first time-dasu...
Ishimatsu! Are you all right-dasu?
Musashi... A real fight is a decision of death of your enemy or yourself.
To pull out your sword is to prepare for your own death.
Ishimatsu!
Musashi. I am now done for.
What are you talking-dasu?! What's up with this weak talk?! That's not like you-dasu!
Musashi. Become the number one martial artist of Jipangu. In the afterworld, I shall be waiting for you to become one.
I will-dasu... I will become one-dasu!
So, please, Ishimatsu!
Ishimatsu!
Hey, Jirochou! Isn't it time for you to beg for your life?
I do not forgive anyone harassing the hardworking weak people in Shimizu Harbor!
Hmph! You're making me laugh! Just begone to hell!
Stop right there-dasu!
How dare you deceive me-dasu! Unforgivable-dasu!
Hmph, you are too late. Go to hell!
Give up-dasu, Katsuzō!
Please save my life.
I do not cut one without a sword-dasu.
Eat this!
But I shall not forgive this one-dasu!
Ishimatsu is dead because of you-dasu!
Jirochō boss!
That's enough.
No matter how much you hit him, Ishimatsu won't come back.
Ishimatsu... I... I...
Musashi, become the number one martial artist of Jipangu!
Musashi has realized what is to die, from the friendship between Ishimatsu.
And that a day might come that he dies by a sword of his opponent.
But don't grieve, Musashi! Today might have been bitter, but tomorrow will be bright!
Go forth, Musashi! On the road to the glory!
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
After a long and fun journey, I finally reached Edotopia,
but I helped a villain and I've captured by the boss Zenigatan-dasu.
If I fail to find the real criminal soon, I can't register for the martial arts competition-dasu!
Boss, please do something-dasu!
Next story! Flower and Storm at Edotopia-dasu.
Watch the stormy arresting story-dasu!
Next Episode
Flower and Storm at Edotopia
Look forwards for it!