It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
On the journey to the east, Musashi met Ishimatsu at Shimizu harbor.
Their friendship burns up by his personality that's similar with Musashi's.
But after the fight, Ishimatsu was cut to death.
Musashi is in deep grief, but he still heads to Edotopia.
Flower and Storm at Edotopia
I finally made it-dasu. This is the Edotopia that I admired-dasu!
Musashi was burning with the fighting spirit for Jipangu Martial Arts Competition starting tomorrow.
Otsuru is looking at me-dasu! I will become the number one martial artist of Jipangu-dasu!
I am hungry-dasu...
Otsuru... I want to have some of your rice balls-dasu...
Stop!
Stop right there!
Wh- what's going on-dasu? A pretty woman is being chased-dasu.
I told you to stop!
Now, prepare yourself.
It is unforgivable to bully a delicate girl-dasu!
It's all right now-dasu. Leave the rest to me-dasu.
Thank you so much.
Wh- what are you doing?! Stay out of this, or you will pay!
I'm scared!
Wh- what are you talking about-dasu?! You're a bad guy-dasu!
Don't say stupid! Don't you see who I am?!
Of course I do! You are a grown man-dasu!
That's not it! This truncheon is the seal of proof that I am authorized to catch that woman!
That changes nothing-dasu!
You're one stupid guy! You know who this girl is?!
She works for the thieves currently stirring up a storm in Edotopia!
Re- really-dasu?
It's not true.
See! There is no way such a pretty woman would do such bad things-dasu!
This guy is no good.
You're getting in the way! I'll catch you too!
How's that?
Hmph, justice always wins-dasu!
Dammit! You'll pay for this!
Thank you, kid.
I am not a kid-dasu. I am Musashi from Miyamoto village who will be the number one martial artist of Jipangu-dasu.
Musashi? That is a name with strong feeling.
You make me shy-dasu.
Anyway, Musashi, I have something that I want you to help.
I will do anything for a young lady like you-dasu!
Still...
Still?
I am so hungry-dasu.
Oh.
Stuffed himself up with noodles, Musashi accepted the request of this girl named Akane.
"I'd like if you protected my family from those people with truncheons you saw before."
That's what she said.
Then, Musashi, I'm depending on you.
Now that I'm full, I want to sleep-dasu...
Show me the money.
We got a situation! Everyone, hurry up to Daigokuya!
Right!
Zenigatan
Akane's voice...
Akane!
Now! Tie up the criminal right away!
We won't forgive you anymore!
Stop!
Wait! Wait for me-dasu!
Those bastards' comrades again-dasu? How persistent-dasu!
Musashi!
-Now! Akane, run away-dasu!
-Right!
Stop! Hey!
You won't do that-dasu!
You're in the way! Get him!
What impertinence!
Wh- what're you doing-dasu?!
Zenigatan! 4-mon Coin Throw!
You shouldn't throw money-dasu!
Hmph! I pick these up later on, so it's fine!
Finish!
4-mon coin, supersized!
Got you!
Good! Everyone, go get him!
He was so ignorant of the ways of the world.
But still, he called me miss! He's different from you.
Nonsense! You sound like you've lost your mind!
Magistrate's Office
Torture in session
How's that, Musashi?! Still not confessing?
No! I am not a friend of such thieves-dasu!
Then, who from where knocked me into water?!
I didn't know that truncheon was a sign of justice!
Do not make excuses!
Again, there was nobody with such thing in my village-dasu!
Then I'll ask you again. Why were you fooled by that woman?
No, no! Akana cannot be a bad person-dasu!
Are you that oblivious?!
Jipangu
Martial
Arts
Competition
Site
Musashi! The best of Jipangu!
Musashi, do your best!
The decisive match for the number one of Jipangu begins right now.
Kojirō, you shall lose!
What?!
You'll see!
Musashi... you've become strong.
Musashi, you're awesome! So cool!
Musashi! Let's marry right away!
This brat is laughing in coma!
He sure is stubborn! Throw him into jail!
He's new. Get along.
Is he dead?
Well, he at least looks alive.
Will Musashi manage to join the martial arts competition? Wait for the stormy latter half!
Huh? To see the fireworks that flashy... Is there an event today?
The first competition starts today.
I see, that's the martial arts competition.
That fireworks!
Hey, kiddo, what are you so surprised about?
Uh, mister! Is that the fireworks from the martial arts competition-dasu?
That's right.
Oh my god!
Get me out of here! Isn't there anybody around-dasu?!
Get me out-dasu! Damn!
Kiddo, be quiet!
Do you think I can be quiet-dasu?!
For today, nobody will listen to you no matter how you yell.
Why-dasu?
Everyone here are working as guards at the martial arts competition, so nobody's around.
Than what happens to me-dasu?!
Be obedient and be here.
No way-dasu! I came all the way to Edotopia to join the martial arts competition-dasu!
Then I'll use that way!
Here, in Edo Castle, the registration for Jipangu Martial Arts Competition has begun.
Totsugekiryū; Ue Yamadona.
Ue Yamadona.
Go to the sixth venue.
Ganryū; Mister Kojirō.
Yagyūshinkageryū; Jūbee.
Kusarigamaryū; Baiken! I participate!
You may call me Ushiwaka.
I am Benkei!
According to the rules of the first Jipangu Martial Arts Competition, we will accept entries until 6'o clock bell.
Also, for the majority of participants, as soon as you register, you'll have a match in respective preliminary place.
In Jipangu Martial Arts Competition, preliminary contest take place at seven different places.
3rd preliminary place
Place of Match
East! With the full mastership from Horigoshi family, Jūzaburo!
West! Ganryū; Mister Kojirō!
Mister Kojirō wins!
Master, I remember that person passing through our village.
That man will survive to the end.
I wonder where is Musashi...
He might be in another place.
Let's take a restroom break.
Yes.
Extra! Extra! A champion candidate has already appeared!
Huh? What's this?
A strong champion candidate appears in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition?
It's Ganryū Mister Kojirō.
Kojirō?
Are you serious-dasu?!
Idiot.
Why-dasu! Why must only I suffer this-dasu!
I never did something wrong-dasu!
I won't trust anything from now on-dasu...
I will curse the god too-dasu.
Boss Zenigatan, this kid is definitely innocent.
There is no way such pure guy would lie!
Wouldn't you feel uneasy if you charge someone innocent?
Moreover, if you find out the real criminal of this incident, wouldn't it lead to the one behind all this?
That's right.
According to someone, 100 times to the scene. Long before Edo period, they say one should return to
the scene and think again when there are not enough evidences.
Hey, you'd better remember something that will work as a clue.
Th- that is... I'm too hungry to use my head-dasu...
How handful...
One more bowl of kakesoba!
Here you go!
Huh, is there a hungry monster in your stomach or what?
I'm sorry for eating this much-dasu. Do you have money-dasu?
Of course, I have lots of coins.
I remembered.
Hm?
But really, Musashi, your stomach is terrific!
I also like noodles a lot, so I come to eat noodles at Ryōmokuya.
But I never saw someone like you before.
Noodles at Ryōmokuya.
Ryōmokuya.
Ryoumokuya.
What took you so long to remember that?!
But Ms. Akane cannot be a bad person-dasu!
Hmph, forget it!
Extra! Extra!
Another amazing martial artist has appeared! The name is Baiken!
Baiken...
Oh, right!
Don't stop so suddenly!
I forgot! I must go enter-dasu!
Not yet. You are not proven innocent yet!
First, do this properly right now!
But... the deadline!
It's all right.
There is still some time until 6'o clock!
Look! The noodle house we were looking for!
There it is!
Hey, genius! Surrender!
What are you doing?!
What was that for?! You almost hurt me in my back!
You're a woman with all talk!
Now, tell me where your friends are! Spit it out! Or else, it's gonna hurt!
Now, now, now!
What's holding you up?
Musashi!
It's all right now-dasu.
What the heck are you doing?!
Akane didn't do anything-dasu!
That again? You can't be that stupid!
Behave already!
You open your eyes-dasu!
Akane let me have all the noodles until I was totally full, when I was starving to death-dasu!
There is no way such a kind person would do bad things-dasu!
Whatever you say, if you're going to get Akane, I'll protect him for my life-dasu!
Musashi! I'm arresting you for obstruction of justice!
That's what I wanted-dasu.
I guess you used all the money-dasu!
Too bad, but I still have some!
Big coin! 4-mon coin throw!
Hmph, that chair made me miss the target.
Consider yourself lucky, Musashi!
Guards down-dasu?
Akane! Now-dasu! Hurry up and run away-dasu!
B- but... what about you?
I- I'll be all right-dasu. Just run away-dasu!
How's this? Are you still going to accuse Akane as a criminal-dasu?
Musashi, you can stop now.
I give in.
Sorry. To tell you the truth, I work for the thieves just as the boss, Zenigatan, said.
I was happy. Only you, Musashi, trusted me this much.
Akane...
No! Musashi! That's the 6'o clock bell!
Hurry up to the castle!
Now, Musashi! Go for it!
Akane! Let's have noodles together again-dasu!
Wait for me-dasu!
After trusting a person single-mindedly, Musashi managed to change a person.
But sadly for Musashi who wanted to be the number one martial artist of Jipangu, he didn't make it to the registration.
What is waiting in front of Musashi? A rain, a storm, or a typhoon?
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
For not making it to the martial arts competition registration, I can't participate-dasu.
So frustrating! I sneaked into a locker room and got to join for the competition-dasu.
But after all I guess I can't do bad things-dasu...
Now that my identity is revealed, I am now being pursued by officials as a criminal-dasu.
Next story! Raid into the Martial Arts Competition-dasu.
Check out the stormy great activity!
Next Episode
Raid into
the Martial Arts Competition
Look forwards for it!