It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
During their trip, Musashi and others met with Baiken once again.
And Baiken gave them a dish in a superb residence.
But their happiness didn't last long; they had to fight against a monster named Nue.
But thanks to aid of the friendship with Baiken and cooperation of Kojirō,
they took Nue under the control of Onihime down and saved Date family.
Shuten Explodes
The Cursed Valley is over deep there. What is going on?
What could that be?
Missing Gohachi and Heisuke are also there!
I must let villagers know about this.
Are you sure that we aren't lost?
My nose do not have a problem-dasu!
You have zero scientific evidences.
That's not it-dasu.
Don't fight with something that pointless! Let's just hurry up to an inn in a lively town.
We're not going to find one in this rate.
Huh?
This! My nose definitely works perfectly-dasu! Tasty-looking dumplings-dasu!
Hey, Musashi!
Musashi!
Who is it?!
Karakuri martial artist! Have a match with me!
A match?
Forget it, kiddo.
I am not a kiddo! I am Santa! Face me!
You coward! I won't forgive even a child-dasu!
It's because you touched the offering to Ksitigarbha!
W- what?!
Stop right there, Musashi.
Just as Santa said! It's all because you were being crude!
But Kojirō don't give me any allowance or buy me a food...
Why are you wandring?
I just tested my skills.
Test?
I see! You want to be a martial artist, right?
I will become a parent like my dad!
It seems that you have some situation.
While you look like you're showing off, you seem to be with some skills. I'll hire you.
Hire me?
It's not for free, of course. Take my treasure.
This is alluvial gold!
Is that gold in other words-dasu?
Those are large drops!
Will you accept this?
But, you know...
I will take that instead-dasu!
You are not skilled enough to save my dad!
Tch, he's not cute at all...
-Kojirō?
-I can't just let this pass by.
With gold that much, I'll be able to get dumplings, dangos, sweet red bean paste, ...
I'll finally be able to fill my stomach to the full extent-dasu!
Hey, wait for me! I'm going too-dasu!
What is it, Jiraiyan?
Shuten wanted to pay back his debts with me.
Gold bars, eh... But this is not enough for redemption of failure of assaulting Senhime.
We know that well. Not only this, but also we wanted to offer you war funds of thousands and millions of ryos instead.
Now that's an another story. There are lot of war funds required to take General Ieyasu down and become Shōgun.
Yessir. I'll be back after making war funds with Shuten.
Then.
Wait, Jiraiyan.
Leave the gold mountain to Shuten. You will keep an eye on Jūbee.
Jūbee?
That Jūbee bastard...
It is clear that he is protecting Senhime and others in shadow and observing us in the back.
That's why I'm ordering you, Jiraiyan, to find out Jūbee's traces and assassinate him.
Yessir.
And when we got Senhime in our hands, we'll take the shōgunate down at once.
And then, the world will fall into my hands.
Missing?
Yeah. People who went to hunt or to mushroom... There are 8 people from our village.
And your dad, too...
In The Cursed Valley, there must be an evil creature.
Yeah.
Hm? My nose is detecting something-dasu.
That fish is dead-dasu.
What's going on-dasu?
The water must be toxic.
A evil creature must have took his place.
There's nothing to worry about that evil creature-dasu! I'll cut it with my dual blades-dasu!
And...
It's the sound of that creature.
That's the sound of the creature.
Leave it to me-dasu!
There are Senhime and Musashi.
O- Orochi!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
I will never forget the failure and the humiliation I received from them even if I die.
The Cursed Valley will be your permanent graves.
You will see.
T- this is...
Daddy!
Do not come, Santa!
Santa!
You monster bastard!
You really did it!
My body is getting stiff-dasu!
Santa!
Daddy!
Musashi! Santa!
Senhime, please hide in somewhere safe.
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
Are you alright?
You bastard!
Kojirō!
You...!
One of Four Iga Kings, Shutentiger!
I will resolve my hatred as of today!
Kojirō and Musashi, I will cook you slowly.
Not only my dad but also everyone... What should I do?
What a big and severe crisis! Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
I will send you as an offering along with these treasures. Behave until then.
Musashi... Kojirō...
You brats! Work properly!
Do you want to become like this hinderance?
Hurry up and work!
Now, how should I cook them up?
Dad...
Santa...
Hey, dad!
I see! Mud melts by water!
Santa!
Dad!
Cutting your neck into two at once won't resolve my hatred.
I will kill you with this, little by little.
How does that feel?!
I see, I see! You're happy!
Stop it-dasu!
It's almost there, Musashi! My chainsaw will tear off your body into pieces.
It seems that it's touching your body. Time to break you into two pieces.
Take this!
You guys! What was that for?!
Unforgivable!
Santa!
Die!
Stop-dasu!
I'll face you-dasu!
What an impudent brat! I'll face you as you wished!
Santa, please take care of Kojirō of Osenchan-dasu!
Leave it to me!
Anyway, I'm looking you again, Musashi!
How audacious of you, to use dual blades?!
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, rise up!
You're here again-dasu! That monster before!
Oh, that's not gonna work anymore-dasu!
That's cheating-dasu!
I look miserable again-dasu!
My eyes are spinning-dasu~
Cut it off-dasu!
Musashi! That clay warrior is made out of mud!
Water will melt mud!
I got it-dasu!
Chase me if you can, you pile of mud-dasu! How's this?!
I did it-dasu!
Shuten! Take my Tsubamegaeshi!
Secret sword or not, that Tsubamegaeshi won't work twice!
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, rock smasher!
You really did it-dasu!
Using magic is cowardly-dasu! Face me with your sword like a real man-dasu!
Don't make me laugh! Winning is important. Winning.
W- who was that?!
That brat!
Now's the time-dasu!
What?!
I can't take my sword back!
Niten'ichiryū - Sword of Crab's Scissors!
That was close.
Acting cool again? I'm more than enough for that-dasu!
I gotta show off for at least once.
You bastard! a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, hurricane state!
We'll rescue Mr. Kojirō and Mr. Musashi!
Push!
-The tornado
-has stopped!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
Prepare yourself, Shuten!
Niten'ichiryū, Ten(十) Shaped Cut!
Wow, it's pretty!
Whoa...
Ack, it's gold-dasu, it's gold-dasu! I can't collect them in this rate-dasu!
Those bastards... Musashi's group is interfering again...
Unforgivable! I will employ any means to take their lives away!
We are sincerely grateful for all your work here.
Thank you, Mr. Kojirō and Osenchan.
Your dad surely have understood your feelings by now, Santa!
-Hey, where's Musashi?
-Huh?
All that gold were spread into air-dasu.
I'm going to recover my investment by eating rice-dasu.
Hey, Musashi! Don't be voracious!
One more bite...
He's such a glutton.
You're right. He should be practicing self-discipline, and moreover, this is a trip with an importan objective.
I'm hungry... Dango... Dumpling...
-Mr. Musashi!
-Huh?
Santa!
What's wrong-dasu?
Here! Your lunch box.
Yes! Santa's parents are great!
You can't train when you're hungry. Do it properly, Musashi!
Got it! I'll do my best-dasu!
Hey, are you being cocky to me, the number one of Jipangu?
I'll get you!
Thinking to help and actually helping, for the love despite any humiliation during the help,
a man must have a way of life of breaking through the violent wind of flowers.
Wild flowers are smiling. Go, go, Musashi! Hit hard!
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
Hot springs are the best when we're tired from a journey! That's why we stopped by a hot spring hotel-dasu,
but what?! There's a mountain around here which dead people's spirits gather.
I met again with my beloved Mr. Ishimatsu there-dasu! I wish him to go to heaven without getting lost!
Next story! Woah! It's Ishimatsu's Ghost!
It's a stormy great spiritual realm-dasu!
Next Episode
Woah!
It's Ishimatsu's Ghost!
Look forwards for it!