It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
During his trip, Musashi met Ishimatsu's ghost in Osorezan and were asked to die together.
But that was a trap of Onihime.
But in front of Musashi's Tornado, that ambition has been collapsed.
The Sea is Scary
It's Onigoroshi
A clean blue sky without a single cloud.
Musashi and others were heading to Hokkaido lightfootedly and lightheartedly.
No matter which way I look at, I can only see the sea! It's wide, it's blue, and I like the salty see breeze!
It's as if some waves are on a big blue canvas. Senhime, please watch out for seasickness.
It's alright, don't worry! I have no problems riding things.
That's true, but you can see someone who can't over there...
What? Senhime and her subordinates are heading to Hokkaido?
Yessir. It is a fresh information.
That cursed Senhime... Trying to interrupt my great plan in Hokkaido?
Karakuri Owl, let Onigoroshi know about this.
Is that Hokkaido over there?
Finally. We're almost there.
That's a relief-dasu... My head was getting limp ever since I got onto this ship-dasu...
I wonder what that is.
It surely does not look like a fish...
What's wrong-dasu?
Karakuri Shark is coming to attack!
Karakuri Shark?
We're going down at this rate!
What should we do?!
I don't know how to swim-dasu...
If there's a lifeboat somewhere...
Huh?
Onigoroshi
(Oni[g/k]oroshi: lit. Demon Slayer in Shōgi, an eastern chess)
I- it's Onigoroshi!
Onigoroshi?
Everyone! Go take all the money and treasures!
Yessir!
Musashi!
Got it-dasu!
Everyone! Take whatever that will make money!
Run away!
Who are you?!
A pirate like you asking me my name is impertinent!
You are one cocky kiddo! I'll make you sink to the very grounds of the sea!
Kojirō!
Damn!
Take everything before the ship sinks!
What will happen to us if we sink like this?
Just leave it to me-dasu. I will protect Osenchan-dasu!
That was one useless help...
I wonder if Kojirō's okay...
Osenchan, hurry up and move-dasu!
Musashi!
Hurry up-dasu!
I'm sorry!
We're moving out!
Musashi!
Kojirō! Where are you?!
W- who's touching my hip?
Musashi!
Musashi...
Huh?
What should I do with him...
I was born in mountains, and because of that, I never swam in sea...
I can swim in river for a little-dasu, though...
How undisciplined are you! A martial artist may not be skillful in swordsmanship, but...
Karate!
Judo!
Baseball!
Skating!
Abacus!
are the least one has to do.
Moreover, I have swimming skills of rank 3.
Hmph! I can at least use abacus-dasu!
Yeah, sure! Try calculating this in your head: someone has 159 yen, 257 yen...
Shutupshutupshutupshutupshutup!
Did you really think now is the perfect time do mental figuring?!
Senhime, somebody named Kojirō just did an unsightly act...
Disembowel yourself-dasu! Go commit suicide!
What the hell?
Hey, over there!
Look! Look over there!
It's a ship-dasu!
Everyone! Get on my ship!
Yes!
Is it you, Karakuri Shark? Good job. I applaudyou for that.
You must be... Finally, an order from Lord Hanzō.
Senhime and others just escaped from the evil hands, but another disaster was again waiting for them.
What do you think about her shying face-dasu? Does it mean that-dasu?
Her hot eyesight is never seen before. Her spirit is burning down in front of that guy.
As I thought-dasu...
Let's see how it goes for now.
Um...
What is it?
Can I ask your name?
I am Daisuke.
I am Sen. Looking forwards together...
There was a shark, right?
Huh?
Karakuri Shark, you know.
Uh, yeah, there was.
Do you know Karakuri Shark?
I am chasing that Karakuri Shark.
Karakuri Shark, you say-dasu?
Right.
Why is that?
It is a detestable guy that the pirate Onigoroshi uses.
It killed my dad.
Your dad?
My dad was a skillful fisher. But when he tried to help the ship being attacked by that...
Dad!
I see. That was a terrible thing to happen to your dad...
I will have revenge for my dad, by taking that down.
I understand your will to have revenge for your father well. But your opponent is a huge and fierce Karakuri.
If you get hurt, your dad will be sad.
Stop. Don't talk like that.
Mr. Daisuke will not lose. He will never die. Right?
Of course. I will not die. At least until I take that Karakuri Shark down.
So cool... I'm getting mesmerized!
Musashi! Kojirō! We will help too!
H- help...?
If I get drowned again...
Then learn how to swim!
Please wait. Even if it's an order, I, Kojirō, got my job from General Ieyasu,
and I cannot let you be dragged into a dangerous job like shark extermination!
Oh, what did you say, Kojirō? Are you saying that you're fine with me not being able to marry for the rest of my life?
That's not what I meant.
Then will you do as I said?
Okay...
Does this mean Musashi, who can't swim, will have to drown again? Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
Senhime has decided to help with Daisuke's revenge, and she asked for a help to the feudal lord of Matsumai [?] castle.
And while then, Kojirō was giving Musashi a training.
Musashi! Do it properly! Learn!
One! Two! One! Two! One! Two! One! Two! One! Two!
Kojirō, I'm already tired-dasu...
Don't be a crybaby! Efforts! Guts! Spartan!
The heck...
That was painful-dasu...
By the way, Musashi, why can't you swim in seas, when you can in rivers?
T- that is-dasu... a bit embarrassing-dasu...
Seawater is saltwater-dasu, right?
Yeah.
That is, I like sweet dangos and dumplings, but not the salty ones-dasu.
What?
Moron.
Mr. Daisuke!
I wasn't late, after all!
I was about to go exterminate the shark.
I have something to give to you.
What? Something for me?
It'll be here soon.
Look!
It's here!
You mean, that ship?
Osenchan!
T- that ship, for me...
Yeah. Have revenge for your father with that!
With that scrap ship?!
It does look so, but it is full of secret weapons!
I see! Thank you so much, Osenchan!
I wonder if we can meet that Shark well...
No need to worry! We're having this much load. It is bound to appear.
Karakuri Shark!
You've finally appeared, Karakuri Shark! I will have the revenge for my dad today!
It's gonna get us!
N- no way!
-A- awesome!
-Yeah, it is! I specially asked for this!
On this ship, we'll be alright even if that Karakuri Shark decides to do a ramming attack.
That's right-dasu!
That must be Senhime.
Lord Hanzō will award me a lot of goods.
Onigoroshi!
Musashi and I will face Onigoroshi. You will exterminate that Karakuri Shark and have revenge for your father.
Got it.
Mr. Daisuke... You can do this...
Mr. Daisuke...
Alright! Musashi, let's scare those pirates!
Right-dasu!
Those brats! Unforgivable! I will show my horror!
Mr. Daisuke!
Bet you were scared, you brat!
I was scared-dasu...
But I will not lose-dasu! You may come attack-dasu, Onigiri-korori(Rolling rice ball)!
W- what?! It's not Onigirikorori! It's Onigoroshi!
What? Onikorori(Rolling monster)?
It's Onigoroshi!
I can't hear you-dasu! Is it Onigoro(Monster hooligan)?
You think you're clever, eh?!
Wait right there, you brat!
Now, a hell is waiting in front of you brat!
That's hmph for you! You're the one to go to the hell-dasu! I'm going to dango store-dasu!
Then go to the dango store in hell!
This isn't working. I must do something...
Mr. Daisuke!
Please! Throw a spear to here!
Got it!
I'm throwing this, Mr. Daisuke!
Right!
Here!
Watch out! You almost got me!
I- I'm sorry!
But you didn't have to talk harshly...
Aim for its eyes.
Musashi! I'm done down here!
Just a moment-dasu! I'm about to get Onikorori soon-dasu!
What a big mouth you have, you Musakurushii(filthy)!
It's not Musakurushii, you Onisangorochi!
It's Onigoroshi!
What's wrong with them?
Just prepare yourself!
I don't prepare-dasu!
Do not be surprised, Musashi. One, two, one, two. You know the rhythm.
That's right-dasu. One, two, one, two-dasu. Even in saltwater I can do this-dasu.
One, two, one, two, one, two, one, two...
I'm swimming smoothly-dasu! Swimming in ri-ver isn't re-ally different here-dasu. Also, I'm good at jokes-dasu.
Mr. Daisuke!
Mr. Daisuke, are you alright-dasu?
I'm alright! I can't die until I have revenge for my dad!
W- watch out!
Mr. Daisuke, it's dangerous here-dasu! Let's escape-dasu!
No, I won't run away! You can escape by yourself!
That's nonsense!
We're running away-dasu!
Thank you. I could have revenge for my dad thanks to you.
I don't know how to repay this...
No, you don't need to do anything. I'm happy if you're happy.
I will become a fisher again.
I like eating fishes really much! I can eat them every day.
Osenchan is saying that-dasu...
Shh!
Mr. Daisuke!
Hey, Osaki!
Then I'll be going!
Yeah...
I knew this was coming-dasu.
Agreed...
Osenchan! I can swim now-dasu!
Wow, Musashi did a great job!
Yeah. There will be at least one or two people I like that actually will become my lover, right?
That's right-dasu! Don't feel bad, and let's go eat some Sapporo ramen-dasu!
Right! With a lot of bean sprouts!
Bean sprouts-dasu!
Wait for us!
Bloomed at a northern sea, and evanescently fell is a flower of love.
But just like the inside Senhime's heart, she kept traveling strongly and brightly. Who will understand her at last?
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
We met Baiken brothers during our way to Hokkaido again-dasu.
We ate great ramens, bask ourselves and it was all warm, but soon,
to help the temporary dwelling being attacked by suspicious ninja force,
we run over a vast plain of limitless white on a covered wagon!
Next story! Desperate Struggle in Hokkai-Western
It's a stormy Musashi Priority Mail Express-dasu!
Next Episode
Desperate Struggle
in Hokkai-Western
Look forwards for it!