It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Musashi fell into Jigokudani. Despite everyone's nursing, Musashi was lured by dango's smell and died.
But who he met in hell was deary Ishimatsu.
In hell, Shuten and Onihime were doing whatever they want since they had obtained the Register of Hell.
With Ishimatsu, Musashi took them down and put them into the hell of infinite suffering.
And Musashi crossed over the Sanzu River, and revived safely.
Mysterious
Ms. Himiko
Life has its ups and downs. Let it go through, Kerokichi.
Well, now that we've taken some rest, let's begin selling again!
Great! That relay station will just do. You know what to do, Kerokichi!
I wonder if he'll be alright.
He didn't even eat...
I can't believe that big eater isn't eating. I wonder what is he troubled about.
If Musashi can be troubled, then it must be meaning that he can think. I didn't know.
Thank you, Kerokichi, good job! I've been feeding this frog for 80 years! Now I can even talk with him!
He says that today's audiences were so great!
Now, let me tell you about my invention that took 79 years of research... huh?
That's...
Right. That's the woman that Musashi looked like he was so friendly with her.
That woman has a suspicious atmosphere.
Hey!
And so what?!
Hurry up and continue!
Oh, ah, right, right! Today's sale ends right now! Thank you for your interest!
Then see you next time!
Hey! Are you leaving already?! You did nothing yet!
(To sell oil: Japanese expression; to loaf)
This is how you sell oil!
Did you wait for a while?
No. I just came here
Hanzō!
I knew that woman isn't an an ordinary person.
Damn! What the heck are they talking about?
They're too far away to listen to!
But it is dangerous to go closer...
Yes! Kerokichi, you do it!
Musashi used to interfere us all the time, but since he's dead now, Kojirō and Senhime are nothing to fear about.
What?! Musashi's dead?!
Musashi used to deal with whatever we were doing, but not anymore.
He was an interesting boy. Maybe there was no need to kill him...
I hope you're not being serious.
It's a joke.
That sounded like you were serious.
So that's why now's the perfect chance. Shiranui Clan should act in full-scale.
Of course. For Shiranui Clan to claim the whole islands, we have to take control of the kingdom of Saikai first.
I, Hanzō, will help you to the best of my ability.
I know you will.
Now for the concrete plan...
And?!
Damn!
Who's there?!
I wonder if many frogs live here.
Get rid of that guy.
Kerokichi!
Here we go!
Do not let them get away! Chase them!
They're so persistent...
I'm hungry now...
That Musashi's been ahh-ing for hours...
Hey, Musashi! That's enough!
Don't do that.
I wonder if my mom was a person like her-dasu...
Musashi?
Oh, mom!
Musashi!
He is longing for his mother since he revived.
Did he meet his mother in heaven?
But there's no way Musashi's going to heaven...
So, his mother went to hell?
It's about Musashi's mother. That totally makes sense.
What are you babbling about?! Know to worry about Musashi at least for a bit!
Are you okay, Musashi?
Don't you know that this is not the time for that?!
You shouldn't be so cold to him. Who found Hououmaru when your sword was broken, Kojirō?
T- that's... Musashi.
Isn't it our turn to cheer up this guy?
Yes.
Oh, right! This will do it! Musashi, let's go for mudskipper fishing!
Huh? Mudskipper?
Look! That's it!
No, it's too difficult for newcomers. You people can wait there; I'll take some for you.
That's happy to hear! Thank you, old man! Get a lot for us!
What is mudskipper-dasu?
I'll explain. Sit down and listen well, Musashi.
Hmph. Go ahead.
Mudskippers are a type of goby fish. They live around Saikai sea, but then these fishes live in sea of mud.
One will be sunken in if one tries to get one directly,
but by using that ski-like board, one can efficiently move on squishy sea of mud and catch mudskippers.
To catch mudskippers, one can throw a fishline with a hook without any bait. But as he said, it's difficult for newcomers.
But are the fishes living in mud tasty-dasu?
They say, it totally is!
Really-dasu?!
Here you go!
Already?! Thank you!
I was lucky to get this much so quickly!
Hey, take a look, Musashi! There are a lot!
Huh, are these tasty-dasu?
I'll cook these for you!
Cooking is easy! You can simply grill them with fire!
To be able to receive Senhime's handmade food, I, Kojirō, can now find worth in having lived this long to this age!
Kojirō, do you think I'm a fool?
Er, that's impossible! I'll never treat anyone as a fool...
Jiraiyan.
Huh? Musashi!
Watch out! Watch out!
Musashi! You were alive!
Of course! I knew that it's impossible for you to die!
Jiraiyan, why is Shiranui on your back-dasu?!
They're damn persistent...
It's a dead end!
One thing after another! Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
Musashi!
Kojirō, will Musashi and Jiraiyan be alright?
Worry about the situation we're in, not about someone else!
It's alright! Kojirō's strong!
Err, um, you're making me shy... you're telling me the truth... am I that strong and cool?
S- s- snake!
Kojirō! That snake!
W- who are you?!
Tenzen of Snake Flute
I am Tenzen of Snake Flute of Shiranui Clan! I will take Senhime's life!
You guys! Whoever takes Senhime's head will be awarded with 1 year worth of rice from Shiranui Farm!
Whoever takes Kojirō down will be awarded with 1 year worth of rice from Sakurajima!
This is bad...
Hebiko. Find Musashi and Jiraiyan, and come back after taking care of them.
Are you friends with that snake?
She's not my friend! She is my cute sweetheart.
Disgusting...
Say whatever you want! You'll become Hebiko's feed soon!
Aren't you good at joking?! We'll make her into a broiled snake and eat instead!
You won't be saying that for long!
Go!
This is pretty tough even for me.
Get a grip, Kojirō! Are you fine with me becoming a snake's feed?!
She's not caring for me at all!
Did you say something?
No! Not at all!
Oh! Mr. Ushiwaka! And Mr. Benkei in addition!
I am not an addition!
Senhime, can we help you?
Of course!
Musashi, open your eyes. Musashi, wake up. You must not die.
You will become the strongest Karakuri martial artist of Jipangu. For that dream to come true, you must not die here.
Musashi! Fight! Open your eyes! Survive, Musashi!
Jiraiyan!
We survived-dasu...
Jiraiyan! Jiraiyan!
You woke up-dasu!
Musashi. You saved me. What about Kerokichi?
That's great-dasu!
You bastard!
Now, who's next?
Tch! Senhime, take care of this country for a moment!
Everyone, find Musashi's dead body first. Senhime can be dealt with later!
Really! They're running away whenever they're at disadvantage! Cowards!
Let's go find Musashi and Jiraiyan too.
Isn't it just your imagination?
You must not die here. Open your eyes. I definitely heard it.
It might be your mother's voice...
I don't know how my mother looks like-dasu. There's no way for me to remember her voice-dasu.
But...
But?
The voice was somehow similar to that of Ms. Himiko-dasu.
Himiko? About her...
Oh, at a place like that? Well, I never thought they can go far away in such a short time.
You guys! Musashi is on the sea rock ahead of you! Whoever brings them down will be awarded with 1 year worth of grains!
Hmph! Jiraiyan! There are some jokes you can say and some that are bad in the world-dasu!
I'm not joking! It's true!
That's a lie-dasu! It's obvious it's a lie that Ms. Himiko talked together with Hanzō of all people
They were not just simply talking together! They were laughing together!
No way! Are you suggesting that they were some kind of lovers-dasu?!
Yes! They were holding hands!
It's a lie-dasu!
-There they are!
-Over there!
Musashi! We'll talk about this later!
I'll make you into the feed of my sword-dasu!
Their number has decreased already-dasu.
Would you like to fight in 2:2?
My 1 year worth of grain...
A big snake-dasu!
Now! do it, Hebiko!
Musashi! Run away!
Kojirō! Hurry up even more! Musashi'll end up being drowned to death!
I'm, really, rowing, to, my, best!
That was close...
Oh, Musashi, were you there? Great!
Nothing's great-dasu.
I'm sorry to hear that, but you know, it's not me who crashed!
No way! You're laying the blame on me!
Hurry! Hurry!
You persistent bastards! I'm going to make all of you including Senhime into Hebiko's feed!
Leave this guy to me-dasu.
My specialty was extirpating snakes ever since I was young-dasu!
Great to know.
Snakes are my favorite food-dasu!
What kind of life did you have?
Smash him up!
Damn!
Prepare yourself!
Hebiko, let's be happy together on the other world.
Open your eyes, Musashi. It's painful, but you must know the truth!
That can't be true-dasu!
Himiko is-
Shut up, shut up, shut up! Shut up, shut up, shut up-dasu!
Ms. Himiko was so kind to me-dasu!
Nothing will be done if you don't accept the reality.
Don't talk! I don't want to listen-dasu!
I don't want to listen-dasu.
I get it, Musashi.
Himiko gave Musashi the memories of mother, but then she's the queen of Shiranui Clan? Musashi didn't want to believe.
It's too painful to acknowledge that. Is she her mother or a queen? What's your choice, Musashi?
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
What? Mr. Saigo's house is burned down?
Those damn Shiranuis! They finally chased us to Mr. Saigo's house-dasu!
I can't stay silent here.
I will prove that Ms. Himiko is not the queen of Shiranui by invading to their base-dasu!
Next story! Fire Here and There
It's the stormy Mr. Saigo's house-dasu!
Next Episode
Fire
Here and There
Look forwards for it!