It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Not long after reviving and taking some leisurely time, Shiranui Clan appeared, chasing Jiraiyan.
But with everyone's power, they repelled them.
But the words Jiraiyan left before he left, that Himiko is the queen of Shiranui Clan, has knocked down Musashi's heart.
Fire
Here and There
Musashi! Where are you?
He's not here? Really!
Musashi! You were there! When will you be done? Get out promptly!
Wait, it's me-gowasu!
I'm sorry!
Hey, Kojirō!
Excuse me! I see you're putting on makeup!
No way! Why would I want to hide and put on my makeup?! Really...
Well... are you sure that you didn't?
Of course!
Oh, anyway, do you need to see Musashi right now?
I've been finding him everywhere, but I couldn't find him. I wonder where is him...
I see. I did think that fighting and splitting up with Jiraiyan isn't like them.
You know it!!
Well, I guess leaving him be like that is better than being impertinent and bothering oneself to interact with a fool.
Do you know what? About Himiko lady Jiraiyan told me about...
N- no way! That's impossible!
That Himiko is the queen of Shiranui Clan! Be careful, Musashi!
That's a lie-dasu! That's nonsense-dasu!
But Jiraiyan wouldn't lie to me...
That person is Shiranui's queen?
Why are you dejected?
Your sudden loud voice has stopped my heartbeat-dasu!
You didn't respond when we called you!
Hey, tell me what you're thinking!
N- no, not really...
Musashi. What do you want to achieve?
That's, of course, to become the number one-
But you're young now. It's not a bad thing to love someone.
But.
You have a lover named Otsuru! Maybe some people have forgotten about her as it's been a while since she showed up.
Mr. Musashi! Hurry up and become the number one martial artist of Jipangu! Otsuru is asking you!
Right? You must not do anything that will make Ms. Otsuru sad. He who runs after two hares will catch neither, they say.
He's right, Musashi!
What are you two talking about-dasu? I- I don't get it at all-dasu!
Aren't you making friends with someone named Himiko? Spit it out!
No, no, you two are misunderstanding-dasu! Most of all, Ms. Himiko is as old as my mother-dasu!
They also say that with love, age difference isn't a problem.
Should I write a letter to Ms. Otsuru?
No, you can't!
Then spit it out! I'll give you a consultation!
How far did you go? Tell me!
That's...
Look! A good man!
Hey, where? Where, where, where?
Forget it-dasu!
Hey, stop!
Senhime!
What does a Toad Oil seller have to do with Sakurajima Gang that's told to make a crying baby stop?!
You bastard! What's so funny?!
If you're here to fight us, we won't let you go so easily!
I have something to ask you.
Yessir...
Where is the base of Shiranui Clan?
I don't know.
No idea.
Damn. They're also useless.
ribbit-ribbit! ribbit-ribbit! ribbit-ribbit!
If Musashi's believing in Himiko that much, there's no way he's going to change his mind just by talking to him.
Of course. I have to find out where Himiko is by myself.
I was rescued by Ms. Himiko around this place!
I must do anything to find out that person and ask her personally-dasu!
Did Mr. Musashi not tell you where's he going-gowasu?
Yes, I was so worried about him.
What were he thinking?! It's just like the saying no child knows how dear he is to his parents!
Did you see?
No.
The place is here-dasu. I fell from that place...
No doubt about it-dasu. I lost consciousness around here...
Mommy...
Mommy!
It was a dream...
Mr. Musashi? Did you wake up?
I was nursed at Ms. Himiko's house-dasu!
-Open.
-Ahh.
Ms. Himiko!
Excuse me-dasu. Where's the toilet-dasu?
Yes, I'll take you to there.
Being like this feels like I'm with my mother-dasu!
Am I really that like your mother, Mr. Musashi?
Well, I have never met my mother-dasu.
I'll show you the difference of the swords of Niten'ichiryū-dasu!
When I woke up, I was alone-dasu...
Ms. Himiko!
This...
Oh. I see.
Sakurajima
Good job.
Ms. Himiko!
Hey!
Nobody's there, and I don't think anybody can get in-dasu.
Who's there-dasu?!
You are Shiranui Clan-dasu! Come out! I want to make something clear-dasu!
Increasing your number so quickly is cheating-dasu!
How cowardly-dasu!
What's the name of your boss-dasu?!
Show him the result of our training!
Got it!
Wah! What the heck is this-dasu?!
Hmph! You can't get up to here-dasu! Now spit out the name of your boss-dasu!
Tree height reduction!
What's this-dasu? What's this-dasu?
Are you still shutting your mouths-dasu?!
It's my turn now-dasu!
Retreat!
Stop-dasu!
Damn! They sure run away quickly-dasu!
They're all mere show-dasu!
Was it just me-dasu?
It's probably me-dasu.
I'm back-dasu!
What is Shiranui Clan planning?
Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
I'm back now-dasu!
Today's weather was so good, and I couldn't help but to take a walk until now-dasu...
(bunmei kaika: lit. civilization; basically westernization; govt. system revamp in Meiji Period)
bunmei kaika
Osenchan, I'm back-dasu...
I'm sorry for that-dasu. I was strolling since the weather was so good today-dasu!
Huh? Where's everybody?
Jūbee came and they're discussing.
That's it-dasu...
Do you know you were bad today? You left us worried!
Of course-dasu!
Then I'll forgive you this time!
Tell me how was it!
A- about what-dasu?
Don't try to dodge! About the date with Ms. Himiko!
N- no, no, that's not it-dasu!
Oh, is that so? I wrote a letter to Otsuru.
Omitting the preface, Musashi is cheating on you.
Mr. Musashi! How can you do that while I was taking my off you!
I'm breaking up with you! Get your filthy face off me!
Now I'm going to mail this letter.
Hey, wait!
Then, I'll give you a consultation, since I have a lot of experiences with love!
Your loves are all unrequited-dasu.
Not there-dasu!
Musashi, are you back?
Kojirō! Help me!
Musashi, Senhime, Mr. Saigo is calling you people.
Kojirō, you're a coward!
I'm tired. No gain today after all this walking again...
Where is that Shiranui Clan hiding in?
Kerokichi, where did you go?
What?! Neighbor?!
Those people!
I hate that this mask makes my face hot!
Yeah, yeah!
I didn't know... I knew they were living somewhere around, but not the next to me!
So, are you saying that the base of Shiranui Clan is at Sakurajima-gowasu?
After analyzing and examining the data gathered by my men, there's no doubt about it this time.
You look pretty confident-dasu.
That's right. Everyone, have you heard of the old legend of Kyushu?
Yes, if you're saying about the ancient country named the Fire Country, ruled by a queen, on this land-gowasu.
Fire Country? Ancient country?
The country has prospered, and people forgot how to work and lived extravagantly-gowasu.
That's awesome-dasu.
But one day...
Their guardian deity has erupted, and ended up perishing that Fire Country-gowasu.
Then, all the people must've been...
No. It's an extremely small group of people, but some are told to be alive-gowasu.
Meaning that Shiranui Clan is descendant of those survived people.
You mean, those ninjas-dasu?
What they want is reviving that Fire Country.
I see. That's why they've teamed up with Hanzō, looking to rule over the country.
Ms. Himiko is the queen of Shiranui... no way...
Fire!
Hurry!
True-dasu!
Everyone, escape! Hurry!
There's nothing combustible over there. That's not right-gowasu.
What should we do, Kojirō?!
We have to put off the fire first!
This is bad-dasu!
Musashi! Move!
Kojirō.
I'm... sorry...
Chest!
Whose doing is this-gowasu?!
I knew it was Shiranui Clan-gowasu!
I'll face you-dasu!
I'll protect Senhime-gowasu!
Please do so!
Kojirō! Cool! Handsome! Good man!
Hmph.
Chest!
It seems that their comrade is setting fire from outside!
Unless we find them out and take down, there's no end to this!
Alright! I'll take care of them-dasu!
Attacking without showing yourself is cowardly-dasu!
Where are you looking at?
Appearing out of nowhere is cheating-dasu!
Gaenma of Shiranui Clan is here to get rid of you people!
Gaenma of Fuse
I don't care that you're Gaenma or gamma-dasu, but you'll take my Niten'ichiryū-dasu!
Prepare yourself!
Musashi!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
He disappeared-dasu!
Fire Camouflage, eh.
Here, here!
What are you saying, Gaenma?!
Gaenma, you just wait there-dasu!
Musashi!
-Musashi!
-It's dangerous-gowasu! Leave that guy to me-gowasu.
Chest!
Mr. Saigo!
How's that? You cannot escape from my magic!
He's dreadful. But I'm fine-gowasu.
How impudent! You're all going to hell!
My eyes!
Now!
Chest!
Damn!
Prepare yourself!
Cutting together is cruel!
That's it for today! Retreat!
They were hiding!
Mr. Jūbee!
No! It's collapsing!
Everyone, get away!
But Musashi's still there!
Anyway, just hurry!
Musashi! Where are you?! Musashi!
Musashi!
Leaving Senhime and others' worry behind, Musashi disguised himself as Shiranui Clan and smuggled to the fleeing remnants.
But! You're so unsightly!
Wait for the stormy next story!
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
I entered Sakurajima, disguising as Shiranui.
That Ms. Himiko really is the queen of Shiranui-dasu.
I was being fooled all time-dasu! I am an idiot!
But the one to rescue me fighting Hanzō was Ms. Himiko-dasu!
Next story! The Queen of the Fire Country, Himiko
It's the stormy Sakurajima-dasu!
Next Episode
The Queen of the Fire Country
Himiko
Look forwards for it!