It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Jipangu Martial Arts Competition proceeded to semi-finals, and the stadium was burning up with Musashi and Kojirō's match.
But the match was interrupted, because Megaton Castle invaded Edotopia.
To protect the Highness, Musashi and others get onto Fusion Castle and bump into Megaton Castle.
But they managed to defeat this, by the friendship power of Karakuri martial artists.
Senhime's Love
Wins
To know that they had Fusion Castle...
I am deeply sorry, Lord Rikudomaoh. We were almost there.
Still, I want that sacred sword no matter what. I want the life of the king. I will become the ruler of Jipangu State.
I want to change Jipangu as I want.
Yessir. Allow me one more chance!
Lord Rikudomaoh. Please allow me this time.
Will you do this, Hanzō?
Yessir. I have a secret measure.
L- Lord Rikudomaoh!
Dokuganryu, do not interrupt.
Hanzō. Try showing me your powers.
Y- Yessir!
Make the moat deeper, deeper, deeeeeeeeper! Make the rampart higher, higher, hiiiiiiiiiiigher!
Anyway, heighten the defenses!
I do not know what is that Rikudomaoh capable of...
2 spoons and 3 teaspoons of Sake.
The rest is love! ...this is embarassing!
It'll be delicious!
No, no! That wood goes there! Hurry up, everyone!
Thank you, Senhime!
Kojirō.
For making a meal for me.
This is my favorite, candied sweet potato!
No. This is not for you, Kojirō.
But then, who else? Could it be Musashi?
No way! This is a meal for the Highness!
Oh, I see.
Move, move!
-What was that!?
-We're now storing emergency foods.
Are we even strong chickens here?
Princess! Run!
We also bought pigs!
Osenchan!
Did you take that food for me-dasu?
Senhime!
Wah! Osenchan!
Are you okay-dasu? That was close-dasu!
Thank you, Musashi!
Hey, Musashi! You have a visitor!
F- for me-dasu? Who is it-dasu?
Mr. Musashi! What are you doing?
Oh, Otsuru!
I never knew you had that kind of relationship with her!
What kind of relationship?
You're snuggling someone in front of my eyes without a sign of embarrassment in the daytime!
W- wait!
It's a misunderstanding-dasu! I just caught Osenchan because she fell-dasu!
I came to give you dangos and...
I don't care anymore!
I'm giving this to Jiraiyan!
Thank you.
Ah, Otsuru! Otsuru! You misunderstood-dasu!
Hey, hey! Don't get out of your station on your own!
But...
Being a popular man is hard!
That's not it-dasu!
Jiraiyan! That's my dangos-dasu!
No way. I got it!
Give that back-dasu!
Stop it, you two!
Excuse me. Senhime coming in.
Come in.
Your Highness, please eat if you'd like.
Senhime, I'm happy to hear that. I was just becoming hungry.
Yeah! I'm happy to hear that you're happy! What were you doing?
I was reading haiku.
That's splendid, your Highness! Please tell me some!
Alright. It's just done.
Wind in summer is
truly warmer compared to
wind in winter.
How was that?
Er, it was magnificent! You managed to express something so obvious into a pretty haiku! Especially for that
middle verse "warmer compared to" was so original and it moved my heart instantly!
You know it!
Your Highness, the food is getting cold.
Yes, you're right.
Let me take some food to your dish.
Here!
How is it?
It's delicious.
Let me get some tea!
I'm hungry-dasu...
Musashi, we don't have spare time for lunch!
But I'm too hungry to use power-dasu!
Osenchan, make something for me, too-dasu!
Give it up. Don't you think that Senhime's sincere this time? Keep an eye on her.
But...
Akane! I'm back!
Good job. Now, let's have lunch!
Otsuru, what's wrong? You don't look so well.
Mr. Zenigatan.
Hm? What is it?
Do you also often have extra love affairs?
That's dirty! Are you okay?
Why, so suddenly!?
Oh, of course I don't do that!
I knew it! You only think about your jobl.
I think about you, too!
Really?
That's obvious!
I see that you had something with Mr. Musashi!
You know that Mr. Musashi is bad!
When I went to give him dangos, he was publicly snuggling Senhime
without a sign of embarrassment in front of my bare eyes!
But Mr. Musashi said that was a misunderstanding, but,
Those two are always together, playing with each other friendly, and I can't stand that!
I know Mr. Musashi isn't a person who's so irresponsible, but
Mr. Musashi is kind, stupid, and uncool, but I don't know what I should say - do I have to live with him? I can't hate him!
Moreover, he kept fighting enemies until now, and we might be married!
And... and...
You love Mr. Musashi, right?
Oh, no. I have to return now, or I'm going to be late for afternoon work.
M- me too!
Akane, see you later!
Boss, wait.
Thank you!
Otsuru, it'll be all right.
Yes!
Hey, today's setting sun is awesome! The east sky is so red!
What are you talking about, you idiot? Sun sets at west!
Huh? Now you've told me that...
Then what the heck is this!?
Big fire! Fire!
Fire!
Shotoku, are they making roasted sweet potatoes?
Let me see...
That's a grand fire. Many sweet potatoes will be roasted!
Your Highness, that is fire.
What? A fire?
Yessir.
What? Fire!?
O- oh, my mistake.
Excuse me.
That is bad! The village of Edotopia!
What? Is it a bad thing?
People's houses where they can live will disappear!
I see. They were living in there.
Look!
(Ace no Jō: Joe the Ace; Japanese actor Joe Shishido's nickname,
Ashita no Jō: Tomorrow's Joe; Boxing manga by Ikki Kajiwara,
Megaton jō: Megaton Castle)
A- Ace no Joe! No! Ashita no Joe! No! Right, it's Megaton Castle!
What!?
Megaton Castle is at the place of fire!?
Yes! Megaton Castle was in great flames! It was like a beast!
Let's hurry-dasu!
Right!
Musashi! Hurry up!
I'm doing so-dasu!
Right! We're moving out-dasu!
Do your best! You must not let Megaton Castle come near to the castle!
The village of Edotopia will be completely in fire at this rate!
Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
This way! Nobody rush! It'll be alright!
Where is Megaton Castle-dasu?
-Otsuru!
-Mr. Musashi!
Otsuru, are you alright-dasu?
Mr. Musashi, were you worried about me?
huh? huh?
That's because, Otsuru, you're most important to me-dasu!
Otsuru, I apologize about what happened earlier today-dasu.
No, I'm the one to apologize for questioning you.
Hey, you people! It's not the time to be flirting!
Oh, right-dasu. Otusuru, did you see Megaton Castle-dasu?
Megaton Castle?
It's a monster-like castle that is this big-dasu!
It was the for a very short moment, but it disappeared soon.
It disappeared-dasu?
What do you mean?
Those fools.
Musashi and all others went out from Edo Castle and it's now empty. Hmph! This plan worked!
Alright! We're invading into Edo Castle from air!
Named, like the saying nothing ventured, nothing gained, Lightening Surprise Attack Operation!
What is that-dasu? That's pretty-dasu!
Really.
They're like dandelions bloomed on the hill of Miyamoto village-dasu.
Dandelions?
Right-dasu. Blow the whitened dandelions at once and...
Mr. Musashi, you're so romantic!
Do you think so-dasu? How embarrassing-dasu!
You guys!
Mr. Musashi! It seems that Megaton Castle didn't head to west.
Mr. Jūbee, what's that-dasu?
Could that be...!
Hanzō!
What!? Hanzō!?
We've been fooled! It was a trap to lure us out!
We have to go back to Edo Castle right now!
But we can't let this fire-dasu!
Leave that to me!
Jiraiyan! Is it fine by yourself-dasu?
Just leave it to me.
Please make it-dasu!
Anyway, let's hurry!
Mr. Musashi, do your best! I'll be waiting!
Otsuru, be careful, too-dasu!
Who's there!?
Good! Let's proceed!
What?! Hanzō has invaded?!
Yes. The guard wasn't enough.
What's wrong? If there's a visitor, I won't mind.
No, no, your Highness! Hanzō is here for us!
I see. Ieyasu, what are we going to do now?
Err, that is, that is...
I, Senhime, will protect the Highness!
That was courageous!
E- er, thank you...
Nononononono, anyway, I'll do my best for the Highness!
Mr. Jiraiyan, a well is over there!
Got it!
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ swaka!
Become bigger!
Alright! Do it, Kerokichi!
You're awesome, Kerokichi!
Alright.
Good job, Kerokichi!
This way!
They're over there!
Hurry!
You bastards!
Hmph.
There's no higher place than this.
Then we'll go up the roof!
huh?!
Owie!
There is nowhere more for you to escape! Now, be silent and hand over the king and the sacred sword!
No! I can never hand them over!
Then it can't be helped. Do it!
Your Highness! Use this chance!
Get them!
No! You can't do that to such a splendid Highness!
Hmph! I'll simply cut both of you!
Senhime.
Your Highness!
Die!
Stop-dasu!
Musashi!
Sorry for being late-dasu!
Jūbee's here!
Senhime!
Jūbee! Kojirō!
Damn! Get them!
Well then, me too!
It hurts...
Lord, keep composed. The wound isn't deep.
Ouch!
Senhime, you can be relieved now.
Thank you, Kojirō.
Musashi! I'll make you pay the debt!
Hmph! Like hell I'd replay-dasu!
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
I did it-dasu.
I am invincible!
What did you say-dasu?!
Stop hesitating and come face me!
If you won't, then I'll make the first move!
What?!
We did it!
Hanzō, we'd like to present you a long trip to the wide sky.
Huh?
Remember this!
That's awesome!
Beautiful!
Yes.
You too, Senhime.
Senhime, your battle was beautiful.
No way. I was nothing more than an obstacle to everyone.
No, you saved me. Thank you.
Yes!
Otsuru!
Musashi!
Otsuru, you're safe-dasu!
Yes, but all the dangos are burnt.
That's why I can't give those to you for a while.
Something smells good-dasu.
There are a lot of roasted dangos-dasu!
This is delicious-dasu!
Really?!
Otsuru, you should try them too-dasu! There are a lot of them-dasu!
This is good!
Great! This will become a special product-dasu!
Would you like some roasted dangos?
Try some roasted dangos!
They're good!
Thanks to Senhime's activities, they managed to evade the crisis.
But Rikudomaoh's ambitions are burning up, deepening his rage.
What will he do with frightening Megaton Castle to creep over the king and others?
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
Since Megaton Castle is coming to attack, Edotopia isn't safe anymore!
That's why the Highness is going to Nikko-dasu.
But this time, Shingen came to attack-dasu!
Moreover, they, named Track Driving Corps, have a lot of tanks!
They're persistent-dasu!
Next story! Nikko Plan Shingen
(Kegon Falls: Tourist attraction in Nikko; one of the Three Japanese Falls)
It's the stormy Kegon Falls-dasu!
Next Episode
Nikko Plan
Shingen
Look forwards for it!