It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
According to the information by Ryoma, Musashi and others head to Seto Inland Sea to chase Megaton Castle.
But at the island they stopped by, Hanzō's trap was installed.
Senhime was captured. People went to rescue her.
But at last, thanks to Otsuru, they managed to escape their crisis.
Shingenshin
of Sky and Ground
You were beaten terribly, Dokuganryu.
Lord Rikudomaoh. I deeply apologize.
We still couldn't retrieve the sacred sword, the last of the king's Three Sacred Treasures.
Well, good enough. I might have been underestimating Ieyasu.
No way! Are you Mr. Nobunaga?
Nobunaga is already dead. Who's here is Rikudomaoh, the ultimate one far transcending Nobunaga.
Where are you going?
Hmph. You must be one of Ieyasu's underlings.
You won't make it so far now.
I'm bored-dasu...
Isn't it great? You're bored because it's peaceful now!
What are you saying-dasu, Otsuru? Rikudomaoh is still looking to rule over Jipangu State even meanwhile-dasu!
Mr. Musashi, you like fighting more than being with me!
N- no, I didn't mean that-dasu. Please don't cry-dasu, Otsuru.
I don't know anymore!
Oh, hey, look. Musashi made a girl cry.
That's no good. You won't make it.
Kojirō! Say something-dasu!
Unfortunately, I never made a girl cry before.
You should know that at least.
Really! You're all teasing me!
Maybe I should send her back at the first place, if I knew this was going to happen-dasu.
You're cruel, Mr. Musashi!
I get it! I'll go back! Are you happy?
I'm going back!
Otsuru, what are you trying to do-dasu!?
Let me go! I'll swim my way back to Edotopia!
That's impossible-dasu! You'll drown to death in your way-dasu!
Huh?
Wah! A drowned body-dasu!
He's still alive.
Hey, who did this to you? Hey!
R- report this to Jūbee as soon as possible. The identitiy of Rikudomaoh is Nobunaga.
What? Nobunaga?
Mr. Ryoma, who is Nobunaga-dasu?
I heard about him when I was young.
He was a military commander who fought for the unification of Jipangu State long time ago.
You mean, my grandpa?
His attack was bold and stirring, but he is told that he killed everyone
whoever he didn't like, including women, children, and old people.
(See: Honnō-ji incident)
But leaving the unification of Jipangu State right ahead of him,
he was betrayed by his subordinate Mitsuhide, and died at Temple Honno, according to what I heard.
Then, is that Nobunaga guy dead-dasu?
No, it's possible that he hid himself first and raised war capacity until now.
If Mr. Jūbee's man found out an information so important like that at this place...
then Nobunaga's base must be around here.
Alright! This is a good time to replenish food supply.
Let's investigate during that.
Head to the nearest port.
Per the information we just received, it seems that noisy flies anchored to the nearest port, finding this castle as well.
Listen, you two! Work together and do not let them approach this castle even for one step!
I have one objection, Lord Nobunaga. I do not have to work with this guy.
Please watch I, Shingen, repealing a brat or two easily.
Hmph, that's my line, you red Karakuri tumbler!
What!? You're nothing more than shining!
Stop it, you two!
Are you suggesting that you do not understand my order?
T- that's impossible.
You must not look down of that Musashi brats. Do not forget.
Yessir!
There are so many girls wearing high-leg leotard-dasu!
So much on right!
So much on left!
This is not a time for such a thoughtless speech!
We're here to find the hideout of Nobunaga!
Mr. Musashi, when did you became so lewd?
You don't have to be angry all at once-dasu! Really!
Musashi, we're here to find the hideout of our enemy. Be serious!
Osenchan, you call that serious-dasu?
Isn't it obvious? I disguised to fool the enemies!
Then I'll go investigate the seaside!
Should we disguise, too-dasu?
That might be a good idea!
100 kan
(375kg; 830lb)
(触らぬ神に祟りなし: lit. Don't touch the gods, and you won't be harmed;
if it ain't broke, don't fix it; the line used 女(woman) instead of 神(god))
Let sleeping womens lie!
Agreed.
Ms. Otsuru is so bad-tempered, unlike how she looks...
Jiraiyan! Did you figured something out on your side?
No, not at all!
Then, what about you-dasu, Kojirō?
If I did, then would I be here, eating some snow cone?
Makes sense-dasu!
One more dish!
Anyway, I wonder where would the hideout of Nobunaga at!
It's possible that spy is swept away by ocean current from west.
You guys, if you eat that so fast, then your heads will go dull!
But Kojirō, yours has melt because you ate too slowly-dasu.
What!?
My snow cone!
-I'm having 5th dish-dasu!
-I'm 3rd!
-I'm having 3rd dish!
Hey, Musashi! We're invited to watermelon diving! Follow me!
Alright, we'll go-dasu!
-Me too!
Why are you here?
Boss! One more dish of snow cone of large serving.
Hey, Musashi, a little bit to the left!
No, it's right! Right!
Where is it-dasu!?
-It's left! Left!
-It's right, Mr. Musashi!
Alright! Right then-dasu!
No, that's not right!
Great! Go that way!
Really!
Mr. Musashi, it's right!
Right, I believe in Otsuru-dasu!
You should've done that at the first place!
Sorry, sorry!
Yeah, a little bit to the left!
Right, right!
Great!
Hey, do it with full force!
I'm doing this-dasu!
Hit with all your might, Musashi!
Watermelon, prepare yourself-dasu!
I did it!
Why would a watermelon explode-dasu?
Musashi!
Huh? Who're you?
I was waiting for you, Musashi.
What!?
It seems that you're looking for our hideout. You all can come with us.
Huh? Really-dasu?
Yeah, but...
your head only.
It's dangerous here! Please take shelter!
What!? What's going on here!?
All the people on this beach are my subordinates.
You'd better give up now!
This is bad-dasu.
Will they manage to escape from the fearful trap on the beach of everlasting summer? Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
The exploits are mine by this! Let me break your neck!
Stop!
Kenshin! I cannot let you take all the exploits!
What's going on-dasu?
This is our chance!
My exploits!
Everyone! The exploits are ours! Chase them, chase!
Are you going to steal all the exploits!?
Don't ask what you know!
Don't let them get away! We'll get Musashi with our own hands!
Yessir!
I can't walk anymore.
We should be fine, since we came pretty far-dasu.
But still, the fact that everyone at the beach was enemy was surprising!
To have subordinates who are capable of installing a fearful trap like that...
that Nobunaga is pretty capable.
I finally found the heads of achievement!
Alright! Me too!
Huh?
Oh, right. Mine didn't change.
W- who's there!?
They are my achievements! Get your hands off them!
K- Kenshin! Do not interrupt my happiness!
You don't interrupt my success!
What are you saying? You don't steal what's mine!
I was dealing with them at the first place! Prepare yourself!
Damn! What are you doing!?
You won't get in my way!
Thank you, Kojirō!
Musashi. Take Senhime to somewhere safe!
That's easy-dasu!
Now, Osenchan!
Mr. Musashi, let me go, too!
Otsuru, you can follow us!
But that means Musashi is left with Senhime by two!
There's nothing to worry! He doesn't look so, but he actually is dependable in the time of need.
You're wrong!
What?
Anyway, this place is...
Hey! Your bosses are in danger!
-Lord Kenshin!
-Lord Shingen!
Now's our chance!
That was close.
Right. I wonder if Otsuru's fine-dasu...
Musashi, you truly like Otsuru, don't you?
Well, that's... we made an oath to marry-dasu...
Now that I'm relieved, it became chilly!
Musashi! Do something!
That's not good-dasu. Something to wear...
There's no way one would be here...
I envy Otsuru.
Right!
What are you doing, Musashi?
Do this, do that, and...
Musashi?
Do this!
Look!
It's unsightly, but it'll help you deal with the coldness-dasu.
Musashi, you're really gentle.
Huh?
I think I understand why would Otsuru like you.
No, Osenchan, you're ridiculing me with that-dasu!
Mr. Musashi!
Otsuru!
Musashi! You're safe!
Kojirō! Jiraiyan! What a relief-dasu! Otsuru's safe, too-
Otsuru!
W- why are you angry-dasu?
Hmph!
Let's hurry our way back to the port. Mr. Ryoma is waiting for us.
Right!
They're so persistent!
Kojirō!
Our achievements are in our front!
Don't let Kenshin take our achievements!
Shingen, you bastard! Are you out of mind, to shoot at ally!?
Hmph! The one to obtain the achievement wins! Everyone, go!
They started to fight themselves again-dasu.
How stupid of them. This is our chance!
You won't get away from this!
We are not the tools for success of you old men-dasu!
The achievement is mine!
Do not interrupt! This is mine!
Secret Sword Tsubamegaeshi!
Your interrupt made me miss the chance!
What!? Don't blame me!
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
Look for yourself! Your continuous interruption is allowing them chances!
Damn, this won't get us anymore!
We should combine our powers for now!
Sure!
Sky Ground Fusion!
W- what-dasu!?
Woah! What is that monster-dasu?
We are not a monster! This is our ultimate form, Shingenshin!
Shingenshin? It's Shingenshin when I read from beginning, and it's Shingenshin again when I read from back.
Is it time to think about such an useless thing!?
You're right-dasu.
Taste the wrath of my dual blades-dasu!
If you call that dual blades, then we're quadruple blades!
What!? Using four is cowardly-dasu!
Aren't you using multiple swords already?
Damn!
My legs!
Musashi!
Kojirō! Are you okay-dasu?
Yeah, somehow... ouch!
If we combined at the first place, we wouldn't even have to steal achievements.
I'll take your necks, Musashi and Kojirō!
Kojirō, leave me here, and run away immediately-dasu!
You idiot! Do you think I can do that?
Only if I had powers to raise my sword...
Kojirō, put your sword on these-dasu! I'll hold up the sword-dasu!
Musashi! Got it!
Know when to give up!
Prepare yourself!
Special Technique Phoenix Sword!
Kojirō!
Ride on!
Damn it! Remember this!
That was terrible-dasu.
Yes. We can find the enemy's hideout later; your bodies come first.
What a relief. I was worried what if Mr. Musashi dies...
Otsuru, sorry for making you worry-dasu! But I'm invincible-dasu!
Mr. Musashi!
My leg! My leg! Don't step on my leg! My leg!
Musashi and Kojirō's friendship power has managed to repeal the attack of Shingenshin.
But now they know the fearsome attacking potential of the enemy, an anxiety remains in their hearts.
The wide ocean of battle is about to become violent.
I fought and I got beaten
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
I can't lose, so take my blow!
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
Next is delightful lunchtime
But it's not delightful today
The thunder of my teacher
only hit me and nobody else
I tried to explain
But he won't listen
Now whatever I do
I end up crying
Don't cry when you eat, or
it tastes totally bad
you'll feel downhearted
Hearing that there are armors hidden by aliens, we're heading to the place right away-dasu.
That's because it's impossible for us to defeat that Hanzō at this rate-dasu.
But it's difficult to claim them-dasu. We almost drown in waters, and we fell from stairs.
Thousands of ris of the road of pain! Well, not that much, but still-dasu!
Next Story! Charming Outlook Karakuri Shift
It's stormy aliens-dasu!
Next Episode
Charming Outlook
Karakuri Shift
Look forwards for it!