It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
After making a perverted inventor Gennai make a submarine, Musashi and others search the sea, and found Megaton Castle.
With a determination, Musashi and others got in to rage.
They damaged Megaton Castle, but also destroyed was their submarine.
Big Laughter
Octopus Dance Operation
After repairing the submarine, Musashi and others were looking for Nobunaga's base.
I don't feel so good. I'm seasick.
Mr. Gennai, they say seasickness will be gone if you lick your own nose-dasu!
Yeah, right!
No, Musashi! How dare you get me ride onto this thing!? I don't know what will happen if we don't go up now!
You made this-dasu! You should be more confident with what you made-dasu!
I can't trust this thing because I made this!
Huh? Jiraiyan!
Heya! There's nothing over here!
There should be their base somewhere in this wide sea...
Hey! I'll go find over there!
Just hurry up. Hurry up to the grounds.
Mr. Gennai, is there somewhere else than this place where the enemy's base is likely to be at?
There's no way for me to know that. Just go back to the grounds!
Mr. Kojirō. We've been underwater more than 3 hours. Maybe it's best for us to take a rest around here.
Agreed.
You're right. Even if we hurry, the sea is too wide.
Just a moment-dasu!
What's wrong, Mr. Musashi?
What's that-dasu?
-Mr. Kojirō.
-Roger.
L- look!
This must be Nobunaga's hideout.
We finally found it-dasu!
But still, how did they built a base this big here?
That Nobunaga guy must be having a power that we do not know about.
Their base is big, but so what-dasu? It's a base of a coward-dasu. The victory depends on big guts-dasu!
-Oh?
-Good job, Mr. Musashi. Well said.
Torpedo-dasu!
There are holes in the ship-dasu!
Incoming again!
Let's retreat for now.
Jiraiyan! I'm the man!
Kerokichi's the toad oil~
Hey! Did you find something over there?
Look at front?
Impact confirmed. At least 2 were hit.
They found out Babel 13 at last, but it's not going to help them.
Hanzō. Do not treat this incident lightly.
Lord Nobunaga.
It's about them. Since they found out this place, they will try to invade.
That goes for you too. Make the guards more strict and never let anyone go back alive.
Yessir!
Damn... We finally found the enemy's base, and...
If I ever go there again, I will finish them-dasu!
But you can't use the submarine anymore.
Does that mean we can't go there anymore-dasu?
Can't you just try repairing it once again-dasu?
Look at this. It's unusable.
Even if we can go again, it's difficult to go through that security.
Then, will we be unable to do anything at all anymore?
We have to think of something else.
Mr. Kojirō, do you have any idea?
Yes. For them to live in that deep sea, they have to take air from somewhere.
I see! That's it! You're saying that there's a ventilation on some island around here!
What's that-dasu?
Anyway, if we can discover where their ventilation is, we should be able to get into their base.
-Hey, hey!
-Huh?
Otsuru, you should tan your back, instead of doing nothing over there!
Maybe I really should have followed them...
Leave them be. They won't find anything, else than being bit by mosquitoes.
But Mr. Musashi can't do collective actions...
This island is hot-dasu... It's like we're on a southern island-dasu. Don't you agree, Kojirō?
What is it, Musashi? Are you tired already?
No, that's not it-dasu. I'm so thirsty that I might become stale-dasu.
Yay! Bananas-dasu!
I'm happy that there are a lot of them-dasu!
Mr. Musashi is really skillful. That tree-climbing skill will even scare a monkey away.
This is delicious-dasu! I always wanted to eat at least one banana that'll make my stomach full-dasu!
Hey, Musashi! It's not a time to be eating some grasses!
It's banana, not grass-dasu!
Let's go first.
What's wrong? Did a banana stuck in your neck?
A large earthen pipe is over there-dasu!
What!?
That-dasu!
Mr. Kojirō.
Let's go.
How refreshing-dasu!
Musashi, let's have a race!
Hey, you guys! We don't know where are the enemis hiding at!
That's why we're trying to go over the river-dasu! Right, Jiraiyan?
Right, right! We'll see who'll reach the rock on the other side first. Let's go!
Are they even swimming or what?
I heard that Mr. Musashi learned swimming from you, Mr. Kojirō.
What a giant earthen pipe-dasu!
This must be the ventilation of the enemy's hideout.
Then, let's get in right away!
Wait!
Wait! This is a wait call!
I, Kenshin, will not let you go to Babel 13 from here!
No way! I, Shingen, will send you guys to hell instead!
They're guarding a place like this too...
We already know all your shallow plots. Everyone, get them!
You're being pain in a butt-dasu! I'm going to get rid of all of you-dasu!
How impudent of you!
Shingen! Let's combine our powers right away!
Agreed! Lord Nobunaga will kill us if we let them go through!
Sky Ground Fusion!
T- this is bad-dasu!
Come attack whenever you're ready!
They aren't there...
Fighting them is tiresome-dasu. We'll skip this for now-dasu.
You're right.
Will Musashi and others make their way in? Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
We sweated a lot-dasu.
Running away right after finding the ventilation is really slovenly.
Then, Osenchan, will you get rid of Shingenshin-dasu?
No.
Now, now, it's not a time to be fighting.
We need a new strategy again...
Look, Mr. Musashi!
What's up-dasu, Otsuru?
How cute!
True-dasu!
How cool-dasu!
Everyone are troubled and they're...
It jumped again! Dolphins are awesome!
I want to become a dolphin so that I can swim freely in the sea-dasu.
That's it!
We'll become dolphins, too.
Are you serious that this will work-dasu?
Then, do you have any better idea? Spit it out!
I- I don't-dasu...
Then, don't complain!
Dolphin tolls fins...
Perfect. This will be enough to fool them.
Perfect? A clumsy stuffed toy like this will be revealed soon-dasu!
Sorry for being clumsy, duh! We really did our best to make this!
Take a look at these pitiful fingers!
It's because you did something you can't-dasu.
Shut up! After all my hard work, you still don't want to wear it!?
Yeah, Mr. Musashi, wear it! It's not like I'm good at needlework,
but that Senhime, who can't do laundries, cleaning, cooking, and all other housekeeping at all, really did her best to make!
Hey, you don't have to tell that...
I get it, I'll wear-dasu! I'll wear-dasu!
How cute!
Do you think so-dasu! I knew it!
Let's go, since we're ready!
Here I go!
Heave, ho!
Mr. Musashi!
Listen to Mr. Kojirō well, and try not to bother anybody.
Got it-dasu.
And, since you don't know what kind of danger will be there, be always with Mr. Jūbee.
Oh, and, be careful of sharks. Sharks like octopuses.
I'll be careful of both sharks and whales-dasu. See you later-dasu!
I'm worried about Mr. Musashi so much. Come back soon!
Now, Musashi, do it.
Do I really have to do this-dasu? I'm embarrassed-dasu.
Dance more tastily!
octopus, octopus, I'm a totally tasty octopus-dasu.
octopus, octopus, I'm the best for Edo-Style Sushi-dasu.
Huh? Hey, look! There's a tasty-looking octopus!
Where?
Hey, it's round and fat, good enough to eat.
Hey, what are you up to?
I'm just going to catch that.
octopus, octopus~
It sure looks tasty!
This guy looks great!
Let's eat this as a side dish.
What's this? This isn't right.
I- isn't this cloth!?
What!?
I'm an octopus!
A fake!
Octopus dance plan was successful-dasu!
He did it!
Are you alright-dasu?
Mr. Musashi, your octopus dance was splendid.
Do you think so-dasu? I wanted to show this to Otsuru-dasu!
Now, let's find where Nobunaga is, before they find us out.
I was waiting for you.
You're Dokuganryu! Since you found out, it can't be helped-dasu! Prepare yourself-dasu!
Woah, slow down. I'm not intending to fight you.
This way, please. Lord Nobunaga the Rikudomaoh is waiting.
What? Nobunaga?
This isn't good. This has to be a trap.
What are we going to do, Mr. Kojirō?
I guess we'll have to go.
I'll praise you, for managing to get into this Babel 13.
We don't need appraisal-dasu! What are you going to do-dasu!?
Hmph. I like your stubbornness. Wouldn't you like to become my subordinates?
What?
Hmph! Don't fool around too much-dasu!
I am a Karakuri martial artist of justice-dasu! I won't become villains' friend-dasu!
You have might, Musashi. Then let me ask you: what is justice?
Protecting the peaceful world-dasu!
Peaceful? Are you saying that the world of now is peaceful?
Under Ieyasu, it looks like it's peaceful at first sight,
but aren't powerful families in various areas are fighting to expand their territories?
Only a small number of people live peacefully, while others can't even have dinner tonight.
Now you've said that, that's true-dasu...
I look to lead this whole world into destruction, and create a world without any wars.
For that, I need the power of young people, like you..
What do you think? Wouldn't you want to lend me your powers to me?
Yes! I will help Mr. Nobunaga-dasu!
You idiot! Don't believe what Nobunaga is saying!
Why-dasu? Isn't what Mr. Nobunaga saying correct-dasu?
If you think he's right, then why would he be trying to steal the Three Sacred Treasures?
That makes sense, too-dasu...
You are right in that the battles are going on even now, but Lord Ieyasu is trying to decrease the number of them.
Your way of thinking, to annihilate people who're living peacefully, is wrong!
I agree to Mr. Jūbee!
Hmph. You guys cannot understand my greatness at the first place.
Hanzō! Annihilate them.
Yessir!
Stop-dasu!
Nope!
Hanzō! Get out of my way-dasu!
Hmph. Refusing Lord Nobunaga's invitation? How foolish.
You should have done that at the first place. You're just putting on airs!
Get them!
You think those small fries can be my enemies?
How impudent! Sousou Armor!
Me too-dasu!
Karakuri Shift! Gentoku Armor!
Hanzō! Prepare yourself!
Karakuri Shift! Kanu Armor!
Hanzō! You're not getting away this time-dasu!
You fool. Where do you think you are?
What's this?
You fell into my trap!
What are you going to do-dasu, Hanzō!?
Are you going to take us prisoners!?
Hmph. I wasn't even thinking of letting you alive.
Inundation!
I'm guessing your specialty is swimming, since you swam your way to here. Swim all as you wanted, before you die.
Damn! We're not going to end up drowning-dasu!
My armor!
Right before confronting Nobunaga the Rikudomaoh,
will you end up becoming a drowned body in some fishbowl, Musashi!? Wait for the stormy counterattack!
I fought and I got beaten
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
I can't lose, so take my blow!
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
Next is delightful lunchtime
But it's not delightful today
The thunder of my teacher
only hit me and nobody else
I tried to explain
But he won't listen
Now whatever I do
I end up crying
Don't cry when you eat, or
it tastes totally bad
you'll feel downhearted
We got caught. Meanwhile, that Nobunaga bastard ordered Dokuganryu to capture Senhime, no matter her life-dasu.
This is bad-dasu! Otsuru might be killed, too-dasu!
But at there, everyone came to help-dasu!
Ushiwaka, Benkei, and Boss Zenigatan-dasu.
Next story! Destroy Babel 13
It's the stormy Double Dragon Sword-dasu!
Next Episode
Destroy
Babel 13
Look forwards for it!