It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Musashi and others managed to sneak into Babel 13, but they were captured with Hanzō's trap.
Nobunaga orders Dokuganryu to capture Senhime, allowing to kill her.
Senhime's in crisis. But thanks to Ushiwaka, Benkei, and Zenigatan, they escape from crisis.
Edotopia
in Big Crisis
Mr. Nobunaga.
Well, now we've left Babel 13, we have only one choice.
We will get Ieyasu and the king with all our forces.
Yes.
Jipangu State should have been in my hands by now, but since this happened, we will have to do this.
We will destroy Edotopia, the capital of Jipangu State!
Yessir!
Head to Edotopia!
Err, everyone, Nobunaga is riding on Megaton Castle and heading to Edotopia right away.
To Edotopia!?
Wait-dasu. I'm here, Kojirō's here, ...
Everyone's here, and that means...
Edotopia is empty.
This is bad!
We'll chase immediately-dasu!
What was that for-dasu!?
You moron! The opponent is flying! There's no way possible that we can chase them by running!
That's true-dasu, but we have to go-dasu!
What an eerie geezer-dasu.
I thought this was going to happen, so I have something prepared.
Something?
What is that? Show us!
Wanna see?
I want to, I want to, I want to!
Then will you show me, too?
That must've been hurt.
This is the great invention of justice: Electric Turbo Screw!
With this, you can run on water surface without any problem.
But, look at that...
But, what vehicle can we put that on?
Look!
Mr. Gennai, you're awesome-dasu!
I did my best to come out with something that will let you move without using the power of waves, when there isn't any.
Yes, that kind of job is only possible for the best inventor of Jipangu State.
Is the high-leg girl next to you one, too?
Hey, Mr. Gennai, do you mind?
Yes, yes...
Anyway, Jiraiyan looks happy.
Go, go!
He's so pecaeful-dasu.
Anyway, we do not know what will that Nobunaga do, as he's now cornered.
He'll try to finish this immediately.
I'm worried about Edotopia-dasu.
Burn, burn, and burn up! Make Edotopia into a burnt field!
Mr. Nobunaga. But that will make Edotopia into a ruins.
That will leave you nothing.
It seems that you don't know yet, Hanzō.
Yes?
When I take the world in my hands, I will rebuild everything that Ieyasu made, in a way I like.
Everything will be as I desire.
I will rebuild this Edotopia into the grand Azuchi Palace.
I will get rid of all worthless humans, destroy everything, and build a paradise for me.
For that too, I will destroy everything that's old! Destroy, destroy, and destroy more!
That's how the new system borns!
My... my Edotopia!
Jūbee! Where's Jūbee?
Yessir, he couldn't be reached yet.
That Nobunaga bastard!
We're late-dasu...
Help me!
Unforgivable!
Nobunaga, you bastard!
Mr. Jiraiyan, please put off fire with Kerokichi.
Mr. Zenigatan, Mr. Ushiwaka, and Mr. Benkei, please join.
Yes!
Senhime and Ms. Otsuru will take care of the children!
Got it!
-Then...
-we will...
-stop Megaton Castle.
That must be Fusion Castle!
Lord! There's Mr. Jūbee and others!
Oh, is that so!?
Hey, Megaton Castle! What are you doing-dasu!?
How persistent of them! Get rid of Musashi bastards first!
Even for Musashi and others, are they too tough for them?
It's the biggest crisis ever of Jipangu State.
This place is Nikko. The king is living a life in seclusion, to be out of reach of Nobunaga.
This is just right.
This is an astringent persimmon...
Your Highness!
Oh, Shotoku. Where have you been?
Because you weren't here, I ended up eating an astringent persimmon.
This is not a time to be eating some persimmons!
What's wrong?
Per intelligence, Edotopia is being attacked by Nobunaga by fire.
W- what? Nobunaga?
What should we do?
I see. I get it.
Your Highness, what are you going to do?
Isn't Nobunaga coming? Of course we have to run away.
Your Highness! You cannot be feeble at a time like this!
But, you know... I hate Nobunaga.
According to what I've heard, Edotopia is being attacked by Megaton Castle.
You mean that flying Megaton Castle?
(Chokuden: lit. Super Sky(Flying) Palace)
This is the time to use Chokuden.
Chokuden?
Yes.
This Chokuden is ready to fly to anywhere in times of need.
Again, wouldn't it be better for us to run away on this?
If Nobunaga takes control of Jipangu State, he will chase you to anywhere.
We will have to join Mr. Ieyasu and take down Nobunaga.
But...
No buts. There are no shortcuts.
Please think again.
I will not do that.
We have to fight with all our guts.
The whole Jipangu State is at stake.
I hate high places!
Please bear with it. This is an urgent matter. Most of all, Senhime is involved in this.
What? Senhime?
Will Edotopia end up being completely burnt like this? What will Chokuden do, with the Highness on board?
Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
This way! Nobody panic! It'll be alright!
This is no different from pouring water on some desert.
Wah! Help us-dasu!
What's wrong, Musashi?
Musashi!
Osenchan! It's dangerous here-dasu! Run away fast-dasu!
Do not forgive them; finish them!
End of the road-dasu!
Is this our end?
W- what's that!?
Our chance! Now!
Right!
I'm not sure, but that seems to be a friendly force-dasu!
Let's go.
Mr. Musashi! It's good to have you safe.
Mr. Shotoku! Were you the owner of this-dasu?
This is an invincible ship named Chokuden.
Chokuden.
Indeed!
Senhime, good afternoon.
Y- your Highness!
Did you attack Nobunaga's Megaton Castle by yourself, using this thing?
Yes, you're right.
Awesome!
S- Senhime...
That will just do-dasu. I'll invade into Megaton Castle using that-dasu!
Musashi! If you're going, then me too!
I'll join!
Wait! The Highness owns this!
No, no, if you like it, then please get in. Can they, Shotoku?
Er, yes, if your Highness thinks so.
What a big-hearted man!
No, no, if you'd like, I'll present this to all of you.
Your Highness!
-How generous!
-Don't worry, don't worry!
Then, let's hurry!
Be careful.
That mindset is also awesome!
Come here, Kojirō!
Y- yeah...
Alright! Those Nobunaga bastards won't be doing whatever they want anymore-dasu!
Let's go!
Be careful!
It's up to you, Musashi!
Nobunaga, you bastard! Come out! I, Kojirō, will face you!
Kojirō seems to be in a pretty bad temper-dasu.
Don't worry about that.
You're finally here, Nobunaga! Don't be dazed and do a surprise attack!
G- got it-dasu!
Alright, take them down with a single blow!
Kojirō! Evade well-dasu!
You fool! You fight back first!
Chase them, get them! Corner them! Torture them to death!
Mr. Kojirō, it's only a matter of time before they get us. Go to there first.
Roger.
Yay! Cotton candies! Cotton candies-dasu!
You're wrong!
Damn. Where did they disappear to?
Lord Nobunaga. It is dangerous to chase them too far.
What?
If I was Musashi, then I'd...
Now, Kojirō! Decelerate-dasu!
What are you saying!? We have to get out of here!
No, we'll enter at once!
What!?
It's time for a decisive match-dasu. We'll go round and cut into the back of Megaton Castle at once-dasu!
Musashi!
Mr. Musashi!
Dokuganryu, I will agree to your opinion.
Take down Musashi no matter what!
Yessir!
Alright! Slowing down!
Now's our chance!
Musashi! You're wrong!
Even then, we can't go back-dasu!
Y- you fool!
Musashi! You're a dango brat dashing to your doom!
Nobody's on board!
Find them! Find them exhaustively!
Alright! I set Chokuden to go back by itself.
We have only one enemy: Nobunaga!
We will protect Edotopia.
Mr. Musashi. Mr. Kojirō. Please be careful.
Got it.
He's there! Kojirō's there!
Get out of my way!
Nobunaga! Come out!
Come out, Nobunaga!
Who's that!?
You must be Dokuganryu!
Musashi. It seems that the time to settle this has came. I was waiting for you.
Where's Nobunaga-dasu!?
I do not intend to tell you!
Damn! If then!
Karakuri Shift!
Gentoku Armor!
Show yourself, Double-Headed Dragon!
Musashi! Prepare yourself!
You bastard!
How dare you! Unforgivable!
You're out of your mind, Dokuganryu!
Niten'ichiryū!
Double Dragon Sword!
H- how regretful.
Nobunaga!
What? Musashi bastards!?
Hanzō! Gather subordinates and stop them!
Yessir!
I can't stand just watching Edotopia being burnt up!
Mr. Gennai! Is there anything we can do?
Maybe something might be possible.
Really!?
Will Musashi and others managed to rescue Edotopia, which is being completely burnt?
And how will the last battle between Musashi and Nobunaga end?
The story is approaching the finale.
Wait for the turbulent next story!
I fought and I got beaten
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
I can't lose, so take my blow!
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
Next is delightful lunchtime
But it's not delightful today
The thunder of my teacher
only hit me and nobody else
I tried to explain
But he won't listen
Now whatever I do
I end up crying
Don't cry when you eat, or
it tastes totally bad
you'll feel downhearted
To save Edotopia, the Highness decided to hand over
one of the Three Sacred Treasures, to Nobunaga-dasu.
Will Jipangu end up falling over to the hands of bad guy-dasu?
But, looking for the ruling power, Hanzō kills Nobunaga-dasu!
The one who's truly bad really is Hanzō-dasu!
Next story! Flowering Musashi Cuts the Evil
It's the stormy Edotopia-dasu!
Next Episode
Flowering Musashi
Cuts the Evil
Look forwards for it!