It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Nobunaga's Megaton Castle made Edotopia into a fire of sea.
Musashi and others stopped them somehow, but they were forced into a hard fight.
But, what appeared there was the king's Chokuden.
Musashi and others got into Megaton Castle, and took down Dokuganryu.
Flowering Musashi
Cuts the Evil
Damn, what will happen to Edotopia now?!
Senhime!
Grandpa!
What are you doing here? We have to escape!
Nope.
That great inventor named Mr. Gennai is going to put off the fire on whole Edotopia at once!
At once?
Yeah!
Hey, give me back the hammer!
It's for finishing!
Yeah!
Right!
Your Highness.
Ieyasu, this leaves me no choice.
I made a decision.
Your Highness.
The Highness is going to hand over the remaining one of the Three Sacred Treasure, the sacred sword, to Nobunaga.
The sacred sword? Why?
Saving everyone of Edotopia worths more than the sacred sword.
That means you're handing over the seat of the king to Nobunaga.
That's not necessarily a bad idea.
Nobunaga is also somebody's child. He won't massacre everyone in Jipangu.
He'll make a new country for everyone.
What will happen to you, your Highness?
I'll spend the rest of my life at Nikko, writing Haikus.
Your Highness, what a pity...
Yes, I just made one.
Do forgive me
even if Nobunaga
gets the sacred sword.
Well then.
Hmph. While we're taking down those impudent Musashi and others, Edotopia is burning up pretty.
This is great.
I will cut off Musashi with one slash by myself.
Hanzō! Guide me.
Yessir, Mr. Nobunaga!
They're here again! Destroy it!
Mr. Nobunaga. They're with a white flag.
That is one of the Three Sacred Treasures, the sacred sword.
They finally surrendered.
Get closer.
Mr. Nobunaga. What should we do with Musashi and others?
Lock them in, so that they won't get away!
Yessir!
Hey! Nobunaga! Where are you-dasu?! Come out immediately-dasu! Hey!
Run!
No! We're trapped!
Damn! I'll destroy these walls-dasu!
Are you alright?
It didn't work-dasu.
I now got the sacred sword!
Please stop attacking Edotopia now.
I believe that you won't do further attack. In other words, bring peace to this world. Moderately and harmoniously.
I know. Attacking was not my original intention.
Please.
The jewel, the shield, and the sacred sword. The certificate of the king, the Three Sacred Treasure, are now here.
With these, Jipangu State is mine!
Hanzō! You should be happy, too!
Congratulations with all my respect.
Jipangu State is mine!
H- Hanzō...
Nobunaga! I shall claim the Three Sacred Treasures!
Did you betray me, Hanzō? I'm the one who saved your life!
Hmph.
How dare you betray me, who gave you Sousou Armor?
Die, Nobunaga!
I'll take you to the hell with me!
I was so close...
The Three Sacred Treasures and Megaton Castle. Jipangu State is now mine!
It's now done.
Mr. Gennai, hurry, hurry!
If it can put off all the fire on Edotopia, then would it produce a large amount of water?
What's going on inside that?
It's calling for a storm.
S- storm?
By doing that, a fire like this will be put off at once.
But...
I don't think you can call a storm that easily...
Nothing is impossible to me!
Give us rain.
It's Karakuri Rain Prayer!
Not yet?
It's not getting destroyed at all-dasu.
Now, it's time to finish Musashi bastards, since Nobunaga is done.
My crotch is being ripped-dasu!
-What's going on?!
-He's trying to drop us!
I can't fly-dasu!
Me too!
Are you all right-dasu?
I'm good. Let's find Nobunaga.
Since he has really done this to us, we cannot forgive him!
You're right-dasu!
N- Nobunaga is down-dasu.
What?!
Who did this?
It must be Hanzō.
Hanzō betrayed Lord Ieyasu first, betrayed the queen Himiko of Shiranui Clan, and now he betrayed Nobunaga again.
How cruel of him-dasu!
D- do me a favor.
You're still alive-dasu?
Destroy this Megaton Castle.
Megaton Castle?
It's better to be destroyed than being used by Hanzō.
But, it's a big job-dasu! Even with a huge hammer, it'll take a month or two-dasu!
T- the secret of Megaton Castle is...
Got it-dasu.
The last of evil is pitiful.
That's right.
We'll destroy this Megaton Castle and break Hanzō's ambitions-dasu!
Right!
Give us rain.
Grandpa, I was a fool, to actually believe in this Mr. Gennai.
Osenchan, you're an idiot!
Thanks to that, you wasted your time, grandpa.
Huh? There's a wind.
(bikkuri shitana, mou: I'm suprrised; Japanese comedian Minami Shinsuke's gag punchline)
Huh, really? Even for me, I'm surprised!
The storm called by Gennai came! Literally, wait for the stormy meal!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
Hurry up and escape, but do not rush!
Hey, I made that for a joke, but since it really worked, I must be a genius!
This truly is a blessed rain!
Kerokichi! Our job is done!
Great. Edotopia is now saved by this!
I got a new poem!
On a day it rains
without a good umbrella
I get dripping wet
Mr. Gennai, isn't this too much? We already had enough rain.
Then, let me try stopping the machine.
It doesn't work, after all!
Let's go somewhere dry!
The weather is stormy, Lord Hanzō.
I see. Go above the clouds, so that we don't get mixed up!
Roger! Power room, increase power!
So, this must be the power room of Megaton Castle.
Let's get in-dasu.
This is the power room? What is the power source of Megaton Castle?
Those five people are power sources-dasu.
What?
Nobunaga said that Megaton Castle is powered by the psychokinesis of these Five Mystery Monks-dasu.
Psychokinesis, eh?
But by shifting the seats of these monks, their psychokinesis will work against Megaton Castle, leaving it in pieces.
They're too deep in psychokinesis to notice us-dasu.
Great! That's just great.
I'm tired-dasu.
I'm done, too.
Let's hurry our way out!
W- what's going on?!
I- I don't know!
Find out what's going on!
The panel isn't working right!
Damn! We were almost there!
Everyone, abandon Megaton Castle and get out!
Even without Megaton Castle, I have the Three Sacred Treasures!
Everyone! Follow me!
Phoenix Sword!
Did I do it?
Curse you!
Were you bastards still alive?!
We don't die until we're done with all the evil on this world-dasu!
Megaton Castle is no more! Give it up, Hanzō!
We will finish this right now!
Just as I wanted!
Karakuri Shift!
Gentoku Armor!
Kanu Armor!
Karakuri Shift!
Chohi Armor!
Megaton Castle is falling! Look!
What?! Mr. Musashi's on there!
At last, that's the last battle.
How deplorable, that we have to just gave at that!
Everyone, do your best to finish Hanzō!
Right, I got a new poem.
Your Highness! This is not a good time to read some Haiku!
Understood.
Musashi. Kojirō. Jūbee. Make it.
That Hanzō bastard. How much more do he have to defy me for him to be satisfied?
Mr. Musashi, do your best!
That Megaton Castle is a great invention. I want to make something like that, too.
Mr. Musashi, do not die. If you die, then I'll follow you.
But, I guess it'd be fine. Mr. Musashi is strong! Moreover, he said he'll marry me, after all!
Mr. Musashi! Do your best!
Aren't you good, Musashi!?
That's obvious-dasu! That's because I'm going to be the number one martial artist of Jipang-dasu!
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
I'll break your sword!
What a relief-dasu. Tenkūmaru is important to me, next to Otsuru-dasu.
Musashi! Prepare yourself!
Mr. Musashi!
Mr. Jūbee, you saved me-dasu!
Tch, how dare he do that!?
Hanzō!
All your subordinates are now down! You're the only one remaining!
Give up your ambition to take over the world!
Hmph, you're asking me to give it up? I already have the whole world in my hands!
That's because, I have the certificate of the king: the Three Sacred Treasures!
What?! Why do you have the Three Sacred Treasures?!
The king gave this to me.
Hanzō! Even if you have the Three Sacred Treasures, nobody will recognize you as a king!
Whoever does not recognize will be killed!
We can't stand watching that here! It'll fall!
They have to escape!
Mr. Musashi! Mr. Musashi!
It seems that I'm at disadvantage. See you later again!
Hanzō! Wait-dasu!
Don't run away!
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
Damn! Unhand me-dasu! Damn you!
You have been a fly to me, Musashi. I'll tear off your arms for that!
Ow, ow, ow, ow! stop that-dasu!
It hurts! It hurts! That hurts-dasu!
Damn!
How dare you do that, Musashi?!
The Three Sacred Treasures!
Hanzō, this revenge is for Ms. Himiko-dasu!
Niten'ichiryū: Double Dragon Sword!
Evil will be perished-dasu.
What are you talking? I'm not dead yet!
Mr. Musashi!
Hanzō is taken down. Right at that moment, what is recurring in Musashi's heart?
The long days of battles are over, and the trip with Senhime and Kojirō is also about to end.
Otsuru!
But, Musashi's journey might be about to truly begin.
Wait for the tense next story!
I fought and I got beaten
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
I can't lose, so take my blow!
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
Next is delightful lunchtime
But it's not delightful today
The thunder of my teacher
only hit me and nobody else
I tried to explain
But he won't listen
Now whatever I do
I end up crying
Don't cry when you eat, or
it tastes totally bad
you'll feel downhearted
Osenchan and the Highness are going to marry-dasu!
That might help with Osenchan's selfishness, and she might become like other women-dasu!
And Kojirō and I marry on Ganryu Island-dasu.
No, no, we have a match there-dasu!
This is a serious match between men, risking our lives, which will determine the truly stronger martial artist!
Next story! Musashi vs. Kojirō
It's the stormy last story-dasu!
Next Episode
Musashi vs.
Kojirō
Look forwards for it!