It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Musashi finally made it to Edotopia, but he was caught and jailed by Zenigatan.
His innocence was proven at last and he ran to Edo Castle,
but he was too late and Edo Castle's doors were already closed.
Will Musashi be able to participate in the martial arts competition?
Raid into
the Martial Arts Competition
Jipangu Martial Arts Competition
Ieyasu
Finally! I am Musashi, from Miyamoto village!
A match!
Benkei appears!
It's the Miyamoto watermelon cutting technique-dasu!
I lost!
Baiken! Here I go!
It's the Miyamoto daikon cutting technique-dasu!
Musashi, you're awesome!
Leave it to me-dasu!
How unsightly is your ogling!
Oh, my rival Kojirō! I'll finish you as of today-dasu!
You're 10 years early to say that!
Look! Secret sword Tsubamegaeshi!
Huh?! It's a UFO-dasu.
Huh?
It's the Miyamoto burdock cutting technique-dasu!
Idi...ot...
The match is over! Musashi from Miyamoto village wins the championship!
As of now, I'm the number one of Jipangu-dasu! Otsuru, be happy-dasu!
I'm happy!
Musashi, wake up! Musashi!
It's not the time to be sleeping.
Aren't you joining to the competition?
Otsuru!
Ah, right!
Boss Zenigatan, I am indebted-dasu.
See you later-dasu.
Wait for a moment!
No use stopping me-dasu. To become the number one swordsman of Jipangu...
Huh?
Your swords are here.
Heh, I lost-dasu!
Before the competition, you gotta be full first.
This is an awesome meal-dasu!
Take this as an apology, for throwing you into a prison.
Heh, an apology!
I'm embarrassed-dasu!
I am truly sorry for holding you stubbornly and making you fail to register for the competition.
It's alright-dasu. Something will happen-dasu. I'll ask them-dasu!
Anyway, do your best for the championship in the martial arts competition!
Thank you for the meal!
Here! Have this!
What's this?
It's a viper drink that has the power of 100 people.
Vi- vi- viper drink?!
Feeling it! I'm feeling it! I'm feeling it right now-dasu!
I look forward for your victory!
It burns-dasu! It boils-dasu! It explodes-dasu!
Stop!
I'm in a hurry-dasu. Move away-dasu!
This is the office of General Ieyasu. It's not a place for a kid to come!
No, that's not it! I am Musashi, a Martial Artist from Miyamoto village-dasu!
I am going to participate in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition of General Ieyasu-dasu! Where do I register-dasu?
What's so funny-dasu?!
Hey, registration for the martial arts competition was yesterday. The first preliminary contest is already over.
I know-dasu. But I couldn't register yesterday because I was slightly late-dasu!
Then come again, in next year.
I can't wait until next year-dasu!
Please! I'll give you 10 mons-dasu.
What? Are you trying to bribe us working under the shōgun?
Go back! If you don't go back, we'll call the police!
Bro! I'll make hundreds of funny faces, so cheer up-dasu!
Whatever you do, they are futile! Leave right now!
Don't say that... Look! Mimicry!
Handstanding! Look!
We told you to go back, and we mean it!
I get it-dasu! I'm going to enter the competition by force-dasu!
What? Defiance against the shōgun is a ground for decapitation. Go back!
Decapitated?! My dream that I risked my life for...
I endured the hunger and practiced through all the hardships for this day and...
You're cruel-dasu!
How noisy! Do something with that!
What are you doing-dasu?!
Damn! Remember this...
Fifth Preliminary Contest Place
Preliminary contest places were placed in 7 different areas of Edotopia,
and martial artists from different places were doing their best.
Fifth Preliminary Contest Place
I- I lost!
Match set! Jūbee wins!
-Master...
-I guess he's not here too.
Could it be that something happened to Musashi after all...?
Unlikely. There are 7 places in total. We have two more to check out, so don't worry.
-Then, to the next place!
-Sure. We'll find him in the next place.
Musashi...
Extra! Extra! At the third preliminary place, Kojirō took down three opponents with his Tsubamegaeshi!
-He's so handsome!
-So cool! He's totally my type!
Kojirō!
Kojirō?
It's a water monster!
I'm not a water monster-dasu.
Appeared with his secret sword Tsubamegaeshi like a comet in the first martial arts competition,
Kojirō is a genius martial artist...
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
So cool! Kojirō!
As one of the promising champion candidates, he is popular among the women in Edotopia.
Something must be wrong, to call that unsightly bastard a champion candidate-dasu!
-Look, look! How silly!
-His face and look are all uncool!
Shut up-dasu!
dasu? Uncool!
I won't forgive any more insult-dasu! I'll spank you-dasu!
He's an idiot after all!
This is enough-dasu...
Sixth Preliminary Contest Place
Huh, there's a small castle in this place too-dasu.
This is what Edotopia is like-dasu...
Uh, who lives in this castle-dasu?
What are you talking about? This is one of the preliminary place of Jipangu Martial Arts Competition!
Oh, that's good to know-dasu!
Hey, now, where are you going to?
It's obvious-dasu! I'm competing in the martial arts competition-dasu.
Then show me the voucher.
Voucher? What's that-dasu?
You should have received one from the registration!
In the registration... Ah, right-dasu!
Huh? Something's not right-dasu. I must've left it back at the inn-dasu.
Then go take it.
Hey, I'd like you to let me go inside no matter what-dasu. There is no time-dasu.
Well, the competition already began...
I'd like you to let me go insisde-dasu.
Alright. Let me check the roster. What's your name?
Musashi from Miyamoto village... no, um...
Ah, I am Kojirō-dasu!
Kojirō will go to the third contest place.
Not here.
Ah, I'm sorry-dasu. It's Baiken-dasu.
Baiken? He is already having a match inside here!
This is bad-dasu.
A suspicious guy that impersonate another person's name!
N- no, I, I...
A malcontent interrupting the competition!
Get him!
N- no, stop it-dasu! I didn't do anything wrong-dasu!
No questions accepted! Resist and be cut!
Right!
You're making me do this-dasu!
Stop right there!
Boss Zenigatan!
You idiot! I told you not to fight with random people!
What are you doing-dasu?!
This guy is the one I recently hired, and definitely isn't someone suspicious.
Are you saying that he's under your order?
Right. Please excuse him with your generous mind. He just came from the heart of the mountains after all!
Alright. But be careful.
Now, go! Quick! Help tidying up the place!
I'll introduce him later.
Musashi from Miyamoto village... Hanzō's subordinates must be informed.
Will Musashi be able to compete in the martial arts competition? Wait for the stormy latter half!
I guess we made it in.
Please understand that I had to hit you moments ago.
It's alright. You did surprise me though-dasu!
If something goes wrong and you are pointed out as a traitor, you might get shot by Hanzō's underlings...
Hanzō?
He is a monster-like chief of Iga Ninja Force that guards Edo Castle.
In this place too. Look!
There too.
Are they Hanzō's underlings-dasu?
When they find anyone suspicious, they would get rid of them without second thoughts.
So be careful.
Got it-dasu.
I'll wish you to be able to participate in the competition!
Please stay here.
Hanzō must be...
that bad guy trying to take down the shōgunate.
I did thought I should tell this to Jūbee.
No-dasu! I came to the martial arts competition!
Lunch time begins now. Semi-semi-finals will begin in afternoon.
So it's best eight-dasu... From now on anything goes.
I got a secret plan-dasu!
He's not here too. I wonder what happened to Musashi...
I guess it wasn't here either. We still have the last place left. Don't be disheartened.
Yes.
This is the waiting room for the competition participants.
Non-personnel are not allowed to enter!
I am here to deliver lunch box-dasu.
Lunch box? Nobody told me about this.
But this is true-dasu.
Who asked for it?
E- excuse me!
Ah, ah, there he is-dasu! Hey, you!
Hey, just a moment!
-Can I leave it inside-dasu?
-Right. Come back as soon as possible.
Alright, thank you all the time-dasu!
Who are you?!
I'm not someone suspicious-dasu. I have a present for you-dasu!
What? A present?
Right-dasu! A present from a pretty girl-dasu!
-Wh- what?!
-How wonderful are you, you lady-killer!
Heh, I see, of course!
-Open this right away!
-Alright-dasu.
What could it be...
Did it hurt-dasu? I'm sorry-dasu.
Please don't move until the competition ends-dasu.
Time for the semi-semi-finals!
Semi-semi-final match will be between Narutouzushioryū, Hachisukadonbe,
and his competitor, Hanbasasayamaryū, Gozaemon!
That's right-dasu!
Gozaemon, what's with that mask?
Oh, I suddenly feel dizzy...
Wouldn't it be difficult to have a good match in that case?
N- no, it'll be alright-dasu!
As you see-dasu!
Then come out!
This shall be an one-game match!
Start!
Baiken, we'll have the final match here-dasu!
That's why I must win no matter what-dasu!
Chance!
That posture... and movement reminds me... but still...
That's best 8... He's not going down so easily-dasu!
Secret sword Whirling Tides of Maelstrom!
What-dasu?
In this rate, I'm going to be dizzy and lose-dasu...
Futile attempt!
What should I do-dasu...
I'm getting dizzy-dasu...
That's it-dasu!
Thrust!
I lost!
Match set! Gozaemon wins!
I did-dasu! Yay!
Thank you!
My name is Musashi-dasu, but... it feels complicated-dasu.
That's some fine judgment skills you got, Gozaemon.
Semi-semi-finals will feature Kusarigamaryū Baiken,
The competitor is Fear Destroy-ryū, Suzuki Shigenoshin!
Brother! Do your best!
Stop! Baiken wins!
That's our brother!
G- Gozaemon!
Finals will begin soon in the sixth preliminary place!
Baiken
Gozaemon
Victory
Moreover, the winner of this match can join the final match
in the presence of General Ieyasu as the top 7 Karakuri martial artists.
Whoever wins, it will become one of the good memories.
Start!
Judging on that posture, he is Musashi!
Musashi! Why did you do this?
Chink in the armor!
You are Musashi!
That guy is a fake!
That guy cowardly sneaked in, used violence to make me pass out,
and assumed my identity! A fake Martial Artist!
What? Is that true?
He's a traitor for hindering the sacred martial arts competition the shōgun approved!
Get him and execute him!
-Right!
-Wait!
Whoever he is, this is the match that will decide the participation
to the final match in the presence of General Ieyasu! I will finish this!
Alright, as you wish. To do as Baiken said, step back for now!
Baiken...
We'll settle this, Musashi!
How impertinent!
Escape using the emergency exit on the other side.
Baiken... that will bother...
It's fine! Go!
You heinous impostor martial artist! Take this!
Match set! Baiken wins!
As expected from Baiken!
Where did that man go?!
He isn't there! Get him!
There he is!
If he resists, you may cut him!
Musashi... I don't know what happened, but please be safe!
What happened to Musashi?
It'll be all right! Don't worry!
He is a vicious criminal! Get him no matter what and execute him!
That's wrong-dasu! I didn't do anything wrong-dasu!
Musashi?
-Musashi!
-Move!
Yeah, he definitely is Musashi. But I wonder what did he do...
But it's a relief... Musashi did make it to Edotopia!
This is Musashi.
He was destined to fall to the hell by my hands.
I'm starved-dasu...
Supposed to be dreaming to be the number one martial artist of Jipangu,
but how miserable! Musashi has gained a dishonor of a traitor that defies against Ieyasu,
and became a heinous criminal that is wanted.
Will Musashi even have a tomorrow?
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
As a wanted man, I rescued a cute child surrounded by bad guys-dasu.
That child actually was Senhime, a granddaughter of Ieyasu, but not knowing that,
I sneaked into the martial arts competition place and had a match against Jūbee-dasu.
Next story! Rescue Senhime and Have a Match-dasu.
Check out the stormy great activity!
Next Episode
and Have a Match
Rescue Senhime
Look forwards for it!