It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Hanzō's evil plan was finally discovered by Jūbee, and he ran away after making clear of his ambition to rule over Jipangu.
Onihime attacked Musashi's group and took Senhime away.
Musashi and Kojirō put their swords down in a condition of letting Senhime alive.
Will Senhime survive?!
Ice-Melting
Power of Friendship
See! We've put down our swords! Now keep the promise!
Hanzō!
Only kids make promises. Shouldn't you be old enough to stop being kids, Musashi, Kojirō?
I, Hanzō, am after the domination of the whole globe. Whoever gets in my way will be gotten rid of.
That's dirty-dasu! You call yourself a martial artist-dasu?1
How unfortunate. I am a ninja. If I can win, then it's good enough.
Musashi! Kojirō! Forget about me and run for your lives!
I won't forgive you anymore-dasu!
What a fool.
Help!
The rivals yet friends of Musashi are hurrying.
Will they be able to make it in time?
Musashi!
I won't make it-dasu.
Musashi, do not give up!
Use those as stepping stones!
Thank you, Kojirō!
I'm going-dasu!
Onihime! Fight me-dasu!
How foolish! Take this! Ice Walls!
It's so cold-dasu...
You aren't taking me down by that!
That was pretty good, Kojirō. Then let me show you my Snow Concrete Strategy.
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ...
Yeah!
Pity me!
Musashi! Kojirō!
All the obstacles are gone. Only Senhime to go.
Senhime!
Leave it to me!
Jūbee! Everyone!
Jūbee, you bastard! Again! Everyone, kill them!
I'll get Senhime!
Ushiwaka! Double Eight Leap!
Thank you, Ushiwaka! Are you okay?
You're safe now, Senhime.
Mr. Ushiwaka...
Leaving a good rival be dead to the hands of evil is not fun at all.
Thank you-dasu!
Mr. Ushiwaka! Take care of Osenchan-dasu!
Got it.
Musashi, be careful!
Onihime! It's my turn to pay back-dasu!
Senhime! This way!
Damn! There's no end to this!
Benkei! Cut this off!
What?!
It worked!
Hanzō! You have nowhere to run now! Prepare yourself!
Instead of that, you'll be paid for everything you did to me!
Damn!
Stop!
Ouch! Damn!
That's as far as you go!
Kojirō! You look pretty good, after being so disgraceful of yourself!
Silence! You won't get away anymore!
We'll see about that.
Did you forget that you're now at Karakuri Stronghold?
Stop!
Damn!
You're actually going down this time! Die, Musashi!
Kojirō?!
-I'll face you this time!
-Well then!
Kojirō! Take your sword!
Thanks!
Thank you-dasu!
Now go get Hanzō!
Mr. Musashi!
Sorry for being late!
Hanzō! Prepare yourself!
You're outnumbering me, bastards! That's cowardly!
Cowardly? Who do you mean by that-dasu?!
Give it up if you have any honor!
Silence! Jiraiyan, I'm leaving this to you!
Hanzō! Where did you go?!
I, Jiraiyan, will face you!
Jiraiyan! Give up your futile resistance-dasu!
Do you think that you can win over our teamwork?!
Lord Hanzō belings to my clan! I will protect him risking my life!
That determination is respectable! Now disappear!
Friendship and teamwork. If a martial artist has those...
W- what is it-dasu?1
Lord Hanzō!
I have no choice else than to take care of all of you at once. Prepare yourselves!
The decisive battle at Karakuri Stronghold is a series of crisis!
Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
Mr. Musashi! This way, right now!
You bastard!
Mr. Musashi!
Jiraiyan! You finish that!
Three
Two
One
OK
Why are you working for evil, with your level of skills?!
Lord Hanzō is my clan. For the obligation! But...
Why are you hesitating?
Why do you live in shadows? Wouldn't you like to practice swordsmanship under the sun like us?
I'd be doing that if I could! But...
What?!
Onihime!
Why did you...
I am a human too. I wanted to have a fight with you, Kojirō, for once, under the light.
Onihime!
Damn!
That's as far as you go!
Give it up-dasu!
Damn!
Jiraiyan! You're being slow!
Lord Hanzō!
Jiraiyan! Guide them to the other world! Farewell!
Who's there?!
Feel the might of the chain of friendship!
Baiken!
Baiken! You came for us-dasu!
Without you, Musashi, Jipangu Martial Arts Competition won't be interesting as now!
There must be a power room, to operate a stronghold this big.
So destroying that will do.
It's so pretty!
Senhime! No!
What's this?!
That was close.
It's full of scary traps...
Senhime!
Where are we?
You two should better become a skewer.
Ushiwaka!
It seems that we must be prepared for the worst.
I won't. I believe in Musashi.
More specifically, the friendship between Musashi's friends!
-Osenchan!
-Mr. Ushiwaka!
Osenchan!
So Musashi's here.
Lord Hanzō!
Oh, Jiraiyan, were you safe? You are truly the best of my Four Kings. Good job, good job.
What's with your grim face? We will take those Musashi bunch down and dominate over the globe.
Osenchan!
-Musashi!
-Kojirō!
Anything from that way?
None-dasu.
They already ran away, eh...
Shh! I can hear Osenchan's flute!
This way-dasu!
Musashi... Kojirō... I am here.
I've been waiting for you, Musashi!
Hanzō! Where is Osenchan-dasu?!
Come here. Then you'll know.
Whatever you say, you can't get away-dasu!
Go! Jiraiyan!
Yessir!
Senhime!
Kojirō!
It's a good thing that I believed in you...
Musashi! Senhime is fine!
Hearing that is very relieving-dasu!
Hanzō! When did you escape?! Stop!
Open the door, Hanzō!
A time bomb will soon explode.
What?!
Lord Hanzō!
Jiraiyan, guide them to the other world properly this time. Farewell.
Damn!
Kojirō, get out of my way-dasu!
Damn, it's not working!
Don't give up!
Jiraiyan!
It should open by now!
Alright! We'll scrum by three this time-dasu!
Great!
Again-dasu!
Hanzō! There's nowhere for you to escape anymore! Disembowel and your death will be honorary!
You must be ignorant of the fact that I, Hanzō, am immortal!
I will turn over Jipangu State and take the world into my hands!
Stop!
We found you-dasu!
You won't be doing as you want anymore-dasu!
Senhime!
Musashi! I've been worried for you!
Your ambition ends here!
Give it up, Hanzō!
You were alive! How?!
I helped them!
Jiraiyan! You betrayed me!
We have lost to the teamwork and friendship of Musashi!
Save your honor!
Silence, you traitor! Fall into hell with the stronghold!
No! Everyone, run away!
Got it-dasu!
Are all of you okay-dasu?!
Yeah, seems so!
That's great-dasu!
Jiraiyan, you're safe-dasu!
Musashi! Cut me off!
I am a bad guy. I've betrayed my master.
Even for a fag end of swordsman, I will know my shame!
Please!
Jiraiyan...
Kerokichi!
Jiraiyan!
You can die whenever you want, but then what about Kerokichi-dasu?
Jiraiyan! You're alive, so please keep being alive! For Kerokichi, too!
There's someone who needs me.
That's enough, Jiraiyan.
Great.
Take a good care of Kerokichi.
Musashi! I'll skip my gratitude!
Gratitude, eh...
But!
You have good friends.
Jiraiyan!
I will pay back this favor!
Take care-dasu!
The blood-freezing battle at Karakuri Stronghold is over.
Something hot is gushing out from Musashi's heart, thanking the comrades who fought for the friendship despite of rivalry.
But is Hanzō truly dead?
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
General Ieyasu called us home, and we went back to Edotopia-dasu.
Being relaxed after a long time feels so good-dasu!
Kojirō is watching plays, and I'm at a temple festival with Zenigatan boss.
Osenchan was enjoying her marriage mettings and short holidays,
What?! That Hanzō was still alive-dasu!
Next story! The Most Evil! Hanzō Revives
It's stormy Edotopia-dasu!
Next Episode
The Most Evil!
Hanzō Revives
Look forwards for it!