It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
After getting into Sakurajima, Musashi and others challenge for the last decisive battle against Shiranui Clan,
but Hanzō launches a missile to Satsumania.
But thanks to Musashi, it was stopped.
But Himiko, who gave the feeling of mother, died.
I Defeated
Kojirō!
Musashi? Finish it already!
I'm almost done-dasu!
Musashi, that tree looks like it's more than 300 years old.
You will be cursed, by peeing to a tree that old.
It'll be alright-dasu! I'm refreshed!
What's wrong with you? You're peeing everywhere, like a dog!
Senhime! I do not do that.
Really, Kojirō, stop bragging off-dasu! I know that you peed outdoors before today-dasu.
-W- what did you say!?
-Forget it! Let's stay in here today.
I want to pee again-dasu.
I'm refreshed-dasu!
Musashi!
Kojirō! Are you here to pee-dasu?
Musashi! How dare you reveal to Senhime that I peed outdoor!?
But that's true-dasu!
Unforgivable! Musashi, we'll have a match!
Just as I wanted-dasu!
Ganryu Tsubamegaeshi!
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
Musashi. Finish me.
Sympathy of years. I'll let you live-dasu.
Kojirō! Kojirō! Kojirō!
Do not die! If you die, then I'll die too, Kojirō!
I loved you from a long time ago. So... please don't die!
Senhime, that's same for me. I love you, princess!
Kojirō! Let's make make a happy household together, even if it's an ordinary one!
Let's do so. We'll have, um, 3 children!
If they're girls, then let's name them Naoko, Naoko, and Naoko!
It's full of Naokos!
I didn't ever know that they loved each other-dasu!
Anyway, I became the number one of Jipangu by this-dasu!
Otsuru and I will...
Mr. Musashi!
You finally become the number one of Jipangu! Otsuru's happy!
Otsuru!
Mr. Musashi!
It's just like a dream-dasu!
Ouch! What a relief-dasu! It's not a dream!
But, Otsuru, why are you here?
I wanted to meet you, Mr. Musashi, so much and I couldn't hold it anymore!
Musashi, you did it! I always knew you would make it!
You're here too, Takuan-dasu!
I hope you're happy!
A little bit.
Everyone from Miyamoto village is also here!
Really-dasu!?
Congratulations! Musashi is the Number One of Jipangu
Celebrating that Musashi from Miyamoto village became the number one of Jipangu, cheers!
Cheers!
Tangerine juice is delicious-dasu!
That's our Musashi!
Really! That guy is the pride of Miyamoto village!
That guy really is the genius martial artist that rarely comes out once in 100 years!
True, true!
You became a man while I wasn't seeing you!
You're making me shy-dasu!
Anyway, you're the man!
He's not bragging about his strength, too!
Hey, Musashi bro, tell us about all the stories about your battles!
-Yeah, yeah!
-I want to hear, too!
Really-dasu?
Then let me tell my story about when I got Tenkūmaru and Tenchimaru-dasu!
During our journey, we had to fight Tsuchigumo controlled by Onihime-dasu.
That must be...
That must be Tenchimaru!
Help me!
Otama!
I'm going right now!
W-what-
Tsuchigumo!
It's cowardly to come out of nowhere-dasu!
Kojirō!
Leave this to me. Musashi, you rescue that girl.
Come attack me, monster!
Otama, get a grip!
Otama, get onto my back-dasu!
Thank you.
Musashi! She isn't Otama!
Die, Musashi!
What are you doing?!
Prepare yourself-dasu!
Are you going to torment an old woman?
Grandma...
Musashi!
Go, Tsuchigumo!
Chink in the armor!
Osenchan!
Help me!
-Benkei!
-You're in good hands now!
We also heard about the monster and are here to exterminate! We'll help!
Ushiwaka!
Feeling lucky? I'll kill you all!
Hot!
Go! Tsuchigumo!
Leave the rest to me-dasu!
Musashi! Be careful!
My Kotetsu!
It's for the grudge of my precious Kotetsu-dasu!
After taking Tsuchigumo down and obtaining Tenchimaru, I had to fight Yamata no Orochi.
This definitely is Tenkūmaru!
And that's how I got Tenkūmaru and Tenchimaru-dasu!
Now, I'll tell about the battles I did in Hokkaido-dasu!
Mr. Musashi.
Please keep talking outside.
Now, what is this strange atmosphere? Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
Mr. Musashi, come here more.
Yes-dasu!
Otsuru, your hands are warm!
Mr. Musashi, the journey of training to become a swordman must've been difficult!
No, not that much-dasu. I have an objective, so even if it was tough...
Thinking about that, I showed man's tears for once-dasu.
Tell me, Mr. Musashi.
At that time, we were fighting against Shiranui Clan-dasu.
As long as evil exists in this world, my mission is to exterminate them!
It hurts, it hurts!
Mommy! It hurts, it hurts!
Mommy! It hurts!
What's wrong, Musashi?
I fell down.
That must've hurt! Pain, pain, go away!
Look! You're fine now!
Yeah, I'm good now!
Mommy...
Mommy!
It was a dream...
Mr. Musashi? Did you wake up?
Mommy...
No, Mr. Musashi!
Being like this feels like I'm with my mother-dasu!
Am I really that like your mother, Mr. Musashi?
Well, I have never met my mother-dasu.
I'll show you the difference of the swords of Niten'ichiryū-dasu!
When I woke up, I was alone-dasu...
I see.
If she exists, then I guess that she's just like you, Ms. Himiko!
I feel great-dasu. It really worth it to come to Unzen-dasu!
Ms. Himiko was really kind, and she was as if my mother-dasu.
But...
Musashi! That Himiko woman is the queen of Shiranui Clan!
That can't be true-dasu!
I checked it and there's no doubt about it!
Ms. Himiko was so kind to me-dasu!
That woman is our enemy!
Don't talk! I don't want to listen-dasu!
I don't want to listen-dasu.
I get it, Musashi.
I couldn't believe that kind Ms. Himiko was a queen of Shiranui-dasu.
That's why I went to Sakurajima, the base of Shiranui...
Everyone! The time has come!
We will take General Ieyasu down and claim Jipangu State into our hands!
Just like Jiraiyan said, Ms. Himiko is the queen of Shiranui...
Lord Himiko! Lord Himiko!
Listen to me, everyone. A new comrade is going to help us for our revival.
Mr. Hanzō.
Everyone! For our objective, Shiranui must move first and do an armed uprising to overthrow Jipangu State.
Everyone! Make an oath of victory to Hanzō and me!
Yessir! Queen Himiko! Yesser! Mr. Hanzō!
Where are you going!?
Um, err, that's, I was so excited that I want to urinate-dasu.
dasu?
Nonono, I'm going-gowasu.
Show your face!
N- no, this isn't a face worth being shown-dasu.
Nono, gowasu!
Ahh! Stop it-gowasu!
Musashi?! Musashi, you!
Ms. Himiko! No, Himiko!
You dared to deceive me-dasu, Himiko!
It means that you're a fool.
But as usual, your idiocy wasn't fixed after all!
How dare you sneak into the base of Shiranui unconcernedly!
That dauntlessness is my personality-dasu!
Do not babble, you brat!
Damn!
I will send you back to that world this time!
What!?
Jiraiyan!
Musashi!
I'm sorry-dasu, Jiraiyan. That Himiko really was the queen of Shiranui-dasu.
Forget about that; just run away!
And? What happened?
Hanzō betrayed Ms. Himiko and Ms. Himiko died-dasu.
Musashi. Will you forgive me?
M- Musashi. Please call me mother for the last time.
Mother!
That must've been hurt.
Right-dasu.
Er, Otsuru, when did you get a tail-dasu?
Huh? Wha-!? A dumpling is flying!
Huh? W- where is it flying-dasu?
I can't see it-dasu!
Huh?
Maybe I'm half asleep-dasu.
Here! Your favorite rice balls!
Otsuru's rice balls are the best-dasu!
T- they're hard-dasu.
What is that Musashi doing on a worn-out house?
I wonder if he's half asleep.
L- look at that!
Senhime, you're there.
You too, Kojirō.
Oh my, he's fooled by raccoons again.
Oh, you must be the owner of this inn.
What do you mean by being fooled by raccoons?
Didn't that martial artist peed on that big tree?
Yes, he did that yesterday...
(tanuki: raccoon, ki: tree)
I knew it. That tree is called Raccoon Tree. It's the guardian god of raccoon around this place.
But since he peed on there, raccoons got angry!
T- they're hard-dasu!
How can he be fooled by raccoons?! How miserable! He's a pathetic excuse for a martial artist!
Agreed.
First class martial artists should be able to distinguish between raccoons and humans!
Oh, right. You have to pay for the stay.
Oh, excuse me. It was 300 mons, right?
Thank you so much.
You fool!
R- raccoon!
Can't first class martial artists distinguish between raccoons and humans?!
Otsuru, this rice ball is hard-dasu!
When he thought he became the number one of Jipangu, he was simply fooled by raccoons. That's totally Musashi.
But don't be discouraged, Musashi! A bright tomorrow is waiting for you!
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
We're finally back at Edotopia-dasu!
The real Otsuru is there this time-dasu!
I'm happy-dasu!
The marial artist competition that I've been waiting for is about to begin, so I'm going to do my best-dasu!
But meanwhile, Hanzō joins a mysterious group!
Next story! He Appeared! Mysterious Rikudomaoh
It's the stormy Miyako Palace-dasu!
Next Episode
He Appeared!
Mysterious Rikudomaoh
Look forwards for it!