It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Musashi and others entered Seto Inland Sea to find the base of Nobunaga the Rikudomaoh,
and then they entered into the Mouth of Orc to get the armor of aliens
handed down in Onogoro Island, and they got a mysterious ring.
Thus, with the armor of Gentoku, Kanu, and Chohi, they powered up and their new battles are about to begin.
Surfing Gennai
is the Invention King
Feels good!
I finally found you, Musashi! You'll be paid back for everything you did to me!
Launch Flame Bullets!
This is bad! A monster! A monster is terrorizing the village!
What!?
Fire! Fire!
Megaton Castle!
Damn! What kind of cruel thing to do is that!?
Mr. Musashi! This is bad!
Otsuru!
Senhime isn't there. I couldn't find her when I did!
-What?
-Could she be captured by Megaton Castle?
Get out of my way! Musashi, you're standing in my way! Move!
Osenchan, you're safe!
Osenchan, are you alright? Osenchan?
Don't be tardy and put off the fire!
Understood-dasu!
Where's Jiraiyan!?
I can't find him-dasu!
This way! Don't rush and calm down!
Everyone, don't get lost!
Our village...
How cruel of them!
The villagers didn't do anything wrong...
How dare they harass the people without crimes!? Nobunaga or Kobunaga(small fish), I, Musashi, cannot forgive-dasu!
Hey, Musashi!
-Mr. Musashi, where are you going!?
-Musashi!
Stop right there-dasu, Megaton Castle! Fight fair and square-dasu!
Megaton Castle, where did you go-dasu?
Hey, wake up!
Idiot! Fool! Dimwit! There is no way that you can possibly chase that Megaton Castle, sunk under the sea!
It means that Mr. Musashi's anger is so deep!
Anyway, still, we need a vehicle that can go inside water...
But, how?
That's simple!
If you ask Mr. Gennai, an inventor, then he might make you one!
Mr. Gennai?
Can he really make a vehicle that can go inside the sea-dasu?
Yes. He's an inventor who always make some weird things, so he should make you one!
Huh? I- is this seriously Mr. Gennai's house?
This house looks interesting-dasu!
Mr. Gennai! Mr. Gennai! Mr. Gennai?
-Mr. Gennai!
It seems that he's not home-dasu.
Hey, he's there!
Hey, Mr. Gennai!
Huh? Is him Mr. Gennai?
Mr. Gennai! Mr. Gennai!
Hey!
Mr. Gennai!
What is it, Kenta? Do you need me?
They had something to ask you, Mr. Gennai.
What? You have something to ask me?
Well, that is, we heard about you, Mr. Gennai...
You heard about me?
Yeahyeahyeahyeah! You're one old weirdo geezer with an extremely bad personality-
N- no, we heard that you're a great genius inventor!
Genius, eh?
Yes. Your inventions are famous in Edotopia, too.
From children to old people, everybody knows you!
Kojirō, you're skillful-dasu! You said that you never heard of him-dasu!
Shut up!
I see. I am famous in many places, eh?
Yes!
You're making Gen-chan embarrassed!
After Kenta went back to the village, Musashi and others stayed at Gennai's house.
I see. You want me to make a vehicle that can go underwater, which is a submarine, right?
Yes. Only you, Mr. Gennai, can make such thing, in the whole Jipangu State.
I'm happy to hear that.
-Please!
-We ask you!
If you really want that much...
Will you do it?
No.
I'm sorry, but saying no when being asked is my hobby.
Hey! Don't touch that!
That's why I told you not to touch electricity.
Please! Mr. Gennai!
-Please!
-Please-dasu!
I'm too whimsy to accept whoever's request so easily.
One more cup.
Oh, got it!
I want some fruits.
Oh, right!
I want to read a book.
Yes!
I want a pillow.
I want to eat an eel.
Yes!
My back is itchy.
Yes! To where?
I want to watch television.
Yes!
This feels good.
Both Otsuru and Osenchan can quit-dasu!
He's just fooling around because he can't make one-dasu!
This guy cannot possibly a great inventor, but instead, he's just an old geezer who happens to surf-dasu!
W- what the heck are you saying, Musashi!?
Kiddo, you're the first one to call me a surfing geezer.
Well then, if even one of you can surf on that waves, then I'll think about it.
Well, I was born in mountain-dasu...
What about you, Mr. Jūbee?
I became fat recently.
Kojirō!
I- I'm suffering from anemia recently...
I'll do it.
Osenchan!
Osenchan! Please do it-dasu!
Heh, surfing is beautiful when done by a girl in swimsuit.
Moreover, high-legs! This is the best!
But only one doesn't look complete...
Even for a high-leg, one isn't enough... Maybe I'll feel more like doing it if there are two...
For that, I can do it...
Oh, I see, I see!
N- no way-dasu, Otsuru!
I'll do it, Mr. Musashi! I can't lose to Senhime!
Huh? B- but, Otsuru...
I want to be helpful, Mr. Musashi.
Otsuru...
This is all I can do...
Nostalgic! It'll be a perfect appearance when she gets wet in water! I can't believe this!
The clothes will stick to the body and the lines will show up...
Did I say something?
I like your brave attitude. I am a man too. I'll make a submarine for you.
Don't put on airs-dasu, you perverted old geezer! How unsightly!
Huh?
Will the submarine even be made? Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
Making a submarine is easier than cooking!
Mr. Gennai!
Otsuru's here! Let's take a break!
Yeah!
Ouch!
Ow, my finger! My finger!
What an energetic old man-dasu.
But, can we really trust on Mr. Gennai-dasu?
It's not like there is someone that we can ask.
My sword is not a saw or an ax.
Hey, there aren't enough lumbers!
R- right! I'll be there soon!
This is what my inventions look like. Look at its design and its form. It's completely brilliant.
It looks like a pop-eyed goldfish.
Oh, what did you say?
N- no, no, it's truly excellent, yes!
Let's chase Megaton Castle right away-dasu!
Then, see you later-dasu!
Don't overdo it, Mr. Musashi.
I want to go with them.
Have a nice trip! Bring some present-
What are you saying? You're going with them!
What, me too?
It's obvious-dasu! Who'll pilot this, else than Mr. Gennai-dasu?
Come on.
You're suspicious. You're hiding something, aren't you?
Er, no, I don't have courage to ride in a ship that I made.
Well, there's a manual inside, so that you can learn how to operate!
You're really irresponsible-dasu...
Do your best, everyone!
Mr. Musashi! Be careful!
T- this is so narrow-dasu...
It was low-cost, so deal with it. Now, this will do this, and this...
It's sinking, it's sinking! It's success! Hooray!
Wait. If it just sinks, then it's just a sinking ship. It's a submarine when it floats back up.
You know what will happen to you if they don't make it back, right?
R- right, of course...
Wow! How beautiful-dasu!
We became a fish-dasu.
It's not the time to be festive!
Since we're finding Megaton Castle in this wide sea, it will take a while.
There's a reaction on the radar!
Is it Megaton Castle-dasu?
I don't know. But it's pretty big.
That's it-dasu.
Huh? That must be...
Jiraiyan!
Mr. Jiraiyan?
We couldn't find him because he was scuba diving at a place like this...
Let me explain why is Jiraiyan perfectly fine in waters. It's because he's using the roll as an air tank.
Musashi!
What, what? We are following, -dasu, eh?
He's telling us to follow him-dasu.
Great!
Now!
What's going on!?
It seems that we're attacked with torpedoes from below!
What!?
Punish them thoroughly and make them into scraps of seaweed!
What's this?
Hey, don't do that, Kerokichi!
Wah! We'll end up becoming seaweeds(mozuku)-dasu!
It's scraps of seaweed(mokuzu), you dimwit!
You're great, Kojirō! What artisanship!
But it's only a matter of time before we get hit.
Right. There's supposedly a secret weapon here, for the times of need.
This is it!
This...?
Secret weapon.
Damn! Anything goes now!
W- what's that!?
It's heading toward here directly!
Evade! Evade at full speed!
There's not enough time!
You bastard! You bastard! You bastard! You bastard!
What!? Musashi bastards came into this Megaton castle!?
Yessir! They are heading to the 3rd pathway!
You brat! I'll get rid of you myself!
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
Hmph. How grateful of my prey, to save the trouble of finding one.
You are unforgivable-dasu! How dare you trouble the villagers who didn't do anything wrong!?
Yeah, say all what you want! This place will be your grave!
Hmph. All bark and no bite? It seems that you're 10 years too early to face me.
Go back and drink your mother's milk.
Even for adults, treating children like a fool is unforgivable-dasu!
Karakuri Shift!
Gentoku Armor!
How dare you brat have an armor like that!?
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
We'll sink at this rate! Increase output and rise!
Power Room! Full power!
Dokuganryu, prepare yourself-dasu!
Double-Headed Dragon!
Musashi!
Mr. Musashi!
We'll finish this later!
Stop-dasu!
W- what's going on!?
Wait-dasu!
Stop-dasu, Megaton Castle!
Alright, Kerokichi! Go!
We live...
Thank you, Kerokichi!
Still, it was so close. We went into Megaton Castle...
Well, we gave a lot of damage.
But, we lost the submarine that we just got-dasu...
What a relief-dasu. Otsuru might had to show her swimsuit look again-dasu.
But then again, that's kind of unfortunate-dasu...
Mr. Musashi!
Otsuru!
Look. They came back safely, just as I told you!
But it seems that the submarine is broken.
Hey, isn't that good enough for now?
Even while being abused by Gennai, a weird old geezer, Musashi and others challenged their way to Megaton Castle.
Where is Nobunaga, the boss of their enemy?
Where is the base of Megaton Castle? Wait for the next story when they'll discover the core of the secret!
I fought and I got beaten
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
I can't lose, so take my blow!
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
Next is delightful lunchtime
But it's not delightful today
The thunder of my teacher
only hit me and nobody else
I tried to explain
But he won't listen
Now whatever I do
I end up crying
Don't cry when you eat, or
it tastes totally bad
you'll feel downhearted
Using Mr. Gennai's submarine, we found the base of the enemy in the deep sea-dasu.
But because their defenses are strict, it's difficult to approach-dasu.
And there, Kojirō suggested a plan to disguise using stuffed toy!
But, I'm not sure about this-dasu...
Next story! Big Laughter Octopus Dance Strategy
It's a stormy raw octopus-dasu!
Next Episode
Big Laughter
Octopus Dance Strategy
Look forwards for it!