It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
After discovering the base of Nobunaga, after all the possible ways, Musashi and others managed to invade into Babel 13.
Right before taking Nobunaga down, they fell into Hanzō's trap, and their lives are at stake.
What will happen to them?
Destroy
Babel 13
Are you okay, Musashi?
I almost ended up drowning-dasu!
What a sight. That's what you get for trying to get in my way!
You bastard! Whatever you want won't happen!
No use, no use!
Damn! I don't want to die here!
I can't die until I eat more of Otsuru's dangos-dasu!
You can release them.
Are you saving us-dasu? Mr. Nobunaga, you're a good guy-dasu!
In exchange for that, tell me where Senhime is.
What-dasu!?
What are you going to do with Senhime!?
It's obvious. I'll take her as a hostage and make him pass over the seat of General.
You're cruel-dasu!
Hmph. No matter what you think, I do not like to see unnecessary blood.
Y- you're right!
That's right.
What do you think about that what'll happen if we do an all-out attack to Edotopia?
Edotopia will become a sea of fire, and numerous lives of people without any wrongdoing will be lost.
By taking Senhime as a hostage, nobody will suffer, and the world will fall under my hands.
I see, that makes sense-dasu.
You idiot! Who in the world gets struck with admiration for enemy's strategy!?
We will refuse your favor, no matter what it is, even if I have to die!
Me too!
If you say so... Dokuganryu!
Yessir.
Take some soldiers, search the neighboring islands, and capture Senhime.
Understood.
Wait. If they resists, you may kill them.
B- but, what's the point of taking hostage then?
Know that whether Senhime is alive does not matter. With Senhime's body, blackmailing Ieyasu is easily done.
You bastards! If you even touch Senhime, then I won't forgive you-dasu!
They are being late...
Maybe I should went with them, since it's so boring here.
You can't say that! Mr. Musashi and everyone are fighting to their best!
Lord!
Otsuru...
Well, you know who they are. They won't get caught so easily.
More importantly, here are your roasted sweet potatoes!
Mr. Gennai is the best! Super genius!
What's wrong, Otsuru? Aren't you eating one?
-Even you feel uneasy, it's not like we can help.
-Yeah, right!
Dear God, please forgive me for falling over to the temptation of sweet potatoes while Mr. Musashi is fighting.
Please let Mr. Musashi and everyone come back safely.
Pray all you want, but Musashi and others won't come back anymore!
W- what are you guys? Entering a girl's room without knocking is rude!
What do you mean by that Mr. Musashi and others won't be able to come back!?
Hmph. They should've died by now by water torture.
O- Otsuru!
Now, Senhime, you should follow us without resisting.
No way!
Well then.
We only have to take you, even if we have to kill you.
What is this!? Ganging up on girls is the worst!
Come into here!
Hmph! You have nowhere to go.
I wonder.
You did it! You're awesome, Mr. Gennai!
Nothing is impossible to a genius!
Get them!
Mr. Gennai! This won't hold for long!
(a little bit numb, numb, totally numb, extremely numb, burn)
It'll be alright. I'll teach them a lesson.
Push! Push! Push! Push!
Did it work?
What's wrong!?
What's going on!?
What's this!?
Did you see? This is the masterpiece of masterpiece among the inventions of me, Mr. Gennai! It's electricity!
A geezer with a weird thing, eh?
What are you doing? Get him!
No!
-Mr. Gennai is awesome!
-He's worth being that old!
Leave it to me!
Karakuri martial artists like you are weak to electricity.
Damn!
Well, well, if you aren't going to come, then let me make a move first.
Take this! Take this!
Go, go, go, go, Mr. Gennai!
H- huh? Don't you become numb?
Mr. Gennai! This! This!
What!?
Oh, today must be my last day.
Don't fool around, geezer!
We were so close!
Run!
Yes!
Damn!
Get them!
W- what's this!?
Get on!
Yeah!
Stop right there!
Great! Take off!
You won't be going anywhere now. Finish them!
W- who was that!?
The protector of whole 808 villages of Edo, Zenigatan, will face you!
Boss!
Benkei's here!
Your sword may forgive fighting feeble girls or powerless old men, but I won't forgive that action of a Karakuri martial artist!
Ushiwaka! You look cool!
Mr. Gennai, are you okay?
My back hurts...
Take this!
Damn!
Retreat!
You guys saved us, Ushiwaka!
It's a relief that you're safe, Senhime.
But, how did you make it here?
We were notified that the hideout of the enemies are nearby by Mr. Jūbee, and so we hurried our way to here.
Yeah! Let's ride on that and go save Musashi and others!
Great! Even one second is important now!
Right!
Mr. Musashi, be alive!
Wah! I don't want to die, before doing anything big at all-dasu!
Musashi! Don't be loud and use up all the air by ylurself!
We're going to die earlier than them because of you!
-Why-dasu!?
-Take a look at that!
What a sight. That miserable way of dying really suits you guys.
Damn! Scoundrel! Brute! I'll curse you-dasu!
How pleasant!
What's going on!?
Something is coming to attack this Babel 13!
What!?
Isn't that Megaton Castle?
What's going on!?
I don't know, but it's coming to crash!
I- it isn't! That isn't Megaton Castle!
Will Musashi and others be rescued? Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
N- no way!
Damn, who is it!?
Mr. Musashi, you were safe.
Get me out of here-dasu.
I'll rescue you right away.
Mr. Musashi!
Otsuru, you're here-dasu! Everyone too!
Thank you so much. You saved us.
It's nothing. It is obvious to rescue a friend in danger.
Don't act as if we're distant!
Yeah!
So everyone's here. I'll finish all of you up today!
Our teamwork makes as invincible-dasu! Let's go, everyone-dasu!
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
You dared to drown me!
Stop!
The grudge of a frog is fearful!
Hanzō! Your ambition falls here!
Don't be stupid. You won't take me down!
Sousou Armor!
Karakuri Shift!
Chohi Armor!
Raimeimaru!
I did not expect their comrades to come. I deeply apologize, Lord Nobunaga.
Well, good enough. Even without a hostage, Jipangu State is as good as mine!
What's going on!?
Report! Musashi and others came out from the water tanks and they're raging!
What!?
They must be so excited. Let me chop them down!
Please wait, Lord Nobunaga.
Do not butt in!
We are saying that you do not need to use your sword by your own.
That's right! Those bunch are enough only by Kenshin and me!
Then, I'm leaving this to you. Do not come back until you finish them!
Yessir!
Mr. Nobunaga. Leave this to us, and please go take down Nobunaga!
Got it-dasu!
-Kojirō!
-Right!
Where do you think you're going?
You will not see Lord Nobunaga!
You're getting in my way-dasu!
Musashi!
Take this!
I'll be done for at this rate-dasu!
Karakuri Shift!
Gentoku Armor!
Damn!
Karakuri Shift!
Kanu Armor!
Are you alright?
It seems that I do need your powers.
Come closer! Same for me too!
-Let's do this!
-Right!
Sky Ground Fusion! Shingenshin!
Playtime ends now!
Musashi! Take care of this for a moment!
Huh, Kojirō? Going to pee-dasu!?
Come back as soon as possible-dasu!
Hououmaru! Dance of Phoenix!
We did it-dasu!
How dare you do that, brats!?
I was thinking about sending you to the other world in peace, but...
Do a favor and die!
Mr. Musashi!
Otsuru!
How dare you do that to Otsuru!? I'm mad-dasu!
Niten'ichiryū: Double Dragon Sword!
Mr. Musashi!
Are you okay?
What's wrong, Musashi?
I just used up all my power by that-dasu. I'm hungry-dasu...
Here, Mr. Musashi! Your dangos!
Otsuru, thank you-dasu!
Shingenshin!
Damn!
Stop!
Mr. Jūbee!
Let's chase them!
Right!
Mr. Nobunaga!
What's wrong!? Did you get them?
No, Shingenshin is down!
What!? Shingenshin!?
It's your turn now-dasu!
Now, prepare yourselves!
Give us back the Three Sacred Treasures that you stole from the Highness!
What!? You impudent girl!
Stop!
The Three Sacred Treasures, eh? Hmph. I praise your powers, for being able to take down Shingenshin. I lost.
What-dasu?
Take a look at the corner of this room!
I'm so happy! I finally got it back!
Will the Highness praise me?
Senhime, thank you. Let's marry.
Yes, of course!
Senhime!
No, Kojirō! I have the Highness!
You fooled us!
Farewell!
Well. They ran away.
What's wrong, Benkei!?
It seems that the exit is blocked.
Damn! We're trapped again!
Dokuganryu, press the self-destruction switch of Babel 13!
Are you going to abandon Babel 13?
I do not need such thing anymore.
From now on, Edo Castle is my castle!
Do a full-out attack to Edotopia!
Yessir!
Self-destruction switch, now turning on.
3 minutes until the explosion of Babel 13. Please evacuate immediately.
I don't want to die before being able to marry!
I wanted to marry Otsuru-dasu!
Mr. Musashi, don't say that in front of everyone!
Otsuru...
1 minute until explosion.
You bastard!
30 seconds until explosion.
Beginning countdown.
10 seconds until explosion.
Only Ieyasu stands in my way now.
That is Megaton Castle. Damn, it's heading to Edotopia!
That means, those guys...
Are they gone!?
No! I will be remaining sad if I won't be able to see Senhime and Otsuru's looks in swimsuits!
Mr. Gennai!
Swimsuits what?
Uh, I mean, you're all safe! What a relief!
You're right-dasu!
Musashi and others were in dire crisis,
but they managed to escape the danger, thanks to the burning friendship of Ushiwaka and Benkei.
Do not lose, Musashi! Fight, Musashi! Use all your burning friendship powers to take down Nobunaga's ambitions!
I fought and I got beaten
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
I can't lose, so take my blow!
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
Next is delightful lunchtime
But it's not delightful today
The thunder of my teacher
only hit me and nobody else
I tried to explain
But he won't listen
Now whatever I do
I end up crying
Don't cry when you eat, or
it tastes totally bad
you'll feel downhearted
Nobunaga the Rikudomaoh is trying to make Edotopia into a burnt field-dasu.
Meanwhile, the Highness, who was hiding in Nikko, rides a flying machine named Chokuden to fly over to Edotopia.
We get onto Megaton Castle with a desperate resolution, and do our best to stop Nobunaga's ambitions-dasu!
Next story! Edotopia in Big Crisis
It's the stormy Chokuden-dasu!
Next Episode
Edotopia
in Big Crisis
Look forwards for it!