It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Musashi's group did their best to take down Tsuchigumo, the monster that tormented the villagers,
but under the sorcery of Onihime, they almost ended up as preys of Tsuchigumo.
But thanks to the heaven, or the god or whatever, Ushiwaka and Benkei came to help and
Musashi finally got Tenchimaru, the small sword of legends.
Yamata no Orochi, a Big Showdown
What?
Senhime's group has crossed Watarase river from Kōzuke province and is now heading to Ashikaga?
Yessir. It is a new information.
You bastards... Gone through two of the Four Rulers, Musashi and Kojirō?
You will go down this time.
Karakuri Owl, go to Shutentiger, one of our Four Rulers under Hanzō!
Shutentiger, do not fail. Bring Musashi and Kojirō to their demise, and capture Senhime no matter what.
After all this journey, I can't find a good guy.
Hey, that guy looks pretty nice.
Hey...
What's up-dasu?
Lovely gentleman, wouldn't you share your name with me?
I am Mister Kojirō.
I am Sayonsuke. Got a time for tea with me?
I don't have a hobby like that!
What a cold guy... How cruel.
Ahahahhahah, hey, you lady-killer!
Hmph!
The sun is setting.
Musashi, get over it already!
I'm sorry-dasu.
Go to the village ahead and ask them if they got a room for the night.
Proud of yourself again, eh? I'm going-dasu!
I'll pay all this back someday-dasu!
He sure complaints a lot.
Oh!
What's up, Musashi?
What's up?
What the heck is this?
"Young girls welcome"
"Free one night stay with free meal!"
Isn't it awesome? It's all free!
It's already settled-dasu!
Senhime, this definitely isn't right.
Does it matter? I'm getting starved!
Let's go!
Wait for me, Osenchan!
It's so good!
It's the best! They got so much of foods that I love-dasu!
Musashi, can't you eat quietly!?
This is how you eat noodles-dasu!
Hey, you're splattering it all over!
Isn't it alright? Kojirō, you're just being noisy.
That is too vulgar for a princess!
Leave me alone.
That was a great meal-dasu!
What's that-dasu?
It's a unique tradition of the village - Karaoke Dance!
Karaoke?
You'll fill an empty(kara) bucket(oke), and sing and dance with it.
That does sound interesting-dasu!
It's great, great!
Hey, I wonder why are there only grannies.
Right? I haven't seen any girls around here.
Everyone, welcome to our village tonight.
Even thought nothing is here, we hope you can rest here.
This is a miracle drug of eternal youth from long time ago.
It is told that you can live young even past 100 years old with this.
Past 100 years old-dasu?
This is one good sleeping drug.
Now, hurry, everyone!
Why are you doing this!?
-We're sorry!
-Please forgive us!
What? You're offering girls to Yamata no Orochi?
Yes. If we don't offer a girl every month, the monster will attack fields, children and villagers.
Nonetheless it's unforgivable that you were trying to use us instead of your usual victim.
We understand that you are mad, but there is no girl remaining in this village.
We knew it was a bad thing to do, but...
Nonsense!
That was a good sleep-dasu.
What's up, everyone-dasu?
We apologize, but if we offer an old woman instead, Yamata no Orochi would get angry...
Yamata no Orochi?
Can't you do anything? Why not work together to exterminate it?
That is, it isn't like that we can defeat it by ourselves.
Got it. Leave it to us-dasu!
Musashi, don't forget about our objective!
No, Yamata no Orochi or daikon oroshi, I'm taking it down-dasu!
A- are you serious?
I am looking to become the number one martial artist of Jipangu-dasu. I do not take back my words-dasu!
Musashi, I will stay out of this!
Sure then-dasu! I'll do this no matter what-dasu!
Yamata no Orochi?
Tsuchigumo?
They are monsters that are told to be protecting the sacred swords named Tenkūmaru and Tenchimaru.
So by getting rid of those monsters, I will claim those excellent swords-dasu!
When that time comes, Musashi, you'll become the best of the best swordsmen around the world.
I'll do that with all my might!
If you're being serious, we would be very grateful!
As you see, please do so!
Looks fun! I'll help, too.
P- Princess! That is too reckless!
It's alright! Don't worry! Musashi, let's go.
Please wait!
Damn that luck-pusher!
Can't be helped. It's my duty to protect Senhime.
Yamata no Orochi loved alcoholic drinks.
I repeat. No matter what, do not leave this place!
I want to find out what's going to come out!
What's that?!
Musashi!
Musashi, wake up!
Wake up, Musashi!
Musashi!
You bastard!
What a tough guy-dasu!
Senhime!
Kojirō and Musashi! I'll take Senhime!
Will not happen!
Who are you?! Identify yourself!
Shutentiger
One of the Four Rulers of Iga, Shutentiger!
Osenchan!
I won't be defeated by a snake with many heads-dasu!
-Dammit!
-Musashi! Rescuing Senhime comes first!
But if we don't take this down, we have no hope-dasu!
Now what-dasu?
To seal that neck that's like a ranged weapon...
Forest! Jump into the forest!
Musashi! Let's finish this here!
Understood-dasu!
Musashi!
You bastard! Give me back my Kotetsu-dasu!
Either you stop, or I'll get angry-dasu!
Musashi, watch out! Wait for the stormy latter half!
On your back, Musashi!
Are you alright?
M- my Kotetsu!
My Kotetsu...
Damn you!
-What was that for-dasu?!
-Never mind; just listen!
We did it!
Musashi!
What's up?
Look at this.
Osenchan's flute!
Here it is!
This definitely is Senhime's. Find her around this place!
Osenchan, I'll rescue you no matter what!
Musashi! Pay attention! Must I remind you that it's all your fault!?
I couldn't leave those poor villagers like that-dasu!
What you did is nothing more than being a meddler!
What-dasu?!
That isn't true-dasu!
You bastard!
Stop, Musashi!
Surrendering-dasu?
Musashi! Come over here! It's a cave!
There's a cave here-dasu? What's going on-dasu?
What a blunt guy. Doesn't this place look like a hiding place to you?
Of course I don't know...
This means that it's here.
What is this huge place-dasu?
It's a limestone cave.
-Cold!
-Silence!
It's Yamata no Orochi-dasu.
It escaped already?
Where are Shutentiger and Senhime?
Anyway leave this to me!
No,
Leave it to me-dasu!
W- what's up with that look, Musashi?!
A bottle of drink for the Orochi-dasu.
This is also for Osenchan-dasu.
Quit making scary faces; I know you want to drink!
I brought some alcohol-dasu. Have some.
How good-looking are you, Orochi-chan! Have as much as you want.
As much as you want.
He's extraordinarily good at that for a martial artist.
Huh?
Princess!
Kojirō!
I'm going to rescue you right now.
You fool! You aren't getting away with this!
It is cowardly to attack from behind!
Don't make me laugh!
Hey, aren't you Mr. Tiger?
I'm your wife! Living well enough?
Wife, eh? That was one bad disguise! You must be Musashi!
You are nothing more than a bug in summer flying into fires.
Don't treat me like an idiot-dasu! Let Osenchan go-dasu!
Orochi! Eat up Musashi!
I'll take you down this time-dasu!
Kojirō! Throw me my sword-dasu!
Run away, run away! You'll end up as a feed for Orochi!
Catch this, Musashi!
Got it!
Hey, Orochi, I'll cut your neck down-dasu!
Oh?
Wah!
Kojirō! Give me my Tenchimaru-dasu!
My hands are full now! Do something by yourself!
It's now done.
Dammit! If with Tenchimaru, I'd already have taken down Orochi easily!
Musashi!
Osenchan!
Here it goes! Catch!
With this, Orochi will be nothing... Come and fight, Orochi!
O- Orochi!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
So pretty-dasu!
This must be Tenkūmaru!
W- what's going on-dasu?
Damn!
Stop!
Forget it, Musashi! Do not follow him!
Everyone is now safe.
Musashi and Kojirō! I will not forget this!
Musashi! Hurry up and go outside!
Musashi!
Shutentiger failed too... Musashi and Kojirō. I'll send you to the underworld next time.
Thank you!
-Take care!
-Thank you!
Take care!
But still, I wonder why did Shutentiger collect that much girl from the village-dasu.
I guess he's happy when he's surrounded by girls.
Hmph, I guess he was just lustful. Just like Musashi.
What-dasu?! I'll get you!
Idiot.
Oh dear, aren't you tired of this yet, Musashi and Kojirō?
Anyway, Musashi is deeply encouraged, after taking Yamata no Orochi down and taking Tenkūmaru into his hands.
He protected Senhime and his great endeavors are blossoming like a tornado!
But nobody knows what's waiting for him - a heaven, or a hell? Or could it be the dance of swords?
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
Goemondo, a Karakuri sorcerer, is the ultimate thief in the whole world!
He sent a notification that he's going to steal the gold decoration at the roof of the castle-dasu.
When we decided to stay up all night to guard, a giant centipede came to attack us-dasu!
Next story! The Ultimate Thief of Shining Gold, Goemondo
It's a stormy dual blade-dasu!
Next Episode
The Ultimate Thief of
Shining Gold, Goemondo
Look forwards for it!