It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Musashi met a rare beauty named Himiko, and participated in a martial arts contest.
But the purpose of the contest was to gather capable subordinates for Shiranui Clan.
After hearing about the truth from Ushiwaka, Musashi made a mess of the contest.
That's Bad!
Depressed Kojirō
Ms. Himiko, how is the plan going?
Do not worry, Mr. Hanzō. Everything is going well.
That is good to know. But do not let your guards down.
You mean Senhime and others?
No need to worry. I already sent an assassin.
That's Ms. Himiko I know. How careful of you.
Musashi! We're leaving!
Come here soon!
Just a moment-dasu! I'm now training for a new technique-dasu!
Hmph! If your enemy is the sea, then no matter how many lives you have, they won't be enough!
What?!
Musashi, your sword lacks distance!
What about distance-dasu?
You idiot! Don't you know that?! You have to measure distance between you and your enemy!
What was that idiot for-dasu?!
Look and learn!
Hmph. This is how distance should be.
Hmph! With a sword that long, no matter how far the enemy is, targeting is easi-dasu! That's not at all great-dasu!
What?! Are you looking down of my sword?!
Then what-dasu?
Unforgivable!
Stop! Stop it, you two. If you're going to do it, then do it after you have dealt with Shiranui Clan!
You are right. We were in the middle of an important job.
It is no use to explain the awesomeness of my sword to a guy like that.
I am embarrassed of myself for getting worked up.
Stop right there-dasu! Running away is cowardly-dasu!
KNOW WHEN TO STOP!
Yessir...
Musashi, Kojirō and Senhime, right?
I am a messenger of Mr. Saigo.
What does Mr. Saigo have with us?
Mr. Saigo has prepared a meal to thank all your efforts to deal with Shiranui Clan.
What?! Meal?! Yes, we're going-dasu, we're going-dasu, we're going right now-dasu!
Musashi, how unsightly of you! Whenever you hear about food, your eye changes, and you can't do anything right!
Yeah, yeah!
But still, he went through all the trouble to prepare a meal for us, and we can't refuse that-dasu!
That's right.
Please do so. If you don't, then I'll be scolded.
Then let's go, as he told!
Yay-dasu!
Saigo
This way.
An owner of a country sure lives in a great place-dasu!
Welcome, Musashi, Kojirō, and Senhime.
Mr. Saigo! We're here to eat a lot today-dasu!
Thank you for inviting us to a meal.
No, no, to think about all your hard work of fighting against Shiranui Clan, this is nothing.
Please come in, come in!
Yes-dasu!
It's awesome-dasu!
Satsumaage steak, Satsumaage sashimi,
Satsumaage salad, and Satsumaage pudding.
Everything here is made of Satsumaage, the local specialty of Kyushu.
Please eat as much as you want.
Thank you for the meal!
It's tasty!
Don't eat so greedily! That is so unsightly!
BURP
No matter what you say, everything's so tasty and I can't help myself-dasu!
He's embarassing me to the extent that I lost my appetite...
Don't be like that, and please eat, you two.
By the way, where is Shiro?
Shiro?
The dog you always take along. I can't see him.
Oh, you mean that Shiro! Er, Shiro isn't feeling so good, so he's sleeping in his dog house.
That's too bad. Let me go and take a look myself.
No, no, please don't do that. Please eat for now.
Why are you so hurrying with the meal? I am just trying to take a look.
T- that's...
Kojirō, asking persistently like that is rude.
Let's eat, too.
It got stuck to your throat because you were so hurrying!
No, that isn't it-dasu. My body is getting numb...
Musashi!
This symptom...
This is poisonous. Mr. Saigo, what's the meaning of this?!
Damn, you three should already have been dead by now!
That glutton got everything discovered!
Who are you bastard?!
Kumason
(Kuma: bear)
I am an assassin of Shiranui Clan, Kumason for bear-killing!
Heh, falling into a trap like this would probably mean you are nothing great.
Hmph! I knew this was a trap! I just played along with you because I wanted clues about you bastards!
Why didn't you tell me-dasu?
You already ate it all before I tell you!
Kumason! I will have to know where your hideout is!
I see you're pretty confident. You guys can stay back.
I'll cook this guy up.
Hmph. Fighting me with such short swords? How foolish.
You're pretty good!
Heh, my punch is enough to take a bear down with only one punch! You won't get away this time, so be prepared!
That's my line! I checked out all your techniques! As soon as you appear in front of me, you're going down!
I got you!
What?!
Let me tell you something. I am known for bear-killing Kumason, but I am known for an another name.
I am called sword-breaking Kumason!
My Monohoshizao!
This is not the time for that! Kojirō's gonna be killed at this rate!
Really, you aren't being helpful whenever we need!
Swallow these antidotes and become healthy! You'll become good soon by overdosing!
Swallow it! Just swallow it!
This is not right-dasu. My body is...
Just go already!
Yessir!
You're an eyesore!
Help me-dasu!
Help!
Heh, that fool.
Musashi! Kojirō! Let's run away using this chance!
Kojirō!
My sword... My Monohoshizao...
What are you doing, Kojirō?! Come already!
Stop right there, you bastards!
Damn! Get them! Do not let even one get away!
Is it possible for Musashi and others to defeat Kumason, a powerful enemy?
Wait for the stormy latter half!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
Become Jipangu's Star
How fruitless it was.
What were the painful and tormenting days of training for?
203, come in!
Hey, let me join!
You can't! You're gonna trip since you always drag your feet!
Let's go, let's go!
Hey, wait!
Kojirō. You have to become the bright Venus of Jipangu.
Don't cry! Don't lose heart! Train!
Yessir!
Kojirō, become a splendid martial artist like your father.
Sorry! Please forgive me! Please! I'm sorry!
Day after day, it was an endless pain.
And...
I did it!
Swallows' tails are split ever since then.
Well, that's the folklore.
How did my Monohoshizao end up being broken, after being together for all the long and painful time?
Kojirō's feeling so down...
That was terrible-dasu...
That Kumason bastard made me suffer so much-dasu...
Hey, Musashi! It's all your fault, at the first place! Do something!
Huh? Why is this my fault?
Being paralyzed by eating poisonous food is wrong, for a martial artist!
No way!
Any complaints?!
You will restore Kojirō, or else!
But I don't know how to restore him at all-dasu!
Huh? Kojirō isn't there-dasu.
Where did he go-dasu?
Hey! He's going to take suicide!
He can't-dasu!
-Kojirō!
D- don't be a fool-dasu!
Let me go. I do not worth living anymore since I lost my beloved sword!
What are you saying-dasu?! You can get an another sword-dasu!
You don't know a thing! I know the best that it is difficult to obtain a sword that long!
You must not give up-dasu!
You can't enjoy flowers if you die-dasu! If we try to find one, then we'll find one-dasu!
Musashi... You are a good guy...
I think that I did a good job-dasu!
Report! Did you find them?!
We're searching everywhere possible, but not yet.
Dammit! Go find them already! My hand is bursting into rage and flaaaaaaaaaring up, wanting to take them down!
We don't have any sword that long.
I never saw one...
Finding one that long is almost impossible.
There's no way those would even exist.
We have one.
Really?!
(Southern barbarian: SE. Asia, sometimes including Spain and Portugal, for having colonies there)
It's a sword introduced by Southern barbarians. Would this suit your needs?
Er, it doesn't look so dependable...
No way!
What should we do? Kojirō will be keep feeling down at this rate.
That's it! I'll make a sword for him-dasu!
Really? Can you make one, Musashi?
Leave it to me-dasu!
Here! It's done-dasu!
Sword, eh?
Try using it-dasu!
How do you feel-dasu?
Erm, good enough, I guess.
Musashi! Blades are missing!
Huh? Where did they go?
You can find the blades here!
Osenchan, are you alright-dasu?!
What kind of contraption did you make?! Be thankful that I have a good reaction, and I'm cute!
An usual person would have already died!
H- how does being cute have something to do with it-dasu?
Please stop, Senhime.
Musashi did that for me.
I finally realized after you two were doing all that for me.
Really?
Yes. I won't be particular about the length of sword from now on.
eat shit!
It's no good. It can't make to the distance...
That Kojirō became down again-dasu...
This is bad. I wonder if there's a long sword that compares to Monohoshizao...
There exists one.
Huh?! Mr. Saigo! No, Kumason!
You came here disguised as Mr. Saigo again! We won't be fooled again!
Hm? What are you talking about-gowasu? I was just offering you a meal, for fighting hard against Shiranui Clan-gowasu.
And since that, I bought a handful of Satsumaage-gowasu.
What?! Even for me, I won't be fooled to Satsumaages again-dasu! Mr. Saigo, prepare yourself-dasu!
Chest!
CHE
S
T
Judging by that big voice of yours, you are real one-dasu...
I see-gowasu.
So that's why you confused me with that Kumason guy-gowasu!
I'm sorry-dasu!
So, Mr. Saigo, where is that long sword you told us about?
It's at Amakusa Island.
Amakusa Island?
It seems that there is a legendary secret sword that is even longer than Mr. Kojirō's sword.
Then we'll go take that-dasu!
I will not let you go to Amakusa Island.
Kumason!
Things will get complicated if you go to Amakusa Island. You'd better die here!
I won't lose this time-dasu!
Die!
That's cunning-dasu!
Kojirō, get a grip!
Now we don't know who is whose bodyguard!
Chest!
I hope all of you saw Jigen Style Shout Technique!
Huh? Senhime!
P- please do it with a smaller voice next time...
You won't run away this time!
I don't just run away-dasu!
How guileless of you. Let me break your sword too!
I have more than one sword!
What?!
Even if you're not up for a close combat, there's no difference! Take this instead!
Take it once again!
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
Kojirō.
They managed to take down Kumason, a frightful assassin from Shiranui Clan.
But having his beloved sword broken, Kojirō was deeply disheartened.
Will Musashi managed to recover Kojirō, his eternal rival? And what is that secret hidden in Amakusa Island?
Wait for the stormy next episode!
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
For having his Monohoshizao broken, Kojirō is really feeling down.
I had no choice but to go to Amakusa Island that Mr. Saigo told me about, to find the legendary secret sword!
But, they say that only the ones who are qualified can pull out the sword-dasu.
Will Kojirō's Tsubamegaeshi be revived?!
Next story! The Reviving Legendary Sword!
It's the stormy Amakusa Island!
Next Episode
The Reviving
Legendary Sword
Look forwards for it!