It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
Musashi is here-dasu!
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
A man always dreams of the day
in the center of the world to become
AH! AH! the strongest
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
Go! Fight!
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
Tomorrow will be glorious
The sound of fierce duels
makes life dazzling
Fight the utmost with the stillness
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
His eyes shined! Musashi!
Musashi, learned about the year-end Jipangu Martial Arts Competition from Jūbee,
headed to Edotopia in Miyako, fighting against spear-wielding Hōzōin on his way.
What is waiting in front of Musashi? Is it a flower or a storm?
Clean and Poor Kusarigama
Musashi!
Otsuru!
That was splendid!
Yes! I won the first place at the competition-dasu! I've became the number one martial artist of Jipangu-dasu!
Congratulations.
Otsuru...
You idiot! You're even dreaming too early!
This is a nightmare-dasu!
Those are my Kotetsus!
Give those back-dasu!
What's with this-dasu?
Pfft!
Hey!
You made me mad-dasu!
Stop right there!
You aren't going anywhere-dasu!
Stop!
I'm not falling over that again-dasu!
I've been doing that for the whole time; you shall not defeat me in a mountain-dasu!
Give it up and give my swords back-dasu!
He's pretty good-dasu.
No, it's not the time to be surprised-dasu.
Where did he go-dasu?
Come out!
Hiding is unfair-dasu!
Where are you-dasu?! Show yourself-dasu!
Right there!
What are you doing-dasu? Stop-dasu!
Attacking all of a sudden is cowardly and unforgivable-dasu!
What? Cowardly?
You're the one to talk; you dived onto me while I'm cutting grasses!
Baiken
Cutting grasses... Are you saying that that's a sickle-dasu?
Look!
Now you see?
How convenient! You can cut many at once-dasu!
Ah, sorry for interrupting-dasu.
I am Musashi-dasu.
I am Baiken.
Did you see those kids with swords-dasu?
Children with swords?
Those swords are mine-dasu.
Are they stolen?
During I was taking a nap for a bit...
Were there three children?
Ri- right-dasu.
Baiken, do you have suspects-dasu?
Baiken!
He's up to something-dasu.
I told you countless times, and you still didn't get it?
But bro, you said you wanted it so much!
Ikken! No excuses!
Nikken! A man must not cry!
Now!
I'll cut the hands as promised.
Oharu. You'll be forgiven this time since you're only a girl.
Ikken, Niken! Show your hands!
Oharu! You don't need to!
Brother, we made a promise when we departed from the state.
"From now on, let's combine our powers." We promised.
"We die and live together". We promised.
I can't be left out.
Oharu.
Alright, I get it. We die and live together.
Then I'll cut too.
You don't have to!
I am responsible for your robbery too.
We three live and die together.
So now we go...
Stop!
Stop! Stop right there!
Musashi, right?
This must be the stolen swords.
Those are mine, but...
Take these back.
But they aren't stolen-dasu.
What?
Actually, I rested my swords on a pine tree because it wasn't comfortable to bear my swords while sleeping,
but I forgot and left without them after waking up-dasu.
Do not lie!
It's not a lie-dasu!
A real martial artist will never forget his spirit - his sword!
B- but, still...
I keep completely forgetting those stuff-dasu.
Are you calling yourself a fake martial artist, Musashi?
What was that?
A real martial artist does not forget his own sword! Only an impostor does!
Shut your mouth up! I am a martial artist who had to live apart to learn under Bokuden as my master-dasu!
What? A student of Bokuden, the master martial artist of mutōdori?
How dare you call me a fake-dasu?!
I've been impolite.
If you understand, there's nothing special to apologize.
But I have a request.
Huh? I'll do whatever I can-dasu.
Give me your best shot.
Best shot? Do you want a practice match-dasu?
No. A match with real swords.
What did you say-dasu?
Is that a no?
No, that's not it, but...
You said that you'll do anything you can, but I can see that it was a flat-out lie!
No, a man does not take back his words-dasu!
Sorry for making you wait!
Baiken, is that your weapon?
Right. It's a kusarigama.
Kusarigama?
-Let's do this!
-Right!
Will Musashi defeat Baiken's kusarigama? Wait for the stormy latter half!
Brother! Do your best!
Brother!
Silence!
This is a real match!
Don't say a thing or I'll be distracted!
From now on, keep quiet and stay put! Understood?
Got it!
We'll die if you die!
Oh dear...
Musashi! There will be no going easy on you! Let's do this!
Of course!
What a strength!
This isn't good. What should I do-dasu, what should I...
There are some rapids that you may float once you throw yourself in.
(Fortune favors the bold.)
If you're prepared enough to throw your life for it, you will take your first victory.
Brother!
No!
아야, 뭔 짓이오!
Ouch! What are you doing-dasu?!
I lost.
No. The match isn't over yet-dasu.
No, that's not it. I've told them not to butt into the match, but...
This is also undesirable state brought about by my lack of virtue.
No, it's reasonable to help a crisis of a sibling-dasu!
I understand the feelings of those children-dasu.
I am ashamed. But it's a truth that my siblings helped me. That means, I would have been lost without their help.
We don't know about that yet-dasu.
But...
We won't know if we don't continue-dasu!
You are one tedious guy!
Same goes for Baiken!
We don't have any side dishes, but you can have this barley porridge as much as you want.
Eating around a fireplace with everyone is the best side dish-dasu! It tastes great-dasu.
Musashi's a weird guy.
Why-dasu?
How can be a fire a side dish? I want something roasted.
I want a side dish. Even a few pickled plums would be enough.
-Oharu!
-What? It's true!
But still, even without pickled plums, only by thinking about those, I can feel the sourness and eat the porridge deliciously!
Musashi, I have to apologize. You've covered for my siblings earlier in the day,
but after hearing from you that you're a student of Bokuden, I asked you for a match because I wanted to test your ability.
Nonsense-dasu. I could learn by fighting against an opponent with a kusarigama-dasu.
Anyway, it's an interesting weapon-dasu.
You mean this?
Master Bokuden didn't tell me about this weapon-dasu.
My brother invented it!
Oh, by himself?
We've used to be farmers back at north from this place.
During that turbulent age, the crops and farms we worked on by ourselves have been destroyed numerous times,
and the fields were stamped, being used as battlefields, and our parents' lives were taken away.
Don't move.
Stay put.
But our dad and mom are...
We all die if you go out! If you want to avenge for our parents, keep down!
A new daimyō overthrew the previous lord. This new daimyō is an easily flinching, cruel and horrible person
who drove us to a wasteland and made us do work in a brutal environment.
We alone were not enough to fulfill their demands, leaving us being often whipped.
After seeing my hardworking siblings' hands full of wounds,
I tried to devise a way to cut more grasses at once with this sickle,
and decided to make a big sickle.
Hey, you! Stand up!
Please forgive us!
Do not get in the way!
I have never wanted a sword as much as back then.
Actually, I've been practicing swordsmanship in secret.
Wishing to become a real martial artist, take down the daimyō, and exact revenge for my parents.
But without the most important sword, a real fight is impossible.
I thought.
I thought to use that big sickle as a weapon.
And I finally came up with an idea to attach a weight to the sickle using chains.
One day, yielding kusarigama became natural enough.
On one stormy night, we abandoned our home.
I see...
Despite that I became comfortable using kusarigama, I was always worried about being unable to defeat sword with it.
Knowing that, that's why my siblings stole your swords.
Nope. A sword definitely a spirit of a Martial Artist-dasu. It is my fault, for losing it-dasu.
(It is told that Confucius didn't drink from Tōsen, 盜泉, literally thief pond, because of its name)
You do not drink from Tōsen even when you're thirsty.
(Better starve than fatten on ill-gotten wealth.)
That is the oath of our siblings.
And as we broke our oath...
I, Musashi, will forgive that, and all you have to do is keep the oath again-dasu.
I feel ashamed. I will return the favor someday.
More importantly, you should join Jipangu Martial Arts Competition...
Of course! I've been training for that to this day!
I have a new rival-dasu!
I hope to see you in the final match!
Agreed-dasu.
Good morning-dasu!
Good morning.
Huh? Where are the children?
They went gather potatoes from the field.
They aren't ripe yet, but they wanted to give you some real side dishes.
They're too kind for me...
Brother! We have a problem!
What is it?!
Some samurai is stamping on our field!
What?!
You bastards! Get lost!
You're on our field! Do not trample down!
How annoying. Get him!
Musashi! Now going to help, like a blaze-dasu!
No matter how much I take down, they just keep coming!
Then I'll take down the head of them!
Got you, you brat!
What?!
Run away!
Hooray! Hooray!
Promising to meet again in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition, Musashi heads first to Edotopia.
Still, Baiken is interesting and his kusarigama is again, interesting.
Musashi thought.
The world is broad. There still are a lot of martial artists with strong personalities and strong heart.
He will challenge unknown opponents! The young martial artist's heart was throbbing.
Sometimes the moon jumps over
the pocket of empty sky
Laugh loudly and
morning will come tomorrow
Don't worry too much about losing
Keep going! Go for it!
A bare hand is strong
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how life is! Look, a chance
follows us wagging its tail!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
I've helped a wounded dove on the way to Edotopia, and I ended up being chased by some terrible bunch-dasu.
Their boss is Hanzō, the ruler of night! After a fight against frightening ninja corps, my rival Kojirō is now involved-dasu.
Next story! Evil Hanzō Creeps-dasu.
Be sure to check out the next stormy story-dasu!
Next Episode
Evil Hanzō Creeps
Look forwards for it!